<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><xml><records><record><database name="130_Hampshire_Downs_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\130_Hampshire_Downs_Shortlist.enl">130_Hampshire_Downs_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>223</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="pesa09zzlza298e2xem5erswdp5s90vxtdav">223</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Ingram, J.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Countryside and Community Research Unit, University of Gloucestershire, Dunholme Villa, The Park, Cheltenham, GL50 2RH, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Are farmers in England equipped to meet the knowledge challenge of sustainable soil management? An analysis of farmer and advisor views</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Journal of Environmental Management</style></secondary-title></titles><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">214-228</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">86</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1</style></number><keywords><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Agricultural advisor</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Best management practice</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cultivation</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Diffuse pollution</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Farmer</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Scientific knowledge</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Soil management</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Tacit knowledge</style></keyword></keywords><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2008</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Concern about the agricultural soil resource in England has led to the introduction of a range of measures, which potentially challenge farmers&apos; knowledge about the soil and its management. Our understanding however of how well-equipped farmers are with regard to effectively carrying out more complex and knowledge intensive sustainable soil management practices is limited. Specifically, by drawing on the concept of scientific and tacit forms of knowledge, this paper examines the knowledge of soils held by farmers through analysis of data collected from semi-structured interviews with farmers and agricultural advisors and supplemented with data from an extensive postal questionnaire survey of advisors. The data indicate that, while farmers are technically well informed, they can often lack the in-depth scientific knowledge required to implement more complex practices such as using the nutrient value of manures. They also reveal that, while most farmers have good knowledge of their own soils, their tacit knowledge of soil management can be weak, notably in relation to cultivation. The paper concludes that although farmers&apos; knowledge about soil and its sustainable management appears in general to be well developed there are some areas, which need to be significantly enhanced and as such require both a policy response and further research effort. © 2007 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 13&#xD;Export Date: 16 November 2011&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-35648964320&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=32d16f96e571b033915f819e31460117</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://ac.els-cdn.com.ezproxy.liv.ac.uk/S0301479706004300/1-s2.0-S0301479706004300-main.pdf?_tid=f576d81ee4df4d63e44597683081bf2e&amp;acdnat=1332940907_c160b0776d638d1c2d1e242c994b1db8</style></url></related-urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Ingram-2008-Are farmers in Engla-0153937665/Ingram-2008-Are farmers in Engla.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="130_Hampshire_Downs_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\130_Hampshire_Downs_Shortlist.enl">130_Hampshire_Downs_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>225</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="pesa09zzlza298e2xem5erswdp5s90vxtdav">225</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Ingram, J.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Morris, C.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Countryside and Community Research Unit, University of Gloucestershire, Dunholme Villa, The Park, Cheltenham, GL50 2RH, United Kingdom&#xD;Centre for Rural Research, School of Geography, Archaeology and Earth Resources, Exeter University, Lafrowda House, St. German&apos;s Road, Exeter, Devon EX4 6TL, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">The knowledge challenge within the transition towards sustainable soil management: An analysis of agricultural advisors in England</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Land Use Policy</style></secondary-title></titles><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">100-117</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">24</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1</style></number><keywords><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Agricultural advisor</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">CAP</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Knowledge</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Policy</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Soil best management practice</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Sustainable soil management</style></keyword></keywords><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2007</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">The sustainable management of soils, while constituting an important resource conservation concern in some contexts, has been neglected in the UK. However, this all seems set to change, with implications for various actors within the agricultural knowledge system. New policies designed to encourage the more sustainable management of soils in England together with the introduction of Soil Management Plans (SMP) as part of cross-compliance under recent Common Agricultural Policy reform mean that demands on agricultural advisors&apos; knowledge about soil will increase. This paper reports the findings of research into the nature and extent of agricultural advisors&apos; knowledge about soil best management practice. Specifically, it examines the &apos;know-what&apos;, &apos;know-why&apos; and &apos;know-how&apos; of soils among agricultural advisors through analysis of data collected from an extensive postal questionnaire survey of 162 advisors across England supplemented by qualitative data from semi-structured interviews with 64 advisors. The results show that as a community advisors are generally knowledgeable about soil best management practice and appear to be observing soil degradation, undertaking training, using guides, tools and recommending soil best management practice to a relatively large extent. The data however do indicate that different types of advisors hold different forms of knowledge to a different extent. They also reveal gaps in knowledge gained through practical experience about cultivation and using the nutrient value of manures. The paper concludes that advisors&apos; knowledge about soil and its sustainable management is considerably greater than earlier research on advisors&apos; environmental knowledge has suggested but that some areas will have to be significantly enhanced and standardised to meet the new policy challenges. The significance of the results is discussed in terms of the wider role advisors play in the transition from &apos;production only&apos; goals towards those concerned with more sustainable practices in agriculture. © 2005 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 8&#xD;Export Date: 16 November 2011&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-33748792341&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=3ea9cbd1928a785f6d8c9598a0409872</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://ac.els-cdn.com.ezproxy.liv.ac.uk/S0264837705000384/1-s2.0-S0264837705000384-main.pdf?_tid=8391524fc1a902cf57498f648b39a5fb&amp;acdnat=1332940927_c8edf184671cc64b0ad9e92d0c67cd20</style></url></related-urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Ingram-2007-The knowledge challe-3526177537/Ingram-2007-The knowledge challe.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record></records></xml>