<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><xml><records><record><database name="130_Hampshire_Downs_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\130_Hampshire_Downs_Shortlist.enl">130_Hampshire_Downs_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>239</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="pesa09zzlza298e2xem5erswdp5s90vxtdav">239</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Acornley, R. M.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Sear, D. A.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Department of Geography, University of Southampton, Highfield, Southampton SO17 1BJ, United Kingdom&#xD;Div. of Geogr. and Environ. Mgmt., Univ. of Northumbria at Newcastle, Newcastle-upon-Tyne NE1 8ST, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Sediment transport and siltation of brown trout (Salmo trutta L.) spawning gravels in chalk streams</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Hydrological Processes</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Hydrological Processes</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">447-458</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">13</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">3</style></number><keywords><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Chalk stream</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Salmo trutta</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Sediment deposition</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Spawning gravels</style></keyword></keywords><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1999</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Deposition rates of fine sediment into brown trout spawning gravels were measured at monthly intervals for a period of one year in a small channel of the River Test, Hampshire. Data were also collected on stream discharge, water depth, flow velocity and suspended sediment concentrations. Deposition rates followed a seasonal pattern and were maximal during periods of high discharge in the late winter/early spring when suspended sediment concentrations were high. The material deposited in the spawning gravels included silts and fine sands (&lt;250 μm) that were transported in suspension and coarser fragments of low density tufalike material that were transported as bed load. The ecological implications of fine sediment deposition for salmonid egg survival in chalk streams are considered.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 56&#xD;Export Date: 29 February 2012&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-0033611786&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=92726285a10bacc70cdb05dcbcf65baf</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/store/10.1002/(SICI)1099-1085(19990228)13:3&lt;447::AID-HYP749&gt;3.0.CO;2-G/asset/749_ftp.pdf?v=1&amp;t=h0cebfdv&amp;s=809d35a562b33aafdff81b62f6c0efd11bee7bb1</style></url></related-urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Acornley-1999-Sediment transport a-3827855873/Acornley-1999-Sediment transport a.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="130_Hampshire_Downs_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\130_Hampshire_Downs_Shortlist.enl">130_Hampshire_Downs_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>240</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="pesa09zzlza298e2xem5erswdp5s90vxtdav">240</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Allen, L. G.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Gibbard, P. L.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Subdepartment of Quaternary Research, Botany School, University of Cambridge, Downing Street, Cambridge, CB2 3EA, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Pleistocene evolution of the Solent River of southern England</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Quaternary Science Reviews</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Quaternary Science Reviews</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">503-528</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">12</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">7</style></number><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1993</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">The Solent River no longer exists since most of its course was drowned by eustatic sea level rise during the Flandrian Stage (Holocene). Previously, it flowed eastwards across southeast Dorset and south Hampshire as an extension of the River Frome. As such, it formed the axial major stream of the Hampshire Basin. A sequence of fluvial aggradations, ranging in height from 125 m O.D. to below sea level, provide evidence of the former courses of this substantial river and its tributaries. Detailed study of the deposits, supported by analysis of clast lithological assemblages provide the basis for the recognition of a series of lithostratigraphical units throughout the area. The facies and sedimentary structures indicate that the bulk of the deposits accumulated in a braided river environment under periglacial climates. Late Pleistocene fossiliferous sediments of Ipswichian and Flandrian age provide a biostratigraphical framework. The results demonstrate that the Solent River was a substantial system, comparable in size to the present Thames, and was a tributary of the &apos;Channel River&apos; during periods of low sea level (cold stages). Evolution of the river reflects its response to climatic change, local geological structure and long term tectonic activity. Although datable deposits limit determination of the age of the Solent River sequence, it is undoubtedly of considerable antiquity and potentially extends back to the Early Pleistocene. Discussion of the sequence includes placing the events within their regional context. © 1994.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 35&#xD;Export Date: 1 March 2012&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-0027843543&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=3207a149c958d542a36d0b667b3d3dbd</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://ac.els-cdn.com.ezproxy.liv.ac.uk/027737919390075W/1-s2.0-027737919390075W-main.pdf?_tid=f39a7c9f22fd1d67a0c9f16f06cb0a02&amp;acdnat=1332940620_d3b47040364091c650b2087b7d2db5e2</style></url></related-urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Allen-1993-Pleistocene evolutio-2972224257/Allen-1993-Pleistocene evolutio.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="130_Hampshire_Downs_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\130_Hampshire_Downs_Shortlist.enl">130_Hampshire_Downs_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>232</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="pesa09zzlza298e2xem5erswdp5s90vxtdav">232</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Archer, J.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">ADAS, Nobel House, London SW1P 3JR, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Policies to reduce nitrogen loss to water from agriculture in the United Kingdom</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Marine Pollution Bulletin</style></secondary-title></titles><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">444-449</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">29</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">6-12</style></number><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1994</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Water supply companies in England face increasing difficulty and costs in meeting the 50mg l-1 nitrate limit in drinking water from groundwater sources. Some surface water abstractions also exceed the limit, but usually only in late autumn. Nitrogen-limited eutrophication is not a significant problem of estuary or coastal waters in the UK. Local problems are under investigation but the cause is rarely clear. Agricultural land is recognized as the main source of nitrate reaching ground and surface waters in the UK. Considerable research has been carried out on nitrate and farming systems. There is a substantial, ongoing government funded research programme. A significant remaining problem is the ability to relate losses from agriculture to nitrate in abstracted water or entering tidal waters. Much work remains to be done to improve our predictive ability In 1989, the UK government set up a Pilot Nitrate Scheme. This involved ten Nitrate Sensitive Areas. These were groundwater catchments in which farmers were invited on a voluntary basis to enter into 5 year contracts With the Ministry of Agriculture, Fisheries and Food (MAFF). The basis of the agreements are that the farmer will carry out a range of modifications to current farming practice, thus reducing nitrate loss. There are also options for converting current arable to extensive grass. These areas will initially run for 5 years. In addition nine Nitrate Advisory Areas mere targeted for intensive advice. In 1991, MAFF published its Code of Good Agricultural Practice for the Protection of Water. This provides guidance to farmers on the agreed balance between agricultural production and environmental protection of water which all farmers should follow it includes a section on nitrate. In 1989, the UK government set up a Pilot Nitrate Scheme. This involved ten Nitrate Sensitive Areas. These were groundwater catchments in which farmers were invited on a voluntary basis to enter into 5 year contracts with the Ministry of Agriculture, Fisheries and Food (MAFF). The basis of the agreement is that the farmer will carry out a range of modifications to current farming practice, thus reducing nitrate loss. There are also options for converting current arable to extensive grass. These areas will initially run for 5 years. In addition nine Nitrate Advisory Areas were targeted for intensive advice.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 3&#xD;Export Date: 16 November 2011&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-0028671829&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=e39654ed9b315111e66bbe7022936a0d</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://ac.els-cdn.com.ezproxy.liv.ac.uk/0025326X94906696/1-s2.0-0025326X94906696-main.pdf?_tid=c2e6bacf335341ec7170e33254f417da&amp;acdnat=1332940612_1c2fdf1a7ebe803e5474f85d3d5de3a0</style></url></related-urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Archer-1994-Policies to reduce n-3173541633/Archer-1994-Policies to reduce n.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="130_Hampshire_Downs_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\130_Hampshire_Downs_Shortlist.enl">130_Hampshire_Downs_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>123</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="pesa09zzlza298e2xem5erswdp5s90vxtdav">123</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Atul, H. Haria</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Martin, G. Hodnett</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Andrew, C. Johnson</style></author></authors></contributors><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Mechanisms of groundwater recharge and pesticide penetration to a chalk aquifer in southern England</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Journal of Hydrology</style></secondary-title></titles><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">122-137</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">275</style></volume><keywords><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Chalk</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Groundwater recharge</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Unsaturated zone</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Hillslope hydrology</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Capillary fringe</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Isoproturon</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Chlotoluron</style></keyword></keywords><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2003</style></year></dates><publisher><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Elsevier B.V.</style></publisher><isbn><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">0022-1694</style></isbn><accession-num><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">S0022169403000179</style></accession-num><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">In order to assess the potential for enhanced agrochemical contamination of shallow groundwaters, a field study was established on the Upper Chalk in Hampshire, UK. Two instrumented sites, 380m apart, were established on a hillslope; one on the interfluve with a deep water table (∼18m depth), the other on the dry valley bottom where the groundwater was close to the surface (∼4m depth). Hourly measurements of water potentials in the unsaturated zone to 3.0m depth identified very different groundwater recharge processes between the two sites in response to the same storm event. On the interfluve site with the deep water table only matrix flow through the chalk unsaturated zone at 3m depth was identified. In contrast, at the dry valley bottom with a shallow water table, both rapid preferential flow and matrix flow processes were observed at a 3m depth. The correlation between groundwater depth measurements and unsaturated profile moisture content measurements demonstrated the importance of the capillary fringe in sustaining a higher moisture content in the unsaturated zone at the shallow groundwater site. The resulting reduced water storage capacity for vertical drainage fluxes meant that little water was required to wet the shallow profile before rapid preferential flow events, demonstrated by rapid water potential responses, occurred. However, where the groundwater was deeper, ‘intermediate’ storage sites located on chalk surfaces and at chalk ped/block ‘contact points’ remained empty and unsaturated water potential profiles showed that rainfall pulses were attenuated as these sites absorbed the downward water fluxes. Consequently, preferential events at these deep groundwater sites are rare. The importance of these ‘intermediate’ storage sites in controlling recharge processes is highlighted. The potential mass load of pesticide transported to the shallow groundwater in preferential events during 1996–7 was determined using bromide tracer studies, water balance calculations and measured groundwater pesticide concentrations. An estimated 0.1% of the applied pesticide reached the shallow groundwater along preferential pathways in 1996–7. Calculations under a worst-case scenario showed that this value did not increase beyond 0.2% of pesticide applied.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">(∗)&#xD;Journal of Hydrology&#xD;Author: Atul H Haria (∗); Author: Martin G Hodnett; Author: Andrew C Johnson; Affiliation: Centre for Ecology and Hydrology (formerly Institute of Hydrology), Maclean Building, Crowmarsh Gifford, Wallingford, Oxfordshire OX10 8BB, UK; Keyword: Chalk; Keyword: Groundwater recharge; Keyword: Unsaturated zone; Keyword: Hillslope hydrology; Keyword: Capillary fringe; Keyword: Isoproturon; Keyword: Chlotoluron; Number of Pages: 16; Language: English;</style></notes><work-type><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Article</style></work-type><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://search.ebscohost.com.ezproxy.liv.ac.uk/login.aspx?direct=true&amp;db=edselp&amp;AN=S0022169403000179&amp;site=eds-live&amp;scope=site</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://ac.els-cdn.com/S0022169403000179/1-s2.0-S0022169403000179-main.pdf?_tid=a2ff3cc0a61edad9147897eb362cbc26&amp;acdnat=1332940602_5b54d5e99bff09b034d8b4bbcc0ddb24</style></url></related-urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Atul-2003-Mechanisms of ground-0287850497/Atul-2003-Mechanisms of ground.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><electronic-resource-num><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">10.1016/s0022-1694(03)00017-9</style></electronic-resource-num><remote-database-name><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">edselp</style></remote-database-name><remote-database-provider><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">EBSCOhost</style></remote-database-provider></record><record><database name="130_Hampshire_Downs_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\130_Hampshire_Downs_Shortlist.enl">130_Hampshire_Downs_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>222</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="pesa09zzlza298e2xem5erswdp5s90vxtdav">222</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Bilton, D. T.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">McAbendroth, L. C.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Nicolet, P.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Bedford, A.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Rundle, S. D.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Foggo, A.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Ramsay, P. M.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">School of Biological Sciences, University of Plymouth, Plymouth, PL4 8AA, United Kingdom&#xD;Ponds Conservation: The Water Habitats Trust, c/o Oxford Brookes University, School of Biological and Molecular Sciences, Gipsy Lane, Headington, Oxford OX3 0BP, United Kingdom&#xD;Edge Hill University, St Helens Road, Ormskirk, Lancashire L39 4QP, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Ecology and conservation status of temporary and fluctuating ponds in two areas of southern England</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Aquatic Conservation: Marine and Freshwater Ecosystems</style></secondary-title></titles><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">134-146</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">19</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2</style></number><keywords><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Community composition</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Conservation</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Macroinvertebrates</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Macrophytes</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Temporary ponds</style></keyword></keywords><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2009</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1. A high proportion of ponds are temporary in nature, although the biodiversity value of such sites is still poorly recognized. This work explores the plant and macroinvertebrate communities of 76 temporary and fluctuating water bodies in two regions of southern England (Lizard Peninsula, Cornwall and New Forest, Hampshire) that have retained high pond densities. The ecology and conservation status of sites is examined, and comparisons made with ponds elsewhere in England and Wales. 2. Lizard and New Forest ponds supported 119 plant and 165 macroinvertebrate species respectively. Patterns of community similarity for plants and macroinvertebrates were highly concordant, taxa being related in a similar manner to measured environmental variables including pond area, depth, pH and water chemistry. 3. Patterns of pond occupancy revealed that most species were locally rare, over half occurring in less than 10% of ponds, and less than 10% being recorded from more than 50% of sites. More than 50% of ponds supported at least one nationally rare plant and almost 75%at least one nationally rare macroinvertebrate. These taxa occupied a wide range of pond types in each region, and did not have predictably different ecologies from common species. 4. Comparisons with ponds elsewhere in England and Wales revealed that Lizard and New Forest communities are nationally distinct, being most similar to ponds in areas of low intensity agriculture elsewhere in western Britain. Individual ponds in both regions supported more nationally rare taxa, on average, than ponds sampled in the national survey. 5. Ponds in the two areas have high conservation value, both regionally and nationally, supporting almost 75% of the global species richness of temporary ponds sampled across England and Wales. Within each region, many taxa are found in relatively few sites, and effective conservation of pond biodiversity will require a regional management approach. © 2009 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 7&#xD;Export Date: 16 November 2011&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-65249093292&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=90413fafa0bd8ed4efa12a5ac3f7f2e0</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/store/10.1002/aqc.973/asset/973_ftp.pdf?v=1&amp;t=h0ceew87&amp;s=648694514df0d34c54ac502c218267bd9de98509</style></url></related-urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Bilton-2009-Ecology and conserva-0321579009/Bilton-2009-Ecology and conserva.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="130_Hampshire_Downs_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\130_Hampshire_Downs_Shortlist.enl">130_Hampshire_Downs_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>119</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="pesa09zzlza298e2xem5erswdp5s90vxtdav">119</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Booker, D. J.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Sear, D. A.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Anderson, D. G.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Damon, W.</style></author></authors></contributors><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">A load cell based continuous recording bedload trap</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Earth Surface Processes &amp; Landforms</style></secondary-title></titles><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">659</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">25</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">6</style></number><keywords><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">TEMPERATURE effect</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">GEOMORPHOLOGY</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">INSTRUMENTATION technicians</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">England (Hampshire, Highland Water)</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Instrumentation</style></keyword></keywords><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2000</style></year></dates><isbn><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">01979337</style></isbn><accession-num><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">8434362</style></accession-num><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">This paper reviews the design and performance of pit-type bedload traps that use pressure pillow and load cell systems to measure the accumulation of sediment. A low cost load cell bedload sampler design ispresented. Using a specially designed cradle, a single load cell maybe used to measure the load applied on the bottom of an aluminium box of 0727 m&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;. Bedload enters the trap through a 072 m wideslot cut into a hinged plate on top of the trap. Low profile fences were fitted to the sides of the slot to prevent lateral ingress of sediment. The load cell system converts the immersed weight of sedimentdirectly into an analogue voltage reading that can be stored on a datalogger. Because the load cell is sealed, pressure correction for the water column height is negated. Temperature correction is shown to be necessary for each load cell. The results of laboratory and field calibrations are presented and design improvements suggested. Field data output is illustrated. [ABSTRACT FROM AUTHOR]&#xD;Copyright of Earth Surface Processes &amp; Landforms is the property of John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd and its content may not be copied or emailed to multiple sites or posted to a listserv without the copyright holder&apos;s express written permission. However, users may print, download, or email articles for individual use. This abstract may be abridged. No warranty is given about the accuracy of the copy. Users should refer to the original published version of the material for the full abstract. (Copyright applies to all Abstracts.)</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Booker, D. J.; Sear, D. A.; Anderson, D. G.; Damon, W.; Issue Info: Jun2000, Vol. 25 Issue 6, p659; Thesaurus Term: TEMPERATURE effect; Thesaurus Term: GEOMORPHOLOGY; Subject Term: INSTRUMENTATION technicians; Author-Supplied Keyword: England (Hampshire, Highland Water); Author-Supplied Keyword: Geomorphology; Author-Supplied Keyword: Instrumentation; Author-Supplied Keyword: Temperature effect; Number of Pages: 0p; Document Type: Article</style></notes><work-type><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Article</style></work-type><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://search.ebscohost.com.ezproxy.liv.ac.uk/login.aspx?direct=true&amp;db=eih&amp;AN=8434362&amp;site=eds-live&amp;scope=site</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/store/10.1002/1096-9837(200006)25:6&lt;659::AID-ESP100&gt;3.0.CO;2-5/asset/100_ftp.pdf?v=1&amp;t=h0cecbhv&amp;s=b3867e6d1099f3f24c3a7bebbfe45d8991097748</style></url></related-urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Booker-2000-A load cell based co-3458797313/Booker-2000-A load cell based co.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><remote-database-name><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">eih</style></remote-database-name><remote-database-provider><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">EBSCOhost</style></remote-database-provider></record><record><database name="130_Hampshire_Downs_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\130_Hampshire_Downs_Shortlist.enl">130_Hampshire_Downs_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>113</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="pesa09zzlza298e2xem5erswdp5s90vxtdav">113</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Booker, D. J.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Sear, D. A.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Payne, A. J.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">University of Southampton, Department of Geography, Southampton, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Modelling three-dimensional flow structures and patterns of boundary shear stress in a natural pool-riffle sequence</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Earth Surface Processes and Landforms</style></secondary-title></titles><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">553-576</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">26</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">5</style></number><keywords><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Hydrogeology</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">21</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Geomorphology</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">23</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">boundary conditions</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">channels</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">data processing</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">England</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Europe</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">field studies</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">flows</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">fluid dynamics</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">fluvial features</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">geomorphology</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Great Britain</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Hampshire England</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Highland Water</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">least-squares analysis</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">mathematical models</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">models</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">New Forest</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">pools</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">riffles</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">shear stress</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">simulation</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">SSIIM model</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">statistical analysis</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">surface water</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">three-dimensional models</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">United Kingdom</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Western Europe</style></keyword></keywords><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2001</style></year></dates><pub-location><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">United Kingdom</style></pub-location><publisher><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Wiley &amp; Sons : Chichester, United Kingdom</style></publisher><isbn><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">0197-9337</style></isbn><accession-num><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2001-040912</style></accession-num><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Fluid-sediment interactions control river channel forms and processes. Analysis of spatial hydraulic patterns and the resulting boundary shear stress are required to aid understanding of river system behaviour. In this paper, the hydraulic processes active in a natural pool-riffle sequence are simulated using a three-dimensional computationalfluid dynamics (CFD) model. Methods employed for the prescription ofmodel boundary conditions are outlined. Model calculations are assessed using comparisons with field observations acquired over a range of flows. Simulations are then used to illustrate flow structures and patterns of boundary shear stress for a near-bankfull and an intermediate flow event. Results are used to assess existing theories that seek to explain the development and maintenance of pool-riffle sequences. Simulated results suggest that near-bed velocities and bed shear stresses decrease on riffles and increase in pools as discharge increases. Model simulations indicate that secondary flow acts to route near-bed flow over the downstream side of riffles and into the pool-headaway from the centre of pools. Implications for sediment transport and pool maintenance are discussed. [ABSTRACT FROM AUTHOR]&#xD;Copyright of Earth Surface Processes &amp; Landforms is the property of John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd and its content may not be copied or emailed to multiple sites or posted to a listserv without the copyright holder&apos;s express written permission. However, users may print, download, or email articles for individual use. This abstract may be abridged. No warranty is given about the accuracy of the copy. Users should refer to the original published version of the material for the full abstract. (Copyright applies to all Abstracts.)</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Language: English; Coordinates: N504500N504500W0014500W0014500; Coden: ESPRDT; Collation: 24; Publication Types: Serial; Updated Code: 200112; Illustration(s): illus. incl. 1 plate, 4 tables, sketch map; Number of References: 47; Reviewed Item: Analytic</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://search.ebscohost.com.ezproxy.liv.ac.uk/login.aspx?direct=true&amp;db=geh&amp;AN=2001-040912&amp;site=eds-live&amp;scope=site</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/store/10.1002/esp.210/asset/210_ftp.pdf?v=1&amp;t=h0cec42m&amp;s=863b9550311a5d41e5656f79ad474b0222d856ca</style></url></related-urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Booker-2001-Modelling three-dime-4045989121/Booker-2001-Modelling three-dime.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><remote-database-name><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">geh</style></remote-database-name><remote-database-provider><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">EBSCOhost</style></remote-database-provider></record></records></xml>