<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><xml><records><record><database name="147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl">147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>4</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="2s50ds55250591ewrto5ztd7zwz59v2evpdx">4</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Allen, L. G.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Gibbard, P. L.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Subdepartment of Quaternary Research, Botany School, University of Cambridge, Downing Street, Cambridge, CB2 3EA, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Pleistocene evolution of the Solent River of southern England</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Quaternary Science Reviews</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Quaternary Science Reviews</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">503-528</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">12</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">7</style></number><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1993</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">The Solent River no longer exists since most of its course was drowned by eustatic sea level rise during the Flandrian Stage (Holocene). Previously, it flowed eastwards across southeast Dorset and south Hampshire as an extension of the River Frome. As such, it formed the axial major stream of the Hampshire Basin. A sequence of fluvial aggradations, ranging in height from 125 m O.D. to below sea level, provide evidence of the former courses of this substantial river and its tributaries. Detailed study of the deposits, supported by analysis of clast lithological assemblages provide the basis for the recognition of a series of lithostratigraphical units throughout the area. The facies and sedimentary structures indicate that the bulk of the deposits accumulated in a braided river environment under periglacial climates. Late Pleistocene fossiliferous sediments of Ipswichian and Flandrian age provide a biostratigraphical framework. The results demonstrate that the Solent River was a substantial system, comparable in size to the present Thames, and was a tributary of the &apos;Channel River&apos; during periods of low sea level (cold stages). Evolution of the river reflects its response to climatic change, local geological structure and long term tectonic activity. Although datable deposits limit determination of the age of the Solent River sequence, it is undoubtedly of considerable antiquity and potentially extends back to the Early Pleistocene. Discussion of the sequence includes placing the events within their regional context. © 1994.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 35&#xD;Export Date: 9 January 2012&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-0027843543&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=3207a149c958d542a36d0b667b3d3dbd</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.sciencedirect.com.ezproxy.liv.ac.uk/science/article/pii/027737919390075W</style></url></related-urls></urls></record><record><database name="147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl">147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>7</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="2s50ds55250591ewrto5ztd7zwz59v2evpdx">7</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Allison, R. J.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Kimber, O. G.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Department of Geography, University of Durham, Science Laboratories, Durham DH1 3LE, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Modelling failure mechanisms to explain rock slope change along the Isle of Purbeck coast, UK</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Earth Surface Processes and Landforms</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Earth Surface Processes and Landforms</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">731-750</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">23</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">8</style></number><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1998</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Results are presented of distinct element computer modelling used to examine rates and mechanisms of change in rock slopes and cliffs, where material intact properties determine process and form but but the most significant controls are the joint pattern and cross-joint properties. The modelling approach does not appear to have been used before in a geomorphological context and provides an alternative approach for examining cliff development. Field and laboratory data have been collected for the Portland Limestone outcrop of the Isle of Purbeck, central southern England. The Portland Limestone is a hard, shelly, crystalline sediment of the Upper Jurassic. It has a regular discontinuity pattern throughout the outcrop in Purbeck. While joint orientation remains relatively constant, bedding changes from horizontal to vertical, a consequence of the Purbeck Monocline. There are resulting implications for spatial variations in rock slope evolution. The modelling exercise enhances previous knowledge on rock failure mechanisms and slope development along the Purbeck coast and demonstrates its potential in research where landforms are developed in lithified, jointed rock masses.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 9&#xD;Export Date: 9 January 2012&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-0031763572&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=d78338ee4d582fda848785ef6d921b42</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/store/10.1002/(SICI)1096-9837(199808)23:8&lt;731::AID-ESP885&gt;3.0.CO;2-F/asset/885_ftp.pdf?v=1&amp;t=h02gtyc6&amp;s=f089581da78626cddb17d2287f7a2c4f36c2d29a</style></url></related-urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Allison-1998-Modelling failure me-3375276545/Allison-1998-Modelling failure me.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl">147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>8</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="2s50ds55250591ewrto5ztd7zwz59v2evpdx">8</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Anderson, E.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Passmore, D. G.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Centre for Quaternary Science, Coventry University, Priory Street, Coventry CW 5FB, United Kingdom&#xD;School of Geography, Middlesex University, Queensway, Enfield EN3 4SF, United Kingdom&#xD;Department of Geography, Newcastle University, Tyneside N El 7RU, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">A small glacial cirque basin on Exmoor, Somerset Stephan Harrison</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Proceedings of the Geologists&apos; Association</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Proceedings of the Geologists&apos; Association</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">149-158</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">109</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2</style></number><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1998</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Geomorphological and sedimentological investigations at the Punchbowl on Exmoor, north Somerset, have demonstrated evidence of cirque basin glaciation, some 30 km south of the accepted southern limit of Anglian ice cover in this area. The Punchbowl is a steep-sided, north-facing basin that has a subdued arcuate ridge at its mouth. Analysis of macrofabrics, clast form and roundness and particle size on sediments forming the ridge indicate it to consist of glacial diamict deposited as a terminal moraine. Further evidence supporting the presence of a former cirque basin glacier at this site is derived from basin morphology and a striated sandstone boulder. Palaeoglacier reconstruction gives a surface area of 0.38 km2, a maximum thickness of 46.5 m and a maximum basal shear stress value of 51 kPa. The ELA of the former glacier has been calculated at 334 m OD. There is no evidence for multiple glaciations at this site, and, in the absence of dating controls on the moraine, the glacier is provisionally assumed to have formed during severe climatic conditions associated with the southerly advance of ice sheets during the Anglian cold stage or during the Dimlington Stadial. Development of a glacier at this location appears to have been a rare event during the Quaternary, and may have been facilitated by accumulation of windblown snow from the adjacent plateau. © 1998 Geologists&apos; Association.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 10&#xD;Export Date: 23 December 2011&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-0032469577&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=466b671312f19f8aff584c923e565111</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.sciencedirect.com.ezproxy.liv.ac.uk/science/article/pii/S001678789880014X</style></url></related-urls></urls></record><record><database name="147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl">147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>10</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="2s50ds55250591ewrto5ztd7zwz59v2evpdx">10</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Baily, B.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Collier, P.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Farres, P.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Inkpen, R.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Pearson, A.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Department of Geography, University of Portsmouth, Burnaby Road, Portsmouth PO1 3HE, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Comparative assessment of analytical and digital photogrammetric methods in the construction of dems of geomorphological forms</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Earth Surface Processes and Landforms</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Earth Surface Processes and Landforms</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">307-320</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">28</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">3</style></number><keywords><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Adaptive and non-adaptive strategies</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Analytical photogrammetry</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Automatic terrain extraction</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Digital photogrammetry</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Global positioning system</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Photo-control</style></keyword></keywords><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2003</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Traditionally, landforms have been measured using a combination of field survey techniques and analogue and analytical photogrammetry. With advances in computing power digital photogrammetric solutions are now seen as offering an affordable and cost effective way of mapping topographic features. This paper looks at the relative merits of each of these photogrammetric techniques, in terms of the practical considerations involved in data extraction and accuracies that can be achieved for a case study. The site investigated is Maiden Castle. situated southwest of Dorchester in Dorset, UK. This paper examines the relative accuracies of both digital and analytical photogrammetric techniques in relation to ground control points recorded using a global positioning system (GPS). Colour stereoscopic aerial photographs were laken of Maiden Castle. Dorset, in November 1999 at a scale of approximately 1:4000. Stereo models were constructed using pre-marked ground control points positioned using post-processed differential GPS. Subsequent analysis involved the calculation of residual values produced by comparing the computer-generated surface with a set of test points measured using differential GPS. This research demonstrates that the optimal digital system matched the performance of analytical photogrammetry for the collection of geomorphological data. © 2003 John Wiley and Sons. Ltd.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 19&#xD;Export Date: 9 January 2012&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-0037357024&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=295288c456824a1a7cad69e8cd2d613e</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/store/10.1002/esp.481/asset/481_ftp.pdf?v=1&amp;t=h02gtj4p&amp;s=8e895c4a22386531a4da20e40bfb2f9c23ff6293</style></url></related-urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Baily-2003-Comparative assessme-3593359873/Baily-2003-Comparative assessme.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl">147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>11</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="2s50ds55250591ewrto5ztd7zwz59v2evpdx">11</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Baird, A. J.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Gaffney, S. W.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Department of Geography, University of Sheffield, Winter Street, Sheffield S10 2TN, United Kingdom&#xD;World-wide Intellectual Resources Exchange (WIRE) Ltd., Sussex Innovation Centre, Science Park Square, Falmer BN1 9SB, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Solute movement in drained fen peat: A field tracer study in a Somerset (UK) wetland</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Hydrological Processes</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Hydrological Processes</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2489-2503</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">14</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">14</style></number><keywords><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Bypassing flow</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Fen peat</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Hydrology</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Solute transport</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Somerset Moors (UK)</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Tracer</style></keyword></keywords><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2000</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Little is known about solute transport in peats, despite the obvious importance of solute transport on eco-hydrological processes in both managed and natural peatlands. To address this lack of knowledge, we investigated solute transport processes in an agricultural fen peat using a conservative KBr tracer. The main aim of the study was to elucidate solute transport behaviour in general in this peat, with a more specific aim of investigating whether preferential or bypassing flow occurred. The tracer moved through the peat more rapidly than expected, and the pattern of movement showed clear evidence of plot-scale bypassing flow. The data also provide evidence that bypassing flow occurs in pores at smaller scales. The implications of this study for management of wetland pastures in the Somerset Moors in south-west England are discussed. Copyright (C) 2000 John Wiley and Sons, Ltd. Little is known about solute transport in peats, despite the obvious importance of solute transport on ecohydrological processes in both managed and natural peatlands. To address this lack of knowledge, we investigated solute transport processes in an agricultural fen peat using a conservative KBr tracer. The main aim of the study was to elucidate solute transport behaviour in general in this peat, with a more specific aim of investigating whether preferential or bypassing flow occurred. The tracer moved through the peat more rapidly than expected, and the pattern of movement showed clear evidence of plot-scale bypassing flow. The data also provide evidence that bypassing flow occurs in pores at smaller scales. The implications of this study for management of wetland pastures in the Somerset Moors in south-west England are discussed.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 11&#xD;Export Date: 23 December 2011&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-0034298236&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=19be10def2dc1ac86a5fc1a046d3554e</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/store/10.1002/1099-1085(20001015)14:14&lt;2489::AID-HYP110&gt;3.0.CO;2-Q/asset/110_ftp.pdf?v=1&amp;t=h02gtqph&amp;s=0e9a735c5102d369a3f1e36bf9940f7ac650cf28</style></url></related-urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Baird-2000-Solute movement in d-2234416129/Baird-2000-Solute movement in d.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl">147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>12</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="2s50ds55250591ewrto5ztd7zwz59v2evpdx">12</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Baker, A.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Caseldine, C. J.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Hatton, J.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Hawkesworth, C. J.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Latham, A. C.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Department of Geography, University of Exeter, Amory Building, Rennes Drive, Exeter, EX4 4RJ, United Kingdom&#xD;Earth Sciences Department, Open University, Walton Hall, Milton Keynes, MK7 6AA, United Kingdom&#xD;Dept. of Archaeological Sciences, University of Liverpool, Liverpool, L69 3BX, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">A Cromerian complex stalagmite from the Mendip Hills, England</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Journal of Quaternary Science</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Journal of Quaternary Science</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">533-537</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">12</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">6</style></number><keywords><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cromerian Complex</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Palaeomagnetism</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Pollen</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Stalagmite</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Uranium series</style></keyword></keywords><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1997</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">In order to provide a better chronological constraint on a British Middle Pleistocene interglacial, a large stalagmite boss from the Mendip Hills was selected for palaeoclimate data using pollen analysis. Dating analyses by thermal ionisation mass spectrometry (TIMS) of uranium-thorium ratios and by magnetostratigraphy constrain the age of the sample to 450-780 ka. The isotopic consistency of the TIMS analyses, plus the presence of luminescence laminations, suggest that the sample has been preserved under closed-system conditions. Pollen assemblages have been recovered from the speleothems, despite the fact that the pH of calcite deposition is usually greater than 7. Furthermore the evidence presented here indicates that the pollen was probably transported by the speleothem feedwater, rather than entering the cave aerially. The pollen record contained within the stalagmite is interpreted as early-mid-interglacial but does not have clear Cromerian affinity. © 1997 by John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 2&#xD;Export Date: 23 December 2011&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-0031428832&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=4b8821765de1325745ae1bfabbe74208</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/store/10.1002/(SICI)1099-1417(199711/12)12:6&lt;533::AID-JQS349&gt;3.0.CO;2-L/asset/349_ftp.pdf?v=1&amp;t=h02gu6aa&amp;s=42263ce41d031551b6ea9d878f83fbdaf75a2d42</style></url></related-urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Baker-1997-A Cromerian complex-2653865473/Baker-1997-A Cromerian complex.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl">147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>14</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="2s50ds55250591ewrto5ztd7zwz59v2evpdx">14</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Ballantine, D.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Walling, D. E.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Leeks, G. J. L.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Department of Geography, University of Exeter, Amory Building, Rennes Drive, Exeter EX4 4RJ, United Kingdom&#xD;Centre for Ecology and Hydrology, Wallingford, Oxfordshire OX10 8BB, United Kingdom&#xD;NIWA, Aquatic Pollution, Gate 10, Silverdale Road, Hamilton 3216, New Zealand</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Mobilisation and transport of sediment-associated phosphorus by surface runoff</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Water, Air, and Soil Pollution</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Water, Air, and Soil Pollution</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">311-320</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">196</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1-4</style></number><keywords><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Deposited sediment</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Enrichment</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Erosion</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Land use</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Phosphorus</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Runoff</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Runoff sediment</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Sediment</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Selectivity</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Soil type</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Transport</style></keyword></keywords><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2009</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Surface runoff transporting sediment with high phosphorus (P) concentrations has been identified as a major hydrological pathway for sediment-associated P delivery to surface waters and is considered a major threat to water quality, due to the ability of P to cause eutrophication in fresh water. Not all P-rich sediment that is mobilised by erosion will however be delivered directly to the channel. Some may instead be deposited in intermediate storage away from its source area. The aim of this contribution was to determine the influence of land use and soil type on the P content of surface runoff sediment and sediment deposited in intermediate storage and was undertaken in the largely agricultural and rural catchments of the Rivers Frome and Piddle in Dorset, UK. The study formed part of a larger investigation of hydrological and hydrogeochemical processes and fluxes in lowland permeable catchments in the UK (LOCAR). Soil samples were collected from the main land use types; freshly deposited sediment was sampled from ditches, hedge boundaries and depressions in fields, and sediment-laden runoff was collected during heavy rainfall events. The concentrations of total phosphorus (TP) and the P fractions found in the surface runoff sediment were significantly different from those measured in the original source soils, with a greater degree of enrichment associated with surface runoff sediment from cultivated land than from pasture land. For cultivated land, concentrations of TP and the P fractions in deposited sediment were higher than those in the original source material, while for pasture soils, concentrations of TP and the P fractions tended to be lower than in the original source soils. The relative importance of the P fractions associated with surface runoff sediment and sediment deposits also differed from that for the original soil samples. Surface runoff sediment was finer than source pasture and cultivated soils, reflecting the particle size selectivity of sediment mobilisation and transport. Soil physical properties and land use can both influence the P content of surface runoff and deposited sediment. © 2008 Springer Science+Business Media B.V.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 6&#xD;Export Date: 9 January 2012&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-58149477885&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=ada13ca6744a3915d83f60432bc923ab</style></url></related-urls></urls></record><record><database name="147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl">147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>15</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="2s50ds55250591ewrto5ztd7zwz59v2evpdx">15</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Ballantine, D. J.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Walling, D. E.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Collins, A. L.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Leeks, G. J. L.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Department of Geography, University of Exeter, Exeter EX4 4RJ, United Kingdom&#xD;Centre for Ecology and Hydrology, Wallingford, Oxfordshire OX10 8BB, United Kingdom&#xD;SEPA, Carseview Hse, Castle Business Park, Stirling FK9 5AD, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Phosphorus storage in fine channel bed sediments</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Water, Air, and Soil Pollution: Focus</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Water, Air, and Soil Pollution: Focus</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">371-380</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">6</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">5-6</style></number><keywords><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Bed sediment</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Phosphorus</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Storage</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Study area</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">UK</style></keyword></keywords><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2006</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Deposition and storage of fine sediment on channel beds represents an important component of a catchment&apos;s sediment budget and can have important implications for sediment-associated P fluxes, due to storage and remobilisation, and for P concentrations through water-sediment interactions. Spatial and temporal variations in P content and storage in fine bed sediment have been studied in two UK lowland catchments, the Rivers Frome and Piddle in Dorset. Fine bed sediment was sampled in representative reaches on a bi-monthly basis using a re-suspension cylinder, and the resulting samples were analysed for total P, a range of P fractions and particle size. The results demonstrate significant spatial and temporal variability in PP concentrations and storage, with maximum and minimum P concentrations and storage occurring in late summer and winter, respectively. Temporal variations in concentrations reflect residence times of the sediment and ambient P concentrations, while variations in storage are mainly due to hydrological regimes. Spatial variations reflect catchment characteristics, the location of inputs and local variations in hydrological and channel bed conditions. © Springer Science+Business Media B.V. 2006.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 5&#xD;Export Date: 9 January 2012&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-33845936043&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=4b34f41f7294de3b52c3ae25431d65d8</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.springerlink.com.ezproxy.liv.ac.uk/content/f72t378438465410/fulltext.pdf</style></url></related-urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Ballantine-2006-Phosphorus storage i-0405729537/Ballantine-2006-Phosphorus storage i.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl">147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>16</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="2s50ds55250591ewrto5ztd7zwz59v2evpdx">16</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Ballantine, D. J.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Walling, D. E.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Collins, A. L.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Leeks, G. J. L.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Department of Geography, SOGAER, University of Exeter, Rennes Drive, Exeter, EX4 6RJ, United Kingdom&#xD;CEH Wallingford, Maclean Building, Crowmarsh Gifford, Wallingford OX10 8BB, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">The phosphorus content of fluvial suspended sediment in three lowland groundwater-dominated catchments</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Journal of Hydrology</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Journal of Hydrology</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">140-151</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">357</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1-2</style></number><keywords><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Groundwater-dominated catchments</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Phosphorus</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Spatial variation</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Suspended sediment</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Temporal variation</style></keyword></keywords><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2008</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">This paper reports an investigation of the phosphorus (P) content of fluvial suspended sediment samples collected from three lowland groundwater-dominated agricultural catchments in the UK. In-stream trap samplers were installed at a total of 21 locations in the catchments of the Rivers Frome and Piddle in Dorset and in the Upper Tern in Shropshire, UK. Time-integrated suspended sediment samples (n = 187) were collected at regular intervals over a period of 22 months and analysed for total phosphorus (TP), inorganic phosphorus (IP), organic phosphorus (OP) and algal available phosphorus (AAP). TP concentrations varied between sampling sites in the Rivers Frome and Piddle, allowing key P inputs to be identified, while fractionation of P assisted in identifying the nature of these inputs. There was also significant variation in both the TP concentration and the concentration of individual fractions between the Frome and Piddle catchments and the Upper Tern. These contrasts were attributed to the differing underlying geologies, since the Frome and Piddle are underlain predominantly by chalk, whilst the Upper Tern is underlain by sandstone, and also to the different soil types present. The TP content of suspended sediment collected from the Frome catchment showed a statistically significant relationship with specific surface area, but this relationship was not found for the remaining catchments. Temporal variation in P concentrations at both the seasonal and event scale was also investigated. Seasonal variations were noted for TP concentrations and for the concentrations of IP, OP and AAP in all the study catchments, but no consistent seasonal patterns were discernible. Maximum and minimum concentrations of the individual fractions occurred during different months in each of the study catchments, suggesting that different controls operated in the individual catchments. Short-term temporal variations in TP concentrations were documented for two high flow events. Concentrations were lower during high flow events than in baseflow, reflecting dilution. © 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 3&#xD;Export Date: 9 January 2012&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-45949100341&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=fd1076395521c1e0124d2c8d9dde0784</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.sciencedirect.com.ezproxy.liv.ac.uk/science/article/pii/S0022169408002369</style></url></related-urls></urls></record><record><database name="147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl">147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>17</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="2s50ds55250591ewrto5ztd7zwz59v2evpdx">17</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Bennett, M. R.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cassidy, N. J.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Pile, J.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">School of Conservation Sciences, Bournemouth University, Talbot Campus, Fern Barrow, Poole, BH12 5BB, United Kingdom&#xD;School of Physical and Geographical Sciences, Keele University, Keele, Staffordshire ST5 5BG, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Internal structure of a barrier beach as revealed by ground penetrating radar (GPR): Chesil beach, UK</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Geomorphology</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Geomorphology</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">218-229</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">104</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">3-4</style></number><keywords><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Barrier beaches</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Chesil Beach</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Ground Penetrating Radar</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Sea-level rise</style></keyword></keywords><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2009</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Chesil Beach (Dorset) is one of the most famous coastal landforms on the British coast. The gravel beach is over 18 km long and is separated for much of its length from land by a tidal lagoon known as The Fleet. The beach links the Isle of Portland in the east to the mainland in the west. Despite its iconic status there is little available information on its internal geometry and evolutionary history. Here we present a three-fold model for the evolution of Chesil Beach based on a series of nine ground penetrating radar (GPR) traverses located at three sites along its length at Abbotsbury, Langton Herring and at Ferry Bridge. The GPR traverses reveal a remarkably consistent picture of the internal structure of this barrier beach. The first phase of evolution involves the landward transgression of a small sand and gravel beach which closed upon the coast leading to deposition of freshwater peat between 5 and 7 k yr BP. The second evolutionary phase involves the &apos;bulking-out&apos; of the beach during continued sea level rise, but in the presence of abundant gravel supplied by down-drift erosion of periglacial slope deposits. This episode of growth was associated with a series of washover fans which accumulated on the landward flank of the barrier increasing its breadth and height but without significant landward transgression of the barrier as a whole. The final phase in the evolution of Chesil Beach involves the seaward progradation of the beach crest and upper beach face associated with continued sediment abundance, but during a still-stand or slight fall in relative sea level. This phase may provide further evidence of a slight fall in relative sea level noted elsewhere along the South Coast of Britain and dated to between 1.2 and 2.4 k yr BP. Subsequently the barrier appears to have become largely inactive, except for the reworking of sediment on the beach face during storm events. The case study not only refines the evolutionary picture of Chesil Beach, but illustrates the importance of the subtle interplay between relative sea level and sediment supply in the evolution of a barrier system. In addition, it also illustrates the potential of GPR in resolving the evolutionary history of gravel-rich coastal landforms such as Chesil Beach. © 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 3&#xD;Export Date: 9 January 2012&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-58349093706&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=ec83903b32aef430644752acd9983ad9</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.sciencedirect.com.ezproxy.liv.ac.uk/science/article/pii/S0169555X08003929</style></url></related-urls></urls></record><record><database name="147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl">147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>21</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="2s50ds55250591ewrto5ztd7zwz59v2evpdx">21</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Bowes, M. J.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Leach, D. V.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">House, W. A.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Centre for Ecology and Hydrology, Winfrith Technology Centre, Dorchester, Dorset DT2 8ZD, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Seasonal nutrient dynamics in a chalk stream: The River Frome, Dorset, UK</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Science of the Total Environment</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Science of the Total Environment</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">225-241</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">336</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1-3</style></number><keywords><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Chalk stream</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Mass balance</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Nitrate</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Nutrient dynamics</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Phosphorus</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Silicon</style></keyword></keywords><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2005</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Chalk streams provide unique, environmentally important habitats, but are particularly susceptible to human activities, such as water abstraction, fish farming and intensive agricultural activity on their fertile flood-meadows, resulting in increased nutrient concentrations. Weekly phosphorus, nitrate, dissolved silicon, chloride and flow measurements were made at nine sites along a 32 km stretch of the River Frome and its tributaries, over a 15 month period. The stretch was divided into two sections (termed the middle and lower reach) and mass balances were calculated for each determinand by totalling the inputs from upstream, tributaries, sewage treatment works and an estimate of groundwater input, and subtracting this from the load exported from each reach. Phosphorus and nitrate were retained within the river channel during the summer months, due to bioaccumulation into river biota and adsorption of phosphorus to bed sediments. During the autumn to spring periods, there was a net export, attributed to increased diffuse inputs from the catchment during storms, decomposition of channel biomass and remobilisation of phosphorus from the bed sediment. This seasonality of retention and remobilisation was higher in the lower reach than the middle reach, which was attributed to downstream changes in land use and fine sediment availability. Silicon showed much less seasonality, but did have periods of rapid retention in spring, due to diatom uptake within the river channel, and a subsequent release from the bed sediments during storm events. Chloride did not produce a seasonal pattern, indicating that the observed phosphorus and nitrate seasonality was a product of annual variation in diffuse inputs and internal riverine processes, rather than an artefact of sampling, flow gauging and analytical errors. © 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 28&#xD;Export Date: 9 January 2012&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-10344232647&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=9c5ce54f3f68962e44c64f6b88d297c4</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.sciencedirect.com.ezproxy.liv.ac.uk/science/article/pii/S0048969704004577</style></url></related-urls></urls></record><record><database name="147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl">147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>24</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="2s50ds55250591ewrto5ztd7zwz59v2evpdx">24</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Bray, M. J.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Department of Geography, University of Portsmouth, Portsmouth, PO1 3HE, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Episodic shingle supply and the modified development of Chesil Beach, England</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Journal of Coastal Research</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Journal of Coastal Research</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1035-1049</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">13</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">4</style></number><keywords><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Bluff</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cell</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cliff</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Dorset</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Drift</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Erosion</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Gravel beach</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Littoral</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Protection</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Sediment budget</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Shingle</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Shoreline management</style></keyword></keywords><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1997</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">This paper illustrates a budget approach to investigate and manage littoral sediment for coastal defence within an integrated process system in west Dorset, England. The budget is quantified in terms of inputs, transfers, storage and outputs of sediment within a littoral cell. Complex, long established links are demonstrated between eroding cliff sediment sources and a sequence of pocket shingle beaches that they supply. Sediment inputs and subsequent transfers are found to be episodic so that the beaches naturally alternate between open and closed system states according to prevailing transport conditions. Interestingly, the major storm barrier of Chesil Beach is identified as the ultimate shingle sink. These results suggest that the beach did not simply develop as a product of the Holocene transgression as often envisioned, but until recently, it formed part of a larger natural process system with the periodic input of additional shingle from the west, derived from the erosion of massive unstable cliffs. However, several interventions have dislocated these natural linkages, unwittingly reinforcing the closed system states. In the absence of natural replenishment, the modified beaches are becoming increasingly sensitive to the continuing relative sea-level rise and storm activity that characterises this region. Attention is drawn to the need to establish such understanding prior to undertaking additional interventions. Details are provided of the ways in which this information has assisted in the control of beach mining and future management policies are suggested.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 20&#xD;Export Date: 9 January 2012&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-0030871006&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=58b485de2d35dc891ac4434106b3abfd</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.jstor.org.ezproxy.liv.ac.uk/stable/pdfplus/4298713.pdf?acceptTC=true</style></url></related-urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Bray-1997-Episodic shingle sup-0439305729/Bray-1997-Episodic shingle sup.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl">147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>26</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="2s50ds55250591ewrto5ztd7zwz59v2evpdx">26</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Brunsden, D.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Department of Geomorphology, Department of Geography, King&apos;s College, London WC2R 2LS, Canada</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Geomorphological roulette for engineers and planners: Some insights into an old game</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Quarterly Journal of Engineering Geology and Hydrogeology</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Quarterly Journal of Engineering Geology and Hydrogeology</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">101-142</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">35</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2</style></number><keywords><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Applied geomorphology</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Case history</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Engineering geomorphology</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Event frequency and magnitude</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Geomorphological concepts</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Human well-being</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Inheritance</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Planning</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Risk</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Systems</style></keyword></keywords><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2002</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Engineers have always appreciated that a civil engineering project should be based on a clear understanding of the geomorphology of the site of the proposed works. It is an old &apos;game&apos;! However, although it is good practice to take full account of the morphology and processes of the land-scape during an investigation there is a tendency to restrict the work to basic mapping and identification of features rather than a true understanding of the site in space and time. Particular criticisms are that not enough attention is paid to the effects of landform change, the identification of inherited material conditions, the frequency and magnitude of processes and the nature of risk. Ways of improving the service are identified. It is suggested that future work should be based on a full understanding of the conceptual basis for modern geomorphology. In the past thirty years there has been a revolution in the theoretical basis of the subject as well as a remarkable improvement in the technical capability. A major statement is therefore made on the nature of geomorphology and this is then summarized as a possible conceptual basis for application to engineering and planning. The theme of the paper will be illustrated by a description of the Lyme Regis Environmental Improvements Scheme in West Dorset which is in the design stage and has been based on a full understanding of the geomorphology and geology of the area and the employment of a Geo-Team at all stages of the project.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 15&#xD;Export Date: 9 January 2012&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-0036271422&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=b45357f6b22209d06b2fe1ad1766479b</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://qjegh.geoscienceworld.org/content/35/2/101.full.pdf</style></url></related-urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Brunsden-2002-Geomorphological rou-1278175745/Brunsden-2002-Geomorphological rou.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl">147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>29</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="2s50ds55250591ewrto5ztd7zwz59v2evpdx">29</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Brunsden, D.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Jones, D. K. C.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Department of Geography, King&apos;s College, University of London, United Kingdom&#xD;Department of Geography, London School of Economics, University of London, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">The morphology of degraded landslide slopes in South West Dorset</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Quarterly Journal of Engineering Geology</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Quarterly Journal of Engineering Geology</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">205-222</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">5</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">3</style></number><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1972</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Geomorphological techniques, including morphological mapping and profiling have been used to investigate the distribution of old landslides on the southern slopes of the Char valley in West Dorset. It is shown that these field techniques provide data which can be usefully employed to precede and supplement geotechnical investigations. The spatial pattern of landslide morphology is described and a tentative chronology suggested. The survey reveals a similar, although more extensive and complete, pattern of landslide degradation to that reported for slides on London Clay and the Lias Clay of the East Midlands. © 1972 The Geological Society, London.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 11&#xD;Export Date: 9 January 2012&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-0000556527&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=02e38b2c5acce1ece2205a29c8be5264</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://qjegh.geoscienceworld.org/content/5/3/205.full.pdf</style></url></related-urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Brunsden-1972-The morphology of de-3929063169/Brunsden-1972-The morphology of de.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl">147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>30</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="2s50ds55250591ewrto5ztd7zwz59v2evpdx">30</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Brunsden, D.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Moore, R.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Department of Geography, King&apos;s College, London, United Kingdom&#xD;Rendel Geotechnics, Birmingham, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Engineering geomorphology on the coast: Lessons from west Dorset</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Geomorphology</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Geomorphology</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">391-409</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">31</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1-4</style></number><keywords><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Applied geomorphology</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Attitudes</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Coastal geomorphology</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Geomorphological principles</style></keyword></keywords><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1999</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">The central aim of this paper is to describe the general context in which an applied geomorphological investigation for a management project on a Heritage coast will be set. We attempt to show how the decisions may be affected by historical legacies and public or administrative attitudes. Modern attitudes to the coast in Great Britain are summarized in the light of recent studies by the Department of the Environment and the Ministry of Agriculture, Fisheries and Food. The Dorset coast in southwest England is used to illustrate the main points. The paper describes the coastal features, explains the historical legacy of use, and examines problems of contemporary coastal management. The paper concludes with a consideration of the natural geomorphological principles of landscape design which might be employed as part of the guiding concepts. (C) 1999 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 5&#xD;Export Date: 9 January 2012&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-0342368255&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=d2efdef27f20957b8e952bc67953befc</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.sciencedirect.com.ezproxy.liv.ac.uk/science/article/pii/S0169555X99000823</style></url></related-urls></urls></record><record><database name="147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl">147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>38</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="2s50ds55250591ewrto5ztd7zwz59v2evpdx">38</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Chandler, J. H.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Brunsden, D.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Dept of Civil Eng, Loughborough Univ, Loughborough, Leicestershire, UK</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Steady state behaviour of the Black Ven mudslide: the application of archival analytical photogrammetry to studies of landform change</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Earth Surface Processes &amp; Landforms</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Earth Surface Processes &amp; Landforms</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">255-275</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">20</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">3</style></number><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1995</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">The principles and limitations of the archival photogrammetric technique are described. The method is applied to oblique and vertical aerial photographs of Black Ven at five epochs, commencing in 1946, continuing at approximately 10 year intervals until 1988. The technique is used to generate plans/contours/sections and a dense and accurate digital elevation model (DEM) of the whole site at each epoch. This is used to generate &quot;DEMs of difference&apos; and a &quot;distribution of slope angle&apos; which suggest that the mudlsides are in equilibrium despite the removal of 200 000 m3 of sediment between 1958 and 1988. Extrapolation of the slope distribution through time suggests that the frequency of an episodic landform change model at Black Ven may be approximately 60 years. -from Authors</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 42&#xD;Export Date: 9 January 2012&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-0028870946&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=f881123b7acdc8c6b467aac43992ae7c</style></url></related-urls></urls></record><record><database name="147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl">147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>40</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="2s50ds55250591ewrto5ztd7zwz59v2evpdx">40</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Clarke, S. J.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Wharton, G.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cotton, J. A.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Department of English Nature, Northminster House, Northminster Rd, Peterborough PE1 1UA, United Kingdom&#xD;Centre for Aquatic and Terrestrial Environments, Department of Geography, University of London, London, United Kingdom&#xD;Environment Agency, Leeds, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Spatial and temporal variations in the sediment habitat of Ranunculus spp. in lowland chalk streams - Implications for ecological status?</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Water, Air, and Soil Pollution: Focus</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Water, Air, and Soil Pollution: Focus</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">393-401</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">6</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">5-6</style></number><keywords><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Ranunculus spp.</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">River monitoring</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Sediment</style></keyword></keywords><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2006</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Ranunculus spp. are the dominant plants of lowland chalk stream habitats in England. The spatial variability of sediment characteristics (silt-clay, organic matter, total phosphorus and total nitrogen content) within stands of Ranunculus spp. was investigated in 12 rivers in lowland England. Variability was found to be high and there were no discernible differences between samples taken from within Ranunculus and a limited number of samples from bare substrate. For two of these rivers, comparisons were also made between reaches upstream and downstream of waste water treatment works outfalls in terms of the characteristics of the sediments within Ranunculus stands. In one river a clear increase in sediment nutrient, fine and organic material content was observed downstream but in the other there was no consistent difference. Temporal variability was considered for two rivers in the Frome catchment, Dorset, by analysing the monthly variability in sediment organic matter and silt-clay content beneath Ranunculus stands over an annual cycle of growth and die-back. Whilst a clear pattern of fine and organic material retention consistent with seasonal plant growth patterns was evident at one site, the three sites displayed different temporal patterns. This inconsistency is believed to reflect differences in sediment supply at the three sites. © Springer Science+Business Media B.V. 2006.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Export Date: 9 January 2012&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-33845923903&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=ab129cfbf45bea324b2f38e81a8271fc</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.springerlink.com.ezproxy.liv.ac.uk/content/g88v4n7401342284/fulltext.pdf</style></url></related-urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Clarke-2006-Spatial and temporal-2133832961/Clarke-2006-Spatial and temporal.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl">147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>42</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="2s50ds55250591ewrto5ztd7zwz59v2evpdx">42</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Colborne, G. J. N.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Staines, S. J.</style></author></authors></contributors><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Soil erosion in Somerset and Dorset</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">SEESOIL (South East England Soils Discussion Group)</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">SEESOIL (South East England Soils Discussion Group)</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">62-71</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">3</style></volume><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1986</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">In south Somerset, where local erosion has long been a problem on very fine sandy and silty soils, 40 randomly chosen arable fields were monitored monthly from October 1982 to June 1983. Erosion was measured along fixed traverses and compared with soil attributes, site factors and cultivation practices. Winter cereals were worst affected (over a third of the fields lost more than 4 m3/ha). Bare ploughed ground eroded least, with intermediate losses on cash root fields. The larger losses from clay soils were almost entirely due to off-field water, a negligible factor on the silty soils. -from Authors</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 1&#xD;Export Date: 23 December 2011&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-0022932139&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=6d5b392822db49943b7c87d8a28d431f</style></url></related-urls></urls></record><record><database name="147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl">147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>43</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="2s50ds55250591ewrto5ztd7zwz59v2evpdx">43</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Collins, A. L.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Walling, D. E.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Department of Geography, University of Exeter, Amory Building, Rennes Drive, Exeter, Devon EX4 4RJ, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Sources of fine sediment recovered from the channel bed of lowland groundwater-fed catchments in the UK</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Geomorphology</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Geomorphology</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">120-138</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">88</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1-2</style></number><keywords><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Fine bed sediment</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Sediment fingerprinting</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Sediment sources</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Uncertainty analysis</style></keyword></keywords><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2007</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Groundwater-fed, lowland permeable catchments in the UK are particularly susceptible to fine sediment accumulation on the bed of their main channel systems. Appropriate catchment management solutions are therefore required. Accurate targeting of sediment abatement strategies is, however, hampered by the dearth of reliable information on the principal sediment sources involved. In view of this, a composite fingerprinting technique, incorporating uncertainty analysis, has been used to investigate the primary sources of fine sediment samples recovered from a total of 18 individual sampling sites on the channel bed of the rivers Frome (∼ 437 km2) and Piddle (∼ 183 km2), Dorset, UK. In the Frome study catchment, mean relative contributions from areas of woodland, pasture and cultivation, and from channel banks/subsurface sources ranged between 1 ± 1%-6 ± 2%, 10 ± 2%-42 ± 2%, 44 ± 4%-81 ± 2% and 7 ± 2%-19 ± 4%, respectively. The corresponding mean relative contributions in the Piddle study area were 1 ± 1%-11 ± 4% (woodland), 10 ± 2%-28 ± 4% (pasture), 44 ± 2%-80 ± 2% (cultivated) and 7 ± 2%-21 ± 2% (channel banks and subsurface sources). These findings have important implications for establishing a scientific basis for assisting the targeting of sediment management and control policies. © 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 9&#xD;Export Date: 9 January 2012&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-34249332700&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=6ebc1988f880efe14990d63c484ca88c</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.sciencedirect.com.ezproxy.liv.ac.uk/science/article/pii/S0169555X0600496X</style></url></related-urls></urls></record><record><database name="147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl">147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>44</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="2s50ds55250591ewrto5ztd7zwz59v2evpdx">44</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Collins, A. L.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Walling, D. E.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Department of Geography, University of Exeter, Amory Building, Rennes Drive, Exter, Devon EX4 4RJ, United Kingdom&#xD;Environment Systems, ADAS, Woodthorne, Wergs Road, Wolverhampton WV6 8TQ, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Fine-grained bed sediment storage within the main channel systems of the frome and piddle catchments, Dorset, UK</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Hydrological Processes</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Hydrological Processes</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1448-1459</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">21</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">11</style></number><keywords><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Channel bed sediment storage</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Lowland permeable catchments</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Sediment budget</style></keyword></keywords><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2007</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Lowland permeable catchments in the UK are particularly prone to sedimentation problems, on account of the increased fine sediment loadings generated by recent land-use change and their stable seasonal hydrological regimes, which are frequently depleted by groundwater abstraction. Fine-grained sediment storage on the bed of the main channel systems of the Frome (437 km2) and Piddle (183 km2) catchments, Dorset, UK, has been examined at 29 sites using a sediment remobilization technique. Measurements encompassed the period February 2003-July 2004. At individual sites in the Frome, average values ranged between 410 and 2630 g m-2, with an overall mean of 918 g m-2. In the Piddle, the average values for individual sites varied between 260 and 4340 g m-2, with an overall mean of 1580 g m-2. Temporal variations in fine bed sediment storage at each site were appreciable, with the coefficients of variation ranging between 43 and 155% in the Frome and between 33 and 160% in the Piddle. Average reach-scale specific bed sediment storage increased markedly downstream along each main stem from 2 to 29 t km-1 (Frome) and from 4 to 19 t km-1 (Piddle). Total fine sediment storage on the channel bed of the Frome varied between 479 t (5 t km-1) and 1694 t (17 1 km-1), with a mean of 795 t (7 t km-1), compared with between 371 t (5 t km-1) and 1238 t (14 t km-1) with a mean of 730 t (9 t km-1) in the Piddle. During the study period, fine bed sediment storage was typically equivalent to 18% (Frome) and 57% (Piddle) of the mean annual suspended sediment flux at the study catchment outlets. Copyright © 2006 John Wiley &amp;amp; Sons, Ltd.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 16&#xD;Export Date: 9 January 2012&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-34248584765&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=3b82ac26918987ca4d8a23c573abc568</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/store/10.1002/hyp.6269/asset/6269_ftp.pdf?v=1&amp;t=h02gvzay&amp;s=1fd975637a6b76472227e17ab0973a61b471d05a</style></url></related-urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Collins-2007-Fine-grained bed sed-1831866881/Collins-2007-Fine-grained bed sed.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl">147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>45</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="2s50ds55250591ewrto5ztd7zwz59v2evpdx">45</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Collins, A. L.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Walling, D. E.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Webb, L.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">King, P.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Environment Group, ADAS, Woodthorne, Wergs Road, Wolverhampton WV6 8TQ, United Kingdom&#xD;School of Geography, Department of Archaeology and Earth Resources, University of Exeter, Rennes Drive, Exeter EX4 4RJ, United Kingdom&#xD;Environment Agency, River House, East Quay, Bridgwater TA6 4YS, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Particulate organic carbon sources and delivery to river channels in the somerset levels ECSFDI priority catchment, southwest UK</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">International Journal of River Basin Management</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">International Journal of River Basin Management</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">277-291</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">7</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">3</style></number><keywords><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Catchment management</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Particulate organic carbon</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Sources</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Uncertainty</style></keyword></keywords><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2009</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Soil erosion and sediment delivery represent an important transport pathway for particulate organic carbon (POC) in fluvial systems. Catchment management strategies designed to protect soil resources therefore require reliable information on the significance of key sediment sources for POC transfers. Within this context, a composite fingerprinting procedure, incorporating uncertainty and prior understanding of catchment processes, was used to investigate the significance of eroding pasture or cultivated topsoils, damaged road verges, channel banks/subsurface sources and point source discharges as POC sources and the associated net delivery to river channels across the Somerset Levels, southwest UK. Overall mean relative contributions of POC from the five individual sediment sources were estimated at 41±2% (pasture topsoils), 18±1% (STWs), 15±2% (cultivated topsoils), 14±1% (damaged road verges) and 12±2% (channel banks/subsurface sources). Respective estimates of net sediment-associated POC delivery to watercourses, provided by integrating sediment source ascription 50th percentiles bounded by 95% confidence limits, organic carbon content, sediment yield ranges and sub-catchment or land use areas, ranged between 2.4-48.5 kg ha-1 yr-1, 0-16.5 kg ha-1 yr-1, 1.7-119.2 kg ha-1 yr-1, 0-13.8 kg ha-1 yr-1 and 0-7.4 kg ha-1 yr-1. © 2009 IAHR, INBO &amp;amp; IAHS.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 5&#xD;Export Date: 23 December 2011&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-70350532617&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=4a1de5c8757deded385ee79f8028b2a9</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.tandfonline.com.ezproxy.liv.ac.uk/doi/pdf/10.1080/15715124.2009.9635389</style></url></related-urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Collins-2009-Particulate organic-2603630081/Collins-2009-Particulate organic.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl">147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>46</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="2s50ds55250591ewrto5ztd7zwz59v2evpdx">46</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Collins, A. L.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Zhang, Y.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Walling, D. E.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Grenfell, S. E.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Smith, P.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Environment Group, ADAS Woodthorne, Wergs Road, Wolverhampton WV6 8TQ, United Kingdom&#xD;School of Geography, University of Exeter, Rennes Drive, Exeter, EX4 4RJ, United Kingdom&#xD;Environment Agency, Lutra House, Dodd Way, Walton Summit, Preston PR5 8BX, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Tracing sediment loss from eroding farm tracks using a geochemical fingerprinting procedure combining local and genetic algorithm optimisation</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Science of the Total Environment</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Science of the Total Environment</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">5461-5471</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">408</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">22</style></number><keywords><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Farm tracks</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Genetic algorithm</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Local optimisation</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Mitigation</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Sediment</style></keyword></keywords><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2010</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Eroding farm tracks represent important spatially distributed features in many agricultural landscapes and there is concern over their role in catchment sediment problems. It is, however, important to place eroding farm tracks in the context of catchment sediment sources more generally, especially since the former afford potential for targeted sediment mitigation. A sediment source tracing procedure was therefore used to assess the importance of eroding farm track surfaces as a contemporary primary suspended sediment source relative to inputs from pasture or cultivated topsoils and channel banks/subsurface sources, in the upper River Piddle catchment (~100km2), in southern England. The study provided a timely opportunity to assess the performance of both local and global (genetic algorithm; GA) optimisation techniques in the sediment geochemistry mass balance modelling used to apportion sources. Over the duration of the study, average median source contributions for individual time-integrated suspended sediment samples collected from three sub-catchments ranged between 1±1 and 19±3% for farm track surfaces, 31±3 and 55±2% for pasture topsoils, 1±1 and 19±1% for cultivated topsoils and 23±2 and 49±1% for channel banks/subsurface sources. Comparison of the local and GA optimisation techniques demonstrated that GA with random initial values improved the minimisation of the objective functions compared to local searching by 0.01-0.04% of 5000 repeat Monte Carlo iterations. GA informed by the outputs of the local optimisation as initial values improved corresponding performance by 0.05-0.20%. These findings increased confidence in the outputs from the local optimisation mass balance modelling, but fingerprint property datasets should be treated on an individual basis. Future sediment source tracing studies should always endeavour to combine local and global search tools to avoid the risk of using localised solutions for source apportionment estimates. © 2010 Elsevier B.V.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Export Date: 9 January 2012&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-77956872173&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=d10441324f7ad39312573af0c196163c</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.sciencedirect.com.ezproxy.liv.ac.uk/science/article/pii/S0048969710008363</style></url></related-urls></urls></record><record><database name="147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl">147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>48</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="2s50ds55250591ewrto5ztd7zwz59v2evpdx">48</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Conway, B. W.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Institute of Geological Sciences, Exhibition Road, London SW7, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">The contribution made to cliff instability by Head deposits in the west Dorset coastal area</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Quarterly Journal of Engineering Geology</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Quarterly Journal of Engineering Geology</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">267-275</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">12</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">4</style></number><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1979</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">In the west Dorset coastal area superficial materials include Head deposits which, by the nature of their origin, are variable in structure and composition. Two broad types are recognized depending on the provenance of the predominant constituent: Cretaceous Head and Lias Head. The Cretaceous Head was probably formed near to or at the end of the Devensian stage of the Late Pleistocene. Where the two types of Head deposit are superimposed, Cretaceous Head always lies above Lias Head. On many slopes Lias Head has topographic expression as lobate sheet forms which are frequently masked by a blanket of Cretaceous Head. The high permeability of Cretaceous Head together with the low strength of Lias Head produce slopes presenting potentially unstable conditions to depths of up to 4 m below ground surface. Three minor types of instability are generated in the Head deposits themselves: shallow translational movements, block slides, and shallow rotational slides. In addition, the high permeability of Cretaceous Head permits water to be introduced to undercliff areas, thus facilitating the development of instabilities in the solid formations below. This results in a mechanism of cliff-top retreat which is quite independent of cliff-toe erosion. The events at sites in Lyme Regis and Charmouth are summarized to illustrate the hazard presented by Head deposits in cliff-top areas. © 1979 The Geological Society, London.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 3&#xD;Export Date: 9 January 2012&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-0008845193&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=b3e101dba5a10ce749b65b60ce18c8a5</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://qjegh.geoscienceworld.org/content/12/4/267.full.pdf</style></url></related-urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Conway-1979-The contribution mad-3593536513/Conway-1979-The contribution mad.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl">147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>50</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="2s50ds55250591ewrto5ztd7zwz59v2evpdx">50</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cooper, N. J.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Environmental Agency, Kingfisher House, Goldhay Way Orton Goldhay, Peterborough PE2 5ZR, United Kingdom&#xD;River Coast. Environments Res. Grp., University of Portsmouth, Buckingham Building, Lion Terrace, Portsmouth, PO1 3HE, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Assessment and prediction of Poole Bay (UK) sand replenishment schemes: Application of data to Fuhrboter and Verhagen models</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Journal of Coastal Research</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Journal of Coastal Research</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">353-359</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">14</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1</style></number><keywords><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Beach replenishment</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Coastal erosion</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Sediment transport</style></keyword></keywords><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1998</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">The performance of two major sand replenishment schemes in Poole Bay has been assessed based upon a long-term beach monitoring record. Analyses of post-replenishment volumetric decay trends have enabled a prediction of when a future replenishment scheme will be needed in Poole Bay. The ability to undertake such a prediction has altered the management philosophy in Poole Bay from a reactive to a pro-active one, and the benefits of such a change are discussed. The Poole Bay data are also applied to mathematical models that have been derived by Fuhrboter (1991) and Verhagen (1996). These models express the volumetric decay of a replenished beach with respect to time. The site-specific modelling parameters derived from the first Poole Bay scheme have been compared with those used to calibrate the Verhagen model, and significant differences are observed. Despite this, both models provide a good fit to the measured field data. Consequently, both models have been used to extrapolate the current post-replenishment volumetric decay, to allow additional dates for a future Poole Bay replenishment scheme to be predicted with confidence, and compared with the previously predicted data.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 7&#xD;Export Date: 9 January 2012&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-0031888160&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=744964c859cad06eedc12dee3903448a</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.jstor.org.ezproxy.liv.ac.uk/stable/pdfplus/4298784.pdf</style></url></related-urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Cooper-1998-Assessment and predi-2553317889/Cooper-1998-Assessment and predi.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl">147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>53</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="2s50ds55250591ewrto5ztd7zwz59v2evpdx">53</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cotton, J. A.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Wharton, G.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Bass, J. A. B.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Heppell, C. M.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Wotton, R. S.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">UK Department of Geography, Queen Mary, University of London, United Kingdom&#xD;Centre for Ecology and Hydrology, Dorset, United Kingdom&#xD;Department of Biology, University College London, London, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">The effects of seasonal changes to in-stream vegetation cover on patterns of flow and accumulation of sediment</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Geomorphology</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Geomorphology</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">320-334</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">77</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">3-4</style></number><keywords><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Chalk streams</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Ranunculus</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">River flows</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Sediment</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Submerged macrophytes</style></keyword></keywords><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2006</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">In-stream macrophytes are typically abundant in nutrient-rich chalk streams during the spring and summer months and modify the in-stream environment by altering river flows and trapping sediments. We present results from an inter-disciplinary study of two river reaches in the River Frome catchment, Dorset (UK). The investigation focused on how Ranunculus (water crowfoot), the dominant submerged macrophyte in the study reaches, modified patterns of flow and sediment deposition. Measurements were taken on a monthly basis throughout 2003 to determine seasonal patterns in macrophyte cover, associated changes in the distributions of flow velocities and the character and amount of accumulated fine sediment within stands of Ranunculus. Maximum in-stream cover of macrophytes exceeded 70% at both sites. Flow velocities were less than 0.1 m s- 1 within the stands of Ranunculus and accelerated to 0.8 m s- 1 outside the stands. During the early stages of the growth of Ranunculus, fine sediment mostly accumulated within the upstream section of the plant but the area of fine sediment accumulation extended into the downstream trailing section of the plant later in the growing season. The fine sediment accumulations were dominated by sand (63-1000 μm) with silts and clays (0.37-63 μm) comprising &amp;lt; 10% by volume. The content of organic matter in the accumulated sediments varied within stands, between reaches and through the growing season with values ranging between 9 and 105 mg g- 1 dry weight. At the reach scale the two sites exhibited different growth forms of Ranunculus which created distinctive patterns of flow and fine sediment deposition. © 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 48&#xD;Export Date: 9 January 2012&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-33745193511&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=ee2f36911d0ff24342b1333882a9add4</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.sciencedirect.com.ezproxy.liv.ac.uk/science/article/pii/S0169555X06000201</style></url></related-urls></urls></record><record><database name="147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl">147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>55</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="2s50ds55250591ewrto5ztd7zwz59v2evpdx">55</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cundy, A. B.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Croudace, I. W.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Department of Geology, University of Southampton, Southampton SO17 1BJ, United Kingdom&#xD;Neotectonics Research Unit, Division of Geography and Geology, Brunel University College, Borough Road, London TW7 5DU, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Physical and chemical associations of radionuclides and trace metals in estuarine sediments: An example from Poole Harbour, southern England</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Journal of Environmental Radioactivity</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Journal of Environmental Radioactivity</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">191-211</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">29</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">3</style></number><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1995</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">The physical (grain size) and chemical (mineral, oxyhydroxide coatings and organic matter) associations of 60Co, 137Cs, 210Pb(xs), Pb, Zn and Cu have been examined in two intertidal sediments (from low and medium energy environments). 60Co, 210Pb(xs), Pb, Zn and Cu show a distribution with particle size controlled by Fe- and Mn-oxyhydroxides and total organic carbon. Activity/concentration maxima for these isotopes and elements occur in the 2-8 μm size fraction. A proportion of the 60Co present appears to have been diagenetically mobilised. In contrast 137Cs is strongly sorbed by clay particles and is virtually non-exchangeable.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 27&#xD;Export Date: 9 January 2012&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-0028970676&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=70ad9a9ff65033f957dabb5b8be2f948</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.sciencedirect.com.ezproxy.liv.ac.uk/science/article/pii/0265931X95000315</style></url></related-urls></urls></record><record><database name="147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl">147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>63</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="2s50ds55250591ewrto5ztd7zwz59v2evpdx">63</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Denness, B.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Conway, B. W.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">McCann, D. M.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Grainger, P.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Engineering Geology Unit, Continental Shelf and Geophysical Division, Institute of Geological Sciences, Exhibition Road, London SW7, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Investigation of a coastal landslip at Charmouth, Dorset</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Quarterly Journal of Engineering Geology</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Quarterly Journal of Engineering Geology</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">119-140</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">8</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2</style></number><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1975</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">The Dorset coast is an area with a long history of landslide activity and coastal erosion. Geologically the area is composed of the clays, mudstones and limestones of several divisions of the Lower Jurassic (Lower Lias) which are overlain unconformably by Cretaceous clays and sands (Gault and Upper Greensand.) Areas of serious instability appear to occur in close association with naturally occurring reservoirs of ground water, of which Black Ven at Char-mouth is a good example. Problems connected with a small coastal landslip near a private housing estate at Char-mouth were studied and shown to be related to a Pleistocene mudflow. The main purpose of the investigation was to suggest remedial works but the subsidiary aim, forming the theme of this paper, was to assess the usefulness of shallow depth geophysical and geotechnical methods not normally used in instability studies. © 1975 The Geological Society, London.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 16&#xD;Export Date: 9 January 2012&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-0008854827&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=e175e24c6b0d6057b1424fe9f8d356f9</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://qjegh.geoscienceworld.org/content/8/2/119.full.pdf</style></url></related-urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Denness-1975-Investigation of a c-2402403841/Denness-1975-Investigation of a c.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl">147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>64</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="2s50ds55250591ewrto5ztd7zwz59v2evpdx">64</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Dobinson, A.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">McCann, D. M.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Marine Operations Programme, British Geological Survey, Edinburgh EH9 3LA, United Kingdom&#xD;Regional Geophysics Research Group, British Geological Survey, Keyworth, Nottingham NG12 5GG, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Application of marine seismic surveying methods to engineering geological studies in the near-shore environment</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Quarterly Journal of Engineering Geology</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Quarterly Journal of Engineering Geology</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">109-123</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">23</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2</style></number><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1990</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">This paper discusses the application of various marine geophysical techniques to engineering studies in coastal and estuarine environments. Sea bed morphology can be examined using echo sounding and sidescan sonar whilst geological structure is investigated using continuous seismic profiling surveys based on sparker and boomer sources. In both cases samples of sea floor sediments and rocks are collected and boreholes drilled to calibrate the seismostratigraphy in terms of geological structure. Current geophysical equipment and methods are reviewed and are illustrated by three case histories. The first describes a geophysical survey undertaken in the Wash to provide information on sediment movement as part of a feasibility study for bunded reservoir construction. The second discusses an appraisal of the engineering characteristics of the near-shore environment carried out in connection with coastal engineering studies in Lyme Bay, Dorset. Finally, a description is given of a survey which formed part of a study to investigate the distribution of sand and gravel aggregate resources off the East Anglian coast.Whilst there have been continuous improvements in seismic profiling equipment and survey techniques, most of the underlying principles and interpretation techniques have remained the same. By combining the results from marine seismic surveys and geological sampling programmes it is possible to achieve an accurate assessment of the sub-bottom geology in the near-shore environment. © 1990 The Geological Society, London.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 5&#xD;Export Date: 9 January 2012&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-0004445111&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=9dbbedc5600147655b87256adc962946</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://qjegh.geoscienceworld.org/content/23/2/109.full.pdf</style></url></related-urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Dobinson-1990-Application of marin-0959546113/Dobinson-1990-Application of marin.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl">147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>74</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="2s50ds55250591ewrto5ztd7zwz59v2evpdx">74</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">French, C.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Lewis, H.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Scaife, R.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Allen, M.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Department of Archaeology, University of Cambridge, Downing Street, Cambridge CB2 3DZ, United Kingdom&#xD;Department of Continuing Education, University of Oxford, 1 Wellington Square, Oxford OX1 2JA, United Kingdom&#xD;Department of Geography, University of Southampton, Highfield, Southampton SO17 1BJ, United Kingdom&#xD;Wessen Archaeology, Salisbury, Wiltshire SP4 6EB, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">New perspectives on Holocene landscape development in the southern English chalklands: The upper Allen valley, Cranborne Chase, Dorset</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Geoarchaeology</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Geoarchaeology</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">109-134</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">20</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2</style></number><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2005</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">A combination of on- and off-site paleoenvironmental and archaeological investigations of the upper Allen valley of Dorset, conducted from 1998-2002, has begun to indicate a different model of prehistoric landscape development to those previously put forward for this part of the southern English chalk downlands. Woodland growth in the earlier Holocene appears to have been slower and patchier than the presumed model of full climax deciduous woodland rapidly attained in a warming environment. With open areas still strongly present in the Mesolithic, the area witnessed its first exploitation, thus slowing and altering soil development. Consequently, many areas perhaps never developed thick, well-structured, brown forest earths, but more probably thin brown earths. By the later Neolithic period, these soils had become thin rendzinas, largely as a consequence of human exploitation and the predominance of pastoral land use. The early presence of thinner and less well-developed soils over large areas of downland removes the necessity for envisaging extensive soil erosion and the accumulation of thick colluvial and alluvial deposits in the dry valleys and valley floor as often postulated. If there were major changes in the vegetation and soil complexes in this area of chalk downland, these had already occurred by the Neolithic rather than the Bronze Age as often suggested, and the area has remained relatively stable ever since. This has major implications for models of prehistoric land use in the southern chalkland region, such as a much greater degree of stability in prehistoric and historic times, variability within sub-regions, and differences between different parts of the chalk downlands than had previously been envisaged. © 2005 Wiley Periodicals, Inc.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 4&#xD;Export Date: 9 January 2012&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-13844289484&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=cf666d3fe0665cfc46bd132fae9fdc62</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/store/10.1002/gea.20039/asset/20039_ftp.pdf?v=1&amp;t=h02gxqq7&amp;s=fd8e17a6ed0c4d8c6c46d06a452a1aa52f51d962</style></url></related-urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://French-2005-New perspectives on-1211194369/French-2005-New perspectives on.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl">147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>87</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="2s50ds55250591ewrto5ztd7zwz59v2evpdx">87</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Gurnell, A.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Goodson, J.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Thompson, K.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Clifford, N.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Armitage, P.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Department of Geography, King&apos;s College London, Strand, London WC2R 2LS, United Kingdom&#xD;Department of Animal and Plant Sciences, University of Sheffield, Sheffield, United Kingdom&#xD;School of Geography, The University of Nottingham, Nottingham, United Kingdom&#xD;CEH Dorset, Winfrith Technology Centre, Dorchester, United Kingdom&#xD;Entec UK Ltd., Gable House, Kenilworth Road, Warwickshire CV32 6JX, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">The river-bed: A dynamic store for plant propagules?</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Earth Surface Processes and Landforms</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Earth Surface Processes and Landforms</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1257-1272</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">32</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">8</style></number><keywords><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Hydrochory</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Plant propagules</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">River-bed</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Sediment store</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Seeds</style></keyword></keywords><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2007</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">This paper investigates temporal variations in the abundance, species composition and richness, and spatial distribution of plant propagules stored on river-beds. Samples of the surface layers of river-bed sediments were obtained from two reaches of the River Frome, Dorset, UK, and one reach of the River Tern, Shropshire, UK. Samples were taken from the same bed locations on four occasions spaced at approximately four monthly intervals. Following greenhouse gemination trials, 11 384 viable propagules of 105 species were identified in 192 channel bed samples. On average, 32% of the species found in the propagule samples were not present in the channel and riparian vegetation. Most of these additional species were wetland and terrestrial rather than aquatic species. The number of species and density of propagules stored on the river-bed varied through time and between reaches. These findings indicate that the channel bed is a dynamic store for viable propagules, including a large proportion of species that are not found locally. These propagules are available for redistribution across river-banks and floodplains during high river flows. Propagules were preferentially stored within particular bed habitats. On the Tern, the most retentive habitats were close to the channel margins and adjacent to riparian vegetation and trees. On the Frome, stands of emergent vegetation along the channel margin were the most retentive habitat, and were also associated with trapping of finer sediment and organic matter. This habitat provides an aggrading environment at the bank toe that could potentially offer gemination sites for the non-aquatic propagules that are stored. Germination and growth of wetland and terrestrial plants during bank profile aggradation and lateral extension would provide root reinforcement and flow resistance across the changing bank profile. The preferential accumulation of sediment and species-rich propagules around stands of marginal emergent vegetation is indicative of a subtle coupling of geomorphological and ecological systems. Copyright © 2007 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 21&#xD;Export Date: 9 January 2012&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-34547198796&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=49ae34c7dda1a883f682b5df1a635726</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/store/10.1002/esp.1554/asset/1554_ftp.pdf?v=1&amp;t=h02gynt4&amp;s=b7cd05bcde9922a514849a219533f2706cd7ed96</style></url></related-urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Gurnell-2007-The river-bed_ A dyn-3509713665/Gurnell-2007-The river-bed_ A dyn.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl">147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>88</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="2s50ds55250591ewrto5ztd7zwz59v2evpdx">88</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Gurnell, A. M.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Van Oosterhout, M. P.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">De Vlieger, B.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Goodson, J. M.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Department of Geography, King&apos;s College London, Strand, London WC2R 2LS, United Kingdom&#xD;Larenstein University of Higher Education, Velp, Netherlands</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Reach-scale interactions between aquatic plants and physical habitat: River Frome, Dorset</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">River Research and Applications</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">River Research and Applications</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">667-680</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">22</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">6</style></number><keywords><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Aquatic macrophytes</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Fine sediment</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Flow hydraulics</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Fluvial mesohabitats</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Manning&apos;s n</style></keyword></keywords><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2006</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Substrate and flow velocity are two key physical factors influencing the distribution of aquatic plants. These two controls are closely related and reflect interactions between flow regime, quantity and calibre of sediment supplied to and bounding river channels, and channel dimensions. Seasonal growth of aquatic plants has important impacts upon flow resistance, flow velocities and sediment dynamics. This paper focuses upon the reach scale and the aggregate impact of the seasonal growth of aquatic plants on the meso-habitat characteristics of chalk rivers. It provides a contribution to the broader literature by illustrating how submerged and emergent macrophytes interact with one another at the reach scale to control flow patterns and the retention of fine sediment. The research was conducted within the River Frome, Dorset, UK. Four sets of observations from 2004 of the seasonal growth of aquatic plants, flow velocity behaviour and the storage of fine sediment are presented. Aggregate velocity behaviour over the four observation periods is classified using agglomerative, hierarchical cluster analysis. The spatial arrangement of patches exhibiting different aggregate velocity behaviour are explored and the degree to which velocity behaviour can be attributed to physical characteristics of patches and the growth of aquatic plants is discussed. Conclusions include: (i) patterns of aggregate velocity behaviour within reaches are strongly influenced by macrophyte growth; (ii) average fine sediment deposition is higher around emergents such as Sparganium erectum than submerged plants such as Ranunculus penicillatus subsp. pseudofluitans; (iii) complementary flow patterns evolve across the river channel as aquatic macrophytes grow and it appears that this allows marginal emergents to scavenge fine sediment from faster flow velocity threads that become diverted towards the channel edges. (iv) These processes are important for mesohabitat evolution and maintenance, and they also contribute to patterns of bank erosion and aggradation. Copyright © 2006 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 29&#xD;Export Date: 9 January 2012&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-33746471786&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=b59153560e042806417cf63d5769e436</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/store/10.1002/rra.929/asset/929_ftp.pdf?v=1&amp;t=h02gyvi2&amp;s=c615259c48683cde70723d19c564646969103dc3</style></url></related-urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Gurnell-2006-Reach-scale interact-3862046209/Gurnell-2006-Reach-scale interact.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl">147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>95</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="2s50ds55250591ewrto5ztd7zwz59v2evpdx">95</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Haslett, S. K.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Davies, P.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Curr, R. H. F.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Davies, C. F. C.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Kennington, K.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">King, C. P.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Margetts, A. J.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Quaternary Research Unit, Faculty of Applied Sciences, Bath Spa University College, Newton Park, Newton St Loe, Bath BA2 9BN, United Kingdom&#xD;Port Erin Marine Laboratory, School of Biological Sciences, University of Liverpool, Port Erin, Isle of Man IM9 6JA, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Evaluating late-Holocene relative sea-level change in the Somerset Levels, southwest Britain</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Holocene</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Holocene</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">197-207</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">8</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2</style></number><keywords><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Compaction</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Holocene</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Sea-level change</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Sedimentation</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Somerset Levels</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Tectonics</style></keyword></keywords><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1998</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Holocene relative sea-level (RSL) change is investigated at Nyland Hill (Somerset Levels). The lithostratigraphy comprises turfa peat underlying marine clay, both onlapping a sloping Upper Palaeozoic basement. The altitude of the peat-clay contact ranges from 2.42 to 4.52 m OD, becoming lower down basement slope, yet 14C dates of three samples taken laterally along the contact at different altitudes yield similar ages (3640-3330, 3715-3460, 3725-3465 cal. yrs BP), suggesting either very rapid (&apos;instantaneous&apos;) RSL rise or sediment compaction. Biostratigraphic data indicate a gradual transition to marine conditions across the peat-clay contact. Therefore, the height difference is interpreted as evidence for significant compaction. We consider 4.64 m OD the minimum pre-compaction altitude, indicating maximum observed compaction of 2.22 m. The clay surface, reclaimed during Roman occupation, represents an anthropogenically induced negative tendency and is dated chemostratigraphically to 1776 ± 46, using a datum related to the onset of local Roman lead mining AD 43-49. Sedimentation rates of the marine clay are established: 1.58-1.92 mm yr-1 and 0.8-0.96 mm yr-1 at sites of maximum and less severe compaction respectively. RSL continued to rise throughout the deposition of the clay unit at a rate of 0.41-0.82 mm yr-1, a view that disagrees with previous models that imply stabilised RSL by 3000 BP. These earlier studies underestimate compaction with implications for subsequent studies employing these sea-level data, particularly in crustal studies where the apparent trend of subsidence is overestimated/increased.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 34&#xD;Export Date: 23 December 2011&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-0031922990&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=7f3a0332918b6cf0c86d2197dd4f7599</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://hol.sagepub.com/content/8/2/197.full.pdf</style></url></related-urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Haslett-1998-Evaluating late-Holo-3157441025/Haslett-1998-Evaluating late-Holo.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl">147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>97</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="2s50ds55250591ewrto5ztd7zwz59v2evpdx">97</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Hawkins, A. B.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Kellaway, G. A.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Department of Geology, University of Bristol, Bristol BS8 1TR&#xD;Institute of Geological Sciences, 5 Princes Gate, London SW7 1QN</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">&quot;Burtle Clay&quot; of somerset</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Nature</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Nature</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">216-217</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">243</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">5404</style></number><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1973</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Kidson and Haynes1 following Kidson2,3 claim that marine or estuarine deposits which they call &quot;Burtle Clay&quot; underlie the Burtle Beds of Somerset. The sands and gravels of the Burtle Beds have been described as marine deposits4 but a glacial origin has recently been ascribed to them5,6. It is claimed1 that the Burtle Clay is of considerable stratigraphical significance, that it proves the occurrence of a widespread marine transgression, destroys the case for the glacial origin of the sands and gravels of the Burtle Beds, and throws doubt on the theory of glacial transport of the &quot;bluestone&quot; erratics incorporated in Neolithic and Bronze age monuments on Salisbury Plain. We find nothing to convince us of the marine origin of the Burtle Beds or to change our opinion about the older glaciations. © 1973 Nature Publishing Group.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Export Date: 23 December 2011&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-36949041801&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=bd0193428324c0ce4f09aedff0eb4074</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.nature.com.ezproxy.liv.ac.uk/nature/journal/v243/n5404/pdf/243216a0.pdf</style></url></related-urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Hawkins-1973-_Burtle Clay_ of som-3576826113/Hawkins-1973-_Burtle Clay_ of som.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl">147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>100</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="2s50ds55250591ewrto5ztd7zwz59v2evpdx">100</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Heppell, C. M.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Wharton, G.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cotton, J. A. C.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Bass, J. A. B.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Roberts, S. E.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Centre for Aquatic and Terrestrial Environment, Department of Geography, Queen Mary University of London, Mile End Road, London E1 4NS, United Kingdom&#xD;Centre for Ecology and Hydrology, Dorset, United Kingdom&#xD;Environment Agency, Rivers House, 21 Park Square South, Leeds LS1 2QG, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Sediment storage in the shallow hyporheic of lowland vegetated river reaches</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Hydrological Processes</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Hydrological Processes</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2239-2251</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">23</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">15</style></number><keywords><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Aquatic vegetation</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Hyporheic</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Permeable river</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Reach</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Sediment storage</style></keyword></keywords><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2009</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Excessive fine sediment deposition on the river channel bed together with colmation of finer sediments within the hyporheic are now linked to the degradation of the aquatic habitats of gravel bed rivers in permeable catchments. Previous studies of chalk rivers (associated with outcrops of calcareous rock) have demonstrated the important role of aquatic vegetation in trapping fine sediment on the river channel bed. This research investigated the spatio-temporal patterns and composition of fine sediment stored in two vegetated river reaches, in the Frome and Piddle catchments, Dorset (UK), with contrasting hydrological regimes, in order to establish the importance of aquatic vegetation in controlling the magnitude and timing of sediment storage in chalk rivers. Monthly mapping of macrophyte and sediment cover at the two sites (Maiden Newton and Snatford Bridge, 2003-2004) revealed a cyclical pattern of sediment storage related to the growth and die-back of aquatic vegetation peaking at 66.8 kg m-2 in July 2003 at Maiden Newton, and 23.5 kg m-2 in October 2003 at Snatford Bridge. Sediment was stored within gravels and beneath vegetation in the margins and mid-channel locations at both sites. Significantly more sediment was stored beneath vegetation than within gravels. The spatio-temporal pattern of sediment storage at the reach scale and the composition of the stored sediments reflected the growth patterns and functional form (flexibility) of the dominant macrophytes Ranunculus penicillatus subsp. pseudofluitans (water crowfoot) and Rorippa nasturtium aquaticum (watercress). Finally, the paper discusses the implications of reach-scale patterns in sediment storage for contaminant storage. Copyright © 2009 John Wiley &amp;amp; Sons, Ltd.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 6&#xD;Export Date: 9 January 2012&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-67650324081&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=f2d4de4bf723ceb0e27c66dc5686f462</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/store/10.1002/hyp.7283/asset/7283_ftp.pdf?v=1&amp;t=h02gz80z&amp;s=4e1907e453280ab6ce66b839c65226f609d6fe78</style></url></related-urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Heppell-2009-Sediment storage in-3811729665/Heppell-2009-Sediment storage in.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl">147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>106</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="2s50ds55250591ewrto5ztd7zwz59v2evpdx">106</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Hill, T. C. B.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Woodland, W. A.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Spencer, C. D.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Marriott, S. B.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Case, D. J.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Catt, J. A.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Birmingham Archaeo-Environmental, Institute of Archaeology and Antiquity, University of Birmingham, Edgbaston, Birmingham B15 2TT, United Kingdom&#xD;School of Geography and Environmental Management, University of the West of England, Bristol BS16 1QY, United Kingdom&#xD;Department of Geography, University College London, London WC1E 6BT, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Devensian Late-glacial environmental change in the Gordano Valley, North Somerset, England: A rare archive for southwest Britain</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Journal of Paleolimnology</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Journal of Paleolimnology</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">431-444</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">40</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1</style></number><keywords><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Dimlington Stadial</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Loch Lomond Stadial</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Loess</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Severn Estuary</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Windermere Interstadial</style></keyword></keywords><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2008</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">The Late-glacial and Holocene environmental history of the Gordano Valley, North Somerset, UK has been reconstructed using pollen, sediment particle size and mineralogical analyses and radiocarbon dating. A Devensian sediment ridge across the valley confined the waters of a small lake, within which the initial sedimentation was minerogenic. Radiocarbon dating of overlying organic-rich deposits suggests that this began late in the Dimlington Stadial c. 18,000-15,000 Cal. BP. Petrographic analyses indicate the minerogenic sediments were partly wind-blown in origin. Climatic amelioration during the Windermere Interstadial c. 15,000 Cal. BP encouraged a shift from minerogenic to biogenic sedimentation. A brief return to minerogenic sedimentation between c. 10,400 and c. 9,520 Cal. BP was followed by uninterrupted fen peat accumulation throughout the Holocene. The later minerogenic horizon appears to represent the Loch Lomond Stadial. Few stratigraphic sequences preserving the complete Devensian Late-glacial-Holocene transition exist in southwest Britain, making the sedimentary archive of the Gordano Valley valuable regionally for reconstructing Late-glacial climate change. © 2007 Springer Science+Business Media B.V.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Export Date: 23 December 2011&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-46249098913&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=0ed6818c31530b7b1f06e922ff9decc7</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.springerlink.com.ezproxy.liv.ac.uk/content/b510xh34604l6772/fulltext.pdf</style></url></related-urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Hill-2008-Devensian Late-glaci-0103994369/Hill-2008-Devensian Late-glaci.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl">147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>108</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="2s50ds55250591ewrto5ztd7zwz59v2evpdx">108</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Horrillo-Caraballo, J. M.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Reeve, D. E.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Centre for Research in Coastal and Ocean Science and Engineering, School of Marine Science and Engineering, University of Plymouth, Reynolds Building, Drake Circus, Plymouth, PL4 8AA, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">An investigation of the performance of a data-driven model on sand and shingle beaches</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Marine Geology</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Marine Geology</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">120-134</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">274</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1-4</style></number><keywords><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Beach profile</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Canonical Correlation Analysis</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Empirical Orthogonal Functions</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Forecast</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Statistical models</style></keyword></keywords><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2010</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">In this paper Canonical Correlation Analysis (CCA) is used as the basis for predicting beach profile changes over a timescale of years. In particular, datasets of wave measurements and beach profiles at two locations with different sediment types and wave exposure are used. The study sites are located in Christchurch Bay (South Coast of England) in which the beaches are classified as mixed shingle and sand beaches and in North Carolina (East Coast of the USA) which has sandy beaches. The datasets comprise detailed bathymetric surveys of beach profiles covering a period of more than 15. years for the New Forest dataset and over 27. years for the Duck dataset. The structure of the datasets and the data handling methods are described. The application of the CCA method is discussed as well as the ability of the CCA to provide useful forecasts of the beach profile at each site. Some results and interpretation of the analysis are presented. Predicted beach profiles elevations agreed well with the measured for up to eight years of forecast at both of the sites. This implies that there is no clear degradation in prediction accuracy over the forecast period. Furthermore the level of error obtained using this approach is commensurate with that found with dynamical modelling. This kind of prediction could be of practical use for engineers and planners. © 2010 Elsevier B.V.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 1&#xD;Export Date: 9 January 2012&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-77955701332&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=7d171e04e5a6219ca9a5c84e33d39e42</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.sciencedirect.com.ezproxy.liv.ac.uk/science/article/pii/S0025322710001349</style></url></related-urls></urls></record><record><database name="147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl">147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>109</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="2s50ds55250591ewrto5ztd7zwz59v2evpdx">109</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">House, W. A.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Denison, F. H.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Armitage, P. D.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Institute of Freshwater Ecology, River Laboratory, East Stoke, Wareham, Dorset BH20 6BB, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Comparison of the uptake of inorganic phosphorus to a suspended and stream bed-sediment</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Water Research</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Water Research</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">767-779</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">29</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">3</style></number><keywords><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Adsorption</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Eutrophication</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Nutrients</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Phosphate</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Phosphorus</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Rivers</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Sediments</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Suspended sediments</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Water quality</style></keyword></keywords><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1995</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Results are presented describing the influx of soluble reactive phosphorus (SRP) to a stream sediment in an outdoor experimental channel, a laboratory channel and in well-mixed suspensions. The kinetics of phosphorus uptake are modelled using several kinetic equations including the Elovich, Bangham, diffusion and first-order equation. The Elovich equation is found to describe best the SRP influx to both bed and suspended sediments. The relative contribution of abiotic and biotic processes in the outdoor experimental channel are considered together with estimates of the flux to the bed-sediment predicted from the results describing the kinetics in the laboratory channel. The sediment is characterized by mineralogy, size fractionation and wet-chemical analyses including total phosphorus, iron and calcium determinations as well as biologically available phosphorus (BAP) by the iron-oxide stripping method and the equilibrium phosphate concentration, EPC0, calculated from sorption measurements. The kinetic results from this sediment illustrate the importance of suspended sediment in the fast uptake of SRP. This contrasts with the control of the influx of SRP to the bed-sediment in channels with low concentrations of suspended solids, caused by the rate-limiting diffusional transfer across the sediment-water interface.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 98&#xD;Export Date: 9 January 2012&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-0028976793&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=bfeeff95704b48cf840d9353dfd6ee55</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.sciencedirect.com.ezproxy.liv.ac.uk/science/article/pii/0043135494002372</style></url></related-urls></urls></record><record><database name="147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl">147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>110</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="2s50ds55250591ewrto5ztd7zwz59v2evpdx">110</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">House, W. A.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Leach, D. V.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Armitage, P. D.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Institute of Freshwater Ecology, River Lab., E. Stoke, Wareham, B., Dorset, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Study of dissolved silicon, and nitrate dynamics in a fresh water stream</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Water Research</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Water Research</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2749-2757</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">35</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">11</style></number><keywords><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Chemical dynamics</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Nitrate</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Nutrients</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Phosphorous</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Silicon and chemical fluxes</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Streams</style></keyword></keywords><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2001</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Dissolved reactive silicon and nitrate were measured at weekly intervals over a 3 year period (1991-94) on a 1.2km reach of a gauged Dorset Mill Stream. In addition, dissolved nitrite was measured over a 8 month period from the spring to late autumn in 1992. Two intensive studies with sampling at 2h intervals were also completed in low and high riverflow conditions. The results were analysed using a mass-balance approach with the loss and gains in nutrients dissolved in the water expressed in terms of areal rates. Losses of both nutrients occurred during periods of low streamflow in spring and summer. Losses of silicon are attributed to growth of epilithic diatoms whereas nitrate losses are consistent with a number of processes including the growth of aquatic plants, the development of epilithic biofilms and nitrogen transformations, such as denitrification, in bed-sediments. Stream water gained dissolved nitrite during its passage through the section. Silicon losses from the stream amounted to between 52 and 63mmolm-2d-1 (expressed per area of bed-sediment) for the spring periods in 1992-94. Nitrate losses were more variable with overall rates between 24 and 89mmolm-2d-1 for the summer periods in 1991-93. Copyright © 2001 Elsevier Science Ltd.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 23&#xD;Export Date: 9 January 2012&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-0034999331&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=86938e42a4404167321b1b46776bb7e2</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.sciencedirect.com.ezproxy.liv.ac.uk/science/article/pii/S0043135400005480</style></url></related-urls></urls></record><record><database name="147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl">147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>111</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="2s50ds55250591ewrto5ztd7zwz59v2evpdx">111</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Howden, N. J. K.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Burt, T. P.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Mathias, S. A.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Worrall, F.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Whelan, M. J.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Department of Civil Engineering, University of Bristol, University Walk, Bristol, BS8 1TR, United Kingdom&#xD;Department of Geography, Durham University, Science Laboratories, South Road, Durham, DH1 3LU, United Kingdom&#xD;Department of Earth Sciences, Durham University, Science Laboratories, South Road, Durham, DH1 3LU, United Kingdom&#xD;Natural Resources Department, School of Applied Sciences, Cranfield University, Bedfordshire, MK43 0AL, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Modelling long-term diffuse nitrate pollution at the catchment-scale: Data, parameter and epistemic uncertainty</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Journal of Hydrology</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Journal of Hydrology</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">337-351</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">403</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">3-4</style></number><keywords><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Catchment</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Groundwater</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Land use</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Long-term</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Model</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Nitrate</style></keyword></keywords><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2011</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">A model of catchment-scale nitrate transport is presented for a small, rural headwater basin (Alton Pancras: &amp;lt;10km2) in Dorset, UK, for the period 1930-2007. Estimates of annual nitrogen (N) loading were based on parish land-use data, held in the UK&apos;s National Archives, and previously reported figures of typical UK N loadings from livestock, fertiliser, ploughing of permanent pasture, atmospheric deposition, biological fixation and crop uptake. Loading calculations were performed within an uncertainty framework to allow for the reliance on literature data sources. Loading calculations show that all significant sources must be included not just fertiliser application which, at most, contributes 50% of N input in any given year. A simple algorithm was used to transform estimated catchment N loading (1930-2007) into a river nitrate response (observed data: 1980-2004). This assumed N-loads were delayed by some catchment mean travel time (MTT), ta, attenuated according to a Peclet number, Pe, converted into solute concentrations by a factor, α, to increase some initial baseline river concentration, Cb. Simple graphical translation of estimated catchment N loading to the river concentration data suggested a MTT of around 37years. As Pe→∞, the transport model simplified to a linear relationship between catchment N load and river nitrate concentration response lagged by the MTT. Hence, the model results suggest that, in this catchment, advection is the dominant mechanism for transport of diffuse pollution from land to river: there is little or no dispersion present. The MTT (ta) was then reconsidered using an estimated distribution of unsaturated zone depths in the Alton Pancras catchment. Conclusions suggest that, in modelling of long-term nutrient transport, a detailed source term is of much greater importance than a complex hydrogeological model. Implications of epistemic uncertainty, long-term prediction and management of diffuse agricultural pollution are discussed. © 2011 Elsevier B.V.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 3&#xD;Export Date: 9 January 2012&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-79952522202&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=b1b090ab47b27acde8edac54f6557a2b</style></url></related-urls></urls></record><record><database name="147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl">147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>117</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="2s50ds55250591ewrto5ztd7zwz59v2evpdx">117</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Jacobi, R. M.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Higham, T. F. G.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Department of Prehistory and Europe, Franks House, The British Museum, London, N1 5QJ, United Kingdom&#xD;Department of Palaeontology, Natural History Museum, London, SW7 5BD, United Kingdom&#xD;Oxford Radiocarbon Accelerator Unit, RLAHA, University of Oxford, Dyson Perrins Building, Oxford OX1 3QY, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">The early Lateglacial re-colonization of Britain: new radiocarbon evidence from Gough&apos;s Cave, southwest England</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Quaternary Science Reviews</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Quaternary Science Reviews</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1895-1913</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">28</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">19-20</style></number><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2009</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Gough&apos;s Cave is still Britain&apos;s most significant Later Upper Palaeolithic site. New ultrafiltered radiocarbon determinations on bone change our understanding of its occupation, by demonstrating that this lasted for only a very short span of time, at the beginning of the Lateglacial Interstadial (Greenland Interstadial 1 (GI-1: Bølling and Allerød)). The application of Bayesian modelling to the radiocarbon dates from this, and other sites from the period in southwest England, suggests that re-colonization after the Last Glacial Maximum took place only after 14,700 cal BP, and is, therefore, more recent than that of the Paris Basin and the Belgian Ardennes. On their own, the radiocarbon determinations cannot tell us whether re-colonization was synchronous with, just prior to, or after, Lateglacial warming. Isotopic studies of humanly-modified mammalian tooth enamel may be one way forward. © 2009 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 17&#xD;Export Date: 23 December 2011&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-68549132388&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=c37896e34fac0ba0ff99a5911090586c</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.sciencedirect.com.ezproxy.liv.ac.uk/science/article/pii/S0277379109001127</style></url></related-urls></urls></record><record><database name="147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl">147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>122</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="2s50ds55250591ewrto5ztd7zwz59v2evpdx">122</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Karunarathna, H.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Horrillo-Caraballo, J. M.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Spivack, M.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Reeve, D. E.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Department of Civil Engineering, Rankin Building, University of Glasgow, Glasgow G12 8LT, United Kingdom&#xD;Centre for Coastal and Ocean Science and Engineering, School of Marine Science and Engineering, Reynolds Building, University of Plymouth, Plymouth PL4 8AA, United Kingdom&#xD;Department of Applied Mathematics and Theoretical Physics, University of Cambridge, Wilberforce Road, Cambridge CB3 0WA, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Analysis of key parameters in a diffusion type beach profile evolution model</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Continental Shelf Research</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Continental Shelf Research</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">98-107</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">31</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2</style></number><keywords><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Beach profile evolution</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Behaviour-oriented model</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Canonical correlation analysis</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Christchurch Bay</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Coastal morphology</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Diffusion equation</style></keyword></keywords><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2011</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Diffusion type formulations are commonly used in beach profile evolution models. The practical idea behind that is to map the behaviour of the beach profile onto a simple mathematical model that exhibits the same behaviour under defined operating conditions. The success of this approach is based on the accurate determination of key parameters in the diffusion model that govern its behaviour, using observed beach behaviour in the field. In order to determine these parameters, i.e. diffusion coefficient and a time and space varying source function, we used observations of historic beach profiles at Milford-on-Sea beach in Christchurch Bay, Dorset, United Kingdom. The relationship between the diffusion coefficient and Dean&apos;s equilibrium profile was investigated, leading to a new interpretation of the diffusion coefficient in terms of the sediment characteristics. The analysis also shows the significance of the diffusion process in the medium to long term evolution of the beach profile. A canonical correlation analysis (CCA) was undertaken in order to identify patterns of behaviour between wave conditions and source terms, and the possible correlations between them. The analysis provides strong evidence of a useful link between the source term in the simple dynamical equation and the distribution of wave steepness. © 2010 Elsevier Ltd.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Export Date: 9 January 2012&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-78651438297&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=3748bfa911e1295b287ec59d296ecc05</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.sciencedirect.com.ezproxy.liv.ac.uk/science/article/pii/S0278434310003596</style></url></related-urls></urls></record><record><database name="147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl">147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>123</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="2s50ds55250591ewrto5ztd7zwz59v2evpdx">123</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Keen, D. H.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Dept Geog, Coventry (Lanchester) Poly, Priory Street, Coventry CV1 5FB, UK.</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Late Pleistocene deposits and Mollusca from Portland, Dorset</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Geological Magazine</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Geological Magazine</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">181-186</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">122</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2</style></number><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1985</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">The stratigraphy and fauna of terrestrial deposits at Portland Bill is described. The fauna is restricted to the head and is indicative of a cool climate rather than the temperate conditions suggested by earlier authors. An age in the Devensian Glacial Stage is tentatively suggested.-Author</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 4&#xD;Export Date: 9 January 2012&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-0022180826&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=e4a6609f36b4f827a4aa05e2ee7666b4</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://journals.cambridge.org/download.php?file=%2FGEO%2FGEO122_02%2FS0016756800031095a.pdf&amp;code=d8f9470be97e7c1e892e95a86818a91c</style></url></related-urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Keen-1985-Late Pleistocene dep-2620596993/Keen-1985-Late Pleistocene dep.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl">147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>125</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="2s50ds55250591ewrto5ztd7zwz59v2evpdx">125</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Kidson, C.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Haynes, J. R.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Department of Geography, University College of Wales</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Glaciation in the somerset levels: The evidence of the burtle beds</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Nature</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Nature</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">390-392</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">239</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">5372</style></number><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1972</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">KELLAWAY has postulated1 an ice stream of Wolstonian (Saale) age moving from the Bristol Channel, across the lowlands of Somerset and into Wiltshire. He suggested that erratic rocks, including the &quot;bluestones&quot; from the Prescelly Hills of Pembrokeshire, subsequently erected in the Stonehenge monument, were carried into the chalk upland by this, or the earlier Anglian, ice sheet. At least one piece of the evidence he cites to support this hypothesis can be subjected immediately to critical examination. Kellaway described the Burtle Beds of Somerset in the following terms: &quot;Other residual masses of glacial sand and gravel (&apos;Burtle Beds&apos;) rise out of the marshes at Catcott Burtle, Weston Zoyland and Othery&quot;. Their marine origin is cursorily dismissed in the phrase &quot;These outwash deposits, previously thought of as marine....&quot;. These deposits have, in fact, recently been the subject of detailed re-investigation2,3. This new work supports the conclusion by Bulleid and Jackson4,5 that the sands and gravels of the Burtle Beds are of marine origin. If that is the case then Kellaway&apos;s &quot;glacial&quot; hypothesis is much weakened. It is, therefore, important to review the grounds for re-asserting the marine character of the Burtle Beds. © 1972 Nature Publishing Group.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Export Date: 23 December 2011&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-0015505063&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=ed553724baa1a7510fda512b8f3154af</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.nature.com.ezproxy.liv.ac.uk/nature/journal/v239/n5372/pdf/239390a0.pdf</style></url></related-urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Kidson-1972-Glaciation in the so-1899181569/Kidson-1972-Glaciation in the so.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl">147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>126</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="2s50ds55250591ewrto5ztd7zwz59v2evpdx">126</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Kidson, C.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Haynes, J. R.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Heyworth, A.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Department of Geography&#xD;Department of Geology&#xD;Department of Geography, University College of Wales, Penglais, Aberystwyth, Cardiganshire, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">The Burtle Beds of somerset-glacial or marine?</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Nature</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Nature</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">211-213</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">251</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">5472</style></number><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1974</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">KELLAWAY1 described the Burtle Beds as &quot;residual masses of glacial sand and gravel (&apos;Burtle Beds&apos;), (which) rise out of the marshes at Catcott Burtle, Weston Zoyland and Othery&quot;. Kidson and Haynes2 supported the earlier view of Bulleid and Jackson3 that the deposits are of marine origin and of interglacial rather than glacial age and provenance. They concluded that &quot;any suggestion that the Burtle Beds are ice transported is quite untenable. A fluvioglacial origin is .....so unlikely as to be unacceptable.... &quot;. © 1974 Nature Publishing Group.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Export Date: 23 December 2011&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-36949041872&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=55da338bde520f0e1338eade42d07cb6</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.nature.com.ezproxy.liv.ac.uk/nature/journal/v251/n5472/pdf/251211a0.pdf</style></url></related-urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Kidson-1974-The Burtle Beds of s-3644039681/Kidson-1974-The Burtle Beds of s.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl">147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>136</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="2s50ds55250591ewrto5ztd7zwz59v2evpdx">136</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Long, A. J.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Scaife, R. G.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Edwards, R. J.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Environmental Research Centre, Department of Geography, University of Durham, South Road, Durham DH1 3LE, United Kingdom&#xD;Quaternary Environ. Change Res. Grp., Department of Geography, University of Southampton, Highfield, Southampton SO17 1BJ, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Pine pollen in intertidal sediments from Poole Harbour, UK; implications for late-Holocene sediment accretion rates and sea-level rise</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Quaternary International</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Quaternary International</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">3-16</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">55</style></volume><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1999</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Marked differences exist between long- and short-term estimates of sea-level rise in sourthern England. Crucial to resolving these differences is the development of dating techniques capable of bridging the gap between the late-Holocene radiocarbon chronology and the more recent 210Pb and observational records of sediment accretion and sea-level change. In this paper we identify an increase in Pinus pollen in a sediment core collected from a saltmarsh in Poole Harbour, Dorset. This has been dated to ca. 1750 AD and reflects the historically documented spread of coniferous plantations across the region. This biostratigraphic age horizon, together with other pollen and radiocarbon data, is used to analyse long- and short-term rates of sediment accretion and sea-level change. A basal radiocarbon date indicates a rise in relative sea-level since 1510-1260 cal. yr BC (3130 ± 60 14C yr BP) of 1.99 m, at a rate of approximately 0.59 mm a-1. Between ca. 1750 AD and ca. 1890 AD sediment accretion rates rose from 0.29 mm a-1 to 1.14 mm a-1, perhaps reflecting an acceleration in relative sea-level rise. These rates increased further to 7.17 mm a-1 after ca. 1890 AD, following the development of a Spartina anglica dominated saltmarsh in Poole Harbour. These data demonstrate that caution should be exercised when using sediment accretion rates from saltmarshes recently colonised by S. anglica as proxy data for sea-level rise.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 20&#xD;Export Date: 9 January 2012&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-0033005941&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=93e84232fbef625767a8c06896bdfc24</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.sciencedirect.com.ezproxy.liv.ac.uk/science/article/pii/S1040618298000172</style></url></related-urls></urls></record><record><database name="147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl">147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>141</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="2s50ds55250591ewrto5ztd7zwz59v2evpdx">141</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Marshall, W. A.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Gehrels, W. R.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Garnett, M. H.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Freeman, S. P. H. T.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Maden, C.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Xu, S.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">School of Geography, University of Plymouth, Drakes Circus, Plymouth, PL4 8AA, United Kingdom&#xD;National Environment Research Council Radiocarbon Laboratory, Scottish Enterprise Technology Park, East Kilbride, G75 0QF, United Kingdom&#xD;Scottish Universities Environmental Research Centre, Scottish Enterprise Technology Park, East Kilbride, G75 0QF, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">The use of &apos;bomb spike&apos; calibration and high-precision AMS 14C analyses to date salt-marsh sediments deposited during the past three centuries</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Quaternary Research</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Quaternary Research</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">325-337</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">68</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">3</style></number><keywords><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">210Pb</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Poole Harbour</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Radiocarbon dating</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">sea-level change</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Spheroidal carbonaceous particles</style></keyword></keywords><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2007</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">A combination of &apos;bomb spike&apos; calibration and conventional calibration of AMS 14C dating has been used to determine a detailed age-depth model for a 1-m sediment section collected from a salt marsh in Poole Harbour, southern England. These data were compared with the chronology obtained from 210Pb analysis and 137Cs age markers. We report post bomb values of over 1.46 F14C (&amp;gt; 146% modern 14C), and both the rising and falling limbs of the atmospheric &apos;bomb spike&apos; are identified. Five pre-bomb samples were analysed using multi-target high-precision 2‰ AMS analysis, and after the replicates were combined the one-sigma uncertainty was as low as ± 9 14C yr on some ages. These data, and an additional three normal-precision pre-bomb 14C samples, were calibrated using CALIB 5.0 and the chronology constrained using the &apos;prior knowledge&apos; of independent age markers obtained from the analysis of pollen and spheroidal carbonaceous particle (SCPs). No agreement was found between the 14C &apos;bomb spike&apos; dates and the CRS 210Pb chronology modelled for this sequence. In addition, poor agreement was found between the signal of the 1960s weapons test fallout indicated by the 14C &apos;bomb spike&apos; dates and the timing suggested by the 137Cs data. This disagreement is attributed to the influence of the local discharge of 137Cs from the former UKAEA site at Winfrith. We use our new chronology to confirm the existence of an acceleration in sedimentation rates in Poole Harbour during the last 100 yr previously reported for this site by Long et al. (Long, A.J., Scaife, R.G., Edwards, R.J. 1999. Pine Pollen in intertidal sediments from Poole Harbour, UK; implications for late-Holocene sediment accretion rates and sea-level rise. Quaternary International, 55, 3-16.), and conclude that &apos;bomb spike&apos; 14C calibration dating may offer a more robust alternative to the use of 210Pb chronologies for dating sediment deposition in salt-marsh environments. In addition, we demonstrate how the use of high-precision AMS analysis has the potential for reducing some of the uncertainties involved in the high-resolution dating of recent salt-marsh sediments. © 2007 University of Washington.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 11&#xD;Export Date: 9 January 2012&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-35348845771&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=eb34cc4573661ea0f18a2ac3514e9a87</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.sciencedirect.com.ezproxy.liv.ac.uk/science/article/pii/S0033589407000890</style></url></related-urls></urls></record><record><database name="147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl">147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>148</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="2s50ds55250591ewrto5ztd7zwz59v2evpdx">148</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Moggridge Helen, L.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Gurnell Angela, M.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Owen, M. J.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Department of Geography, Kings College London, Strand, London WC2R 2LS, United Kingdom&#xD;Centre for Ecology and Hydrology, Maclean Building, Benson Lane, Crowmarsh Gifford, Wallingford, Oxfordshire OX10 8BB</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Propagule input, transport and deposition in riparian environments: The importance of connectivity for diversity</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Journal of Vegetation Science</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Journal of Vegetation Science</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">465-474</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">20</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">3</style></number><keywords><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Dispersal</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Ecohydrology</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Hydrochory</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">River</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Vegetation</style></keyword></keywords><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2009</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Questions: How important is hydrochory for dispersing propagules along riverbanks and to what extent do the quantity and species composition of deposited propagules reflect the riparian vegetation, represent &quot;new&quot; species that are not present in the vegetation, and vary with river flow and season? River Frome, Dorset, UK. Over 13 consecutive 6-week time periods, during which river water levels were continuously monitored, aerial inputs of propagules to riverbanks were sampled using funnels, hydrochorous propagule transport was sampled using drift nets, and deposition across the riverbanks was sampled using astroturf mats. A survey of the riparian vegetation enabled comparison between samples and the standing vegetation, so that &quot;new&quot; species could be identified. Differences in propagule abundance and diversity between sampling methods, time periods and locations were tested using Mann-Whitney [/-tests and Kruskall-Wallis ANOVA. DCA established contrasts in the floristic composition of all deposited propagules and &quot;new&quot; propagules between different sample types, time periods and locations. Aerial seed fall generated few propagules of low species richness. Hydrochory introduced large numbers of propagules and new species, resulting in high propagule deposition on the riverbank. The number and diversity of deposited propagules was governed by seasonal patterns of seed release and the hydrological regime. Propagule deposition was significantly greater on the most frequently inundated parts of the riverbank and autumn floods were particularly important for transporting &quot;new&quot; species to the study site and for remobilizing previously released propagules. The abundance and diversity of propagules deposited along riverbanks is dependent upon high river flows, which facilitates connectivity between the channel and the riparian zone.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 6&#xD;Export Date: 9 January 2012&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-67650069226&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=49a07fbeac1462ac671f0440472bf524</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/store/10.1111/j.1654-1103.2009.05498.x/asset/j.1654-1103.2009.05498.x.pdf?v=1&amp;t=h02h1ctk&amp;s=a9c54162c015badebd82b1636d1e413b7cae44f3</style></url></related-urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Moggridge Helen-2009-Propagule input, tra-1731454721/Moggridge Helen-2009-Propagule input, tra.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl">147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>149</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="2s50ds55250591ewrto5ztd7zwz59v2evpdx">149</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Moggridge, H. L.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Gurnell, A. M.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Department of Geography, King&apos;s College London, Strand, London WC2R 2LS, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Hydrological controls on the transport and deposition of plant propagules within riparian zones</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">River Research and Applications</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">River Research and Applications</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">512-527</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">26</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">4</style></number><keywords><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Anemochory</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Ecohydrology</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Hydrochory</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Propagule</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Riparian</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">River frome</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Vegetation</style></keyword></keywords><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2010</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">The establishment of vegetation in riparian zones is dependent upon the availability of suitable habitat and the presence of viable propagules. Studies have shown that propagules are transported by rivers (hydrochory) and deposited in the riparian zone. However, there has been no detailed integrated study of fluvial propagule transport and deposition in relation to the hydrological regime and relative to other key dispersal mechanisms, such as wind dispersal (anemochory) and direct fall from local riparian vegetation. This paper presents the findings of a 1 year study of the hydrological controls on propagule input, transport and deposition in the riparian zone along two morphologically contrasting reaches of the River Frome (UK) and the potential importance of these processes for the riparian vegetation. Analysis of samples, taken every 6 weeks, shows that aerial seed dispersal delivered relatively few propagules to the riparian zone and was highly spatially and temporally variable. The river transported and deposited large numbers of propagules of high diversity, including many species which were not present in the local vegetation, although this varied with river water levels and with season. Winter high flows were particularly important for depositing diverse propagules into the riparian zone along with local seed production during the summer. Despite contrasts in the planform and cross profile morphology of the two study reaches, they showed great similarity in patterns of propagule deposition, which were largely driven by the inundation regime, the elevation of the sampling site, and the season of sampling. © 2009 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 4&#xD;Export Date: 9 January 2012&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-77951436066&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=be293820580a8b4649818ab198510e6b</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/store/10.1002/rra.1273/asset/1273_ftp.pdf?v=1&amp;t=h02h203t&amp;s=6b30238c7bd36ec3caf8f30997d2c6bf083303a6</style></url></related-urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Moggridge-2010-Hydrological control-1362387457/Moggridge-2010-Hydrological control.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl">147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>151</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="2s50ds55250591ewrto5ztd7zwz59v2evpdx">151</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Neill, S. P.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Scourse, J. D.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">School of Ocean Sciences, Bangor University, Marine Science Laboratories, Menai Bridge, LL59 5AB, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">The formation of headland/island sandbanks</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Continental Shelf Research</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Continental Shelf Research</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2167-2177</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">29</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">18</style></number><keywords><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Bedload transport</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">English Channel</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Headlands</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Holocene</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Portland Bill</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Sandbanks</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Sediment dynamics</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Tidal currents</style></keyword></keywords><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2009</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">There are four extensive sandbanks in the vicinity of the Isle of Portland, a headland in the English Channel. The formation and maintenance of the two most prominent of these sandbanks (one on either side of the headland) can largely be explained by net bedload convergence, driven by instantaneous headland eddies generated by tidal flow past the headland. However, there are also two less prominent sandbanks (again, one on either side of the headland), which are not located in zones of bedload convergence. It is suggested here that these latter two sandbanks were formed when the Isle of Portland was isolated from the mainland by a tidal strait. Relative sea-level data and radiocarbon dates indicate that this would have occurred ca. 9-7 ka BP, prior to the closure of the strait by sedimentation. Tidal flow through this strait generated eddy systems in addition to the headland eddies, leading to the formation of associated headland/island sandbanks. At 7 ka BP, sedimentation resulted in closure of the strait, leading to the present-day headland configuration, and subsequent reworking of these now moribund sandbanks formed by the strait. A series of idealised morphological model experiments, parameterised using bedrock depths and glacial isostatic adjustment model output of relative sea level, are here used to simulate this hypothesised sequence of sandbank evolution over the Holocene. The results of the model experiments are corroborated by in situ observations of bedforms and sediment characteristics, and by acoustic Doppler current profiler (ADCP) data applied to predictions of bedload transport over the sandbanks. In addition to demonstrating the mechanism which leads to the formation of sandbanks by tidal flow through a strait, the model results show that upon subsequent closure of such a strait, these sandbanks will no longer be actively maintained, in contrast to sandbanks which are continuously maintained by headland eddies. © 2009 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 1&#xD;Export Date: 9 January 2012&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-70349863079&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=b51876501d1b9476ad6acf5b68dded03</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.sciencedirect.com.ezproxy.liv.ac.uk/science/article/pii/S0278434309002507</style></url></related-urls></urls></record><record><database name="147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl">147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>154</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="2s50ds55250591ewrto5ztd7zwz59v2evpdx">154</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Nowell, D. A. G.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2 Tudor Road, New Barnet, Herts EN5 5PA, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Structures affecting the coast around Lulworth Cove, Dorset and syn-sedimentary Wealden faulting</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Proceedings of the Geologists&apos; Association</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Proceedings of the Geologists&apos; Association</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">257-268</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">108</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">4</style></number><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1997</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Pre-Albian northwest-southeast faults have been inferred along the coast between Durdle Door and Worbarrow Tout. From the westward increase in the thickness of Wealden units between Mupe Bay and Lulworth Cove followed by dramatic thinning across the cove it is suggested that these faults were synsedimentary growth faults during the early Cretaceous. Also the Wealden is shown to contain two main quartz grit bands, only the lower of which is seen in Lulworth Cove due to increasing westwards Albian erosion which mainly explains the westwards thinning of the Wealden. These faults may have continued to be active throughout the rest of the Cretaceous. During the later Alpine formation of the Purbcck monocline, southward dipping thrusts also developed. Their alignment may have been controlled by the reactivated northwest-southeast faults. To the west of Lulworth Cove much of the succession between the Portland Stone and the Chalk is cut out by these east-west thrusts. © 1997 Geologists&apos; Association.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Export Date: 9 January 2012&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-0031402390&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=467dc00aab31550d29894b6db1362bea</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.sciencedirect.com.ezproxy.liv.ac.uk/science/article/pii/S0016787897800119</style></url></related-urls></urls></record><record><database name="147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl">147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>161</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="2s50ds55250591ewrto5ztd7zwz59v2evpdx">161</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Park, S. J.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Burt, T. P.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Department of Soil Science, Univ. of Wisconsin, 1525 Observ. Dr., Madison, WI 53706, United States&#xD;Department of Geography, Univ. Durham, Sci. Labs., S. Rd., D., Durham, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Identification of throughflow using the distribution of secondary iron oxides in soils</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Geoderma</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Geoderma</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">61-84</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">93</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1-2</style></number><keywords><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Catena</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Fe oxides</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Mn oxides</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Podzols</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Throughflow</style></keyword></keywords><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1999</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">The hypothesis that the spatial distribution of secondary iron (Fe) oxides and hydroxides in soils can be used an indicator for subsurface flow (throughflow) is tested on a podzolised hillslope at Bicknoller Combe, Somerset, UK. Acid ammonium oxalate solution and citrate-bicarbonate-dithionite solution are used to estimate the amount of Fe oxides (Fe(o) and Fe(d) respectively) in the soils collected at five depths from 64 soil profiles across the hillslope. The spatial distribution of Fe oxides matches the pattern of throughflow over the slope which had been previously identified by mapping of soil water potential and soil morphological analysis. The distribution of Fe(d) on the hillslope correlates well with the relative intensity of lateral throughflow in topsoils; the upper convex shoulder slope shows the highest intensity of throughflow, gradually decreasing towards the base of the slope. On convergent slopes, the intensity of throughflow greatly increases along the line of convergence. The spatial distribution of Fe(o) and Fe(o)/Fe(d) reflects a more dynamic aspect of the removal and deposition processes of Fe associated with podzolisation and gleying processes than that of Fe(d) on the study slope. Significant amounts of Fe removed from upslope soils are precipitated in oxidised subsurface soil horizons at lower slope positions. In the comparison with the ratio Mn(d)/Fe(d) which has been previously proposed as an indicator of lateral throughflow in an acid hillslope, the distribution of Fe(d), Fe(o), and Fe(o)/Fe(d) better reflects spatial patterns of throughflow and its relative intensity.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 9&#xD;Export Date: 23 December 2011&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-0032694674&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=055308e02f89ab22b0392b69ffe3ecd1</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.sciencedirect.com.ezproxy.liv.ac.uk/science/article/pii/S0016706199000427</style></url></related-urls></urls></record><record><database name="147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl">147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>163</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="2s50ds55250591ewrto5ztd7zwz59v2evpdx">163</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Park, S. J.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Burt, T. P.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Center for Development Research (ZEF), Univ. of Bonn, Walter-Flex-Str. 3, 53113, Bonn, Germany&#xD;Dep. of Geography, Univ. of Durham, Science Laboratories, South Road, Durham, DH1 3LE, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Identification and characterization of pedogeomorphological processes on a hillslope</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Soil Science Society of America Journal</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Soil Science Society of America Journal</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1897-1910</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">66</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">6</style></number><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2002</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">This study aims to identify process-response relationships between pedogeomorphological processes and the spatial distribution of soil properties on a hillslope. Thirty-two physical and chemical attributes of 502 soil samples collected from 64 soil profiles on a hillslope in Somerset, UK, were analyzed using an ordination technique. Five factors explaining 80% of the total variation were first identified. Each factor was then regressed with terrain attributes to examine the influence of hillslope geomorphometry on soil distributions. Two-way ANOVA was used to separate the total variance of individual soil properties into vertical and lateral components, and the results were compared with the results of the ordination. The five factors were interpreted as demonstrating the effects of podzolization, nutrient dynamics, Mn leaching, erosion weathering, and soil acidification. The ability to predict soil properties over the landscape using terrain information varies widely among soil properties measured. In general, topsoil properties are better correlated with terrain attributes than subsoil properties. Contemporary pedological and geomorphological processes are most active in the surface horizon, which results in clear lateral differentiation of soil properties. For subsurface soils, only those few soil properties that showed a clear spatial pattern could be successfully modeled using terrain attributes. This research demonstrates that clear differences in the spatial distribution of individual soil properties are mainly determined by differential involvement in in situ pedogenesis and lateral slope processes. Future soil-landscape modeling attempts should pay more attention to the selection of soil properties and the interpretation of statistical results in relation to process-response dynamics.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 20&#xD;Export Date: 23 December 2011&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-0036852064&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=529be84b96e7c6da4ac94015e654a532</style></url></related-urls></urls></record><record><database name="147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl">147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>171</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="2s50ds55250591ewrto5ztd7zwz59v2evpdx">171</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Petts, G. E.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Thoms, M. C.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Department of Geography, University of Technology Loughborough, Leicestershire, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Channel aggradation below Chew Valley Lake, Somerset, U.K</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Catena</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Catena</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">305-320</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">13</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">3</style></number><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1986</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Variations of channel substrate composition are described for a regulated river which has experienced channel change since dam completion. Sediment samples were obtained using bulk (grab) sampling and freeze-coring. Data derived from the two methods are shown to differ. Bulk-sample data describe the bed surface layer; its grain-size variations are related to bedform. Freeze-core data describe the sub-surface structure and the fine size-grades. The gravel framework-supported substrate of the control reaches constrasts with the sand-dominated substrate of the aggraded reach, although in both cases the substrate coarsens upwards. In the former this relates to the development of a sand matrix within the gravel-framework substrate, and in the latter, sand-bed channel, to the progressive addition of a gravel component towards the surface which is related to the process of channel change. At the local-scale, bedform is shown to exert an important control on the character of substrate change induced by flow regulation. © 1986.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 7&#xD;Export Date: 23 December 2011&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-0022858978&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=eabeb88d2f6516e41d35ef20dc22c25a</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.sciencedirect.com.ezproxy.liv.ac.uk/science/article/pii/0341816286900056</style></url></related-urls></urls></record><record><database name="147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl">147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>172</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="2s50ds55250591ewrto5ztd7zwz59v2evpdx">172</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Pinn, E. H.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Mitchell, K.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Corkill, J.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">School of Conservation Sciences, Bournemouth University, Fern Barrow, Poole, Dorset B.&#xD;JNCC, Dunnet House, 7 Thistle Pl., Aberdeen AB10 1UZ, U.</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">The assemblages of groynes in relation to substratum age, aspect and microhabitat</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Estuarine, Coastal and Shelf Science</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Estuarine, Coastal and Shelf Science</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">271-282</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">62</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1-2</style></number><keywords><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">artificial habitat</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">assemblages</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">biodiversity</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">coastal structures</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">community composition</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">groynes</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">intertidal</style></keyword></keywords><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2005</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Despite the long history of urbanisation of the coastal environment, there remains very little understanding of the impact of such construction on the ecology of intertidal habitats. Rock rubble groynes are becoming the favoured approach to reduce beach erosion in Dorset, England. This study investigated the assemblages of 10 rock rubble groynes over a 2-year period, taking four factors into account: age of the groyne (&lt;1 year, 2 years, 6 years and 7 years old), tidal height (high shore versus low shore), groyne aspect (east versus west side) and microhabitat (open rock versus rockpool). The age of the groyne, tidal height and microhabitat were significant factors in the composition of the assemblage. The groyne aspect, however, did not significantly influence community composition. These findings are discussed and related to succession and community development theory. © 2004 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 12&#xD;Export Date: 9 January 2012&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-9944254787&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=e3e39fc741924d450a4cb356a56c5112</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.sciencedirect.com.ezproxy.liv.ac.uk/science/article/pii/S0272771404002434</style></url></related-urls></urls></record><record><database name="147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl">147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>181</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="2s50ds55250591ewrto5ztd7zwz59v2evpdx">181</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Prudden, H. C.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2 Yeovil Road, Montacute, Somerset, TA15 6XG, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">The drainage pattern in west Dorset and east Devon and its relationship to the sub-cretaceous</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Geoscience in South-West England</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Geoscience in South-West England</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">59-61</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">11</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1</style></number><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2004</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">There appears to be a correlation between the present-day drainage pattern and the contours representing the unconformity at the base of the Gault/Upper Greensand. The unconformity surface is an elongated dome approximately over what is now Marshwood Vale. Present-day streams radiate from this centre whilst Beaminster Down marks the watershed between the Bristol and English Channels. Arguably, the west Dorset-east Devon hilltops are the remnants of an extensive plateau which was subjected to prolonged sub-tropical weathering with the formation of solution pipes, silcretes and the Clay-with flints i.e. an etchplain of low relief. There are extensive spreads of gravels in the eastern parts. It would appear that this plain was warped, possibly during Tertiary compression, and the present drainage pattern initiated.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Export Date: 9 January 2012&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-77949329814&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=44eb7ca13bdcc9839c5e5045cb4a28fa</style></url></related-urls></urls></record><record><database name="147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl">147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>184</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="2s50ds55250591ewrto5ztd7zwz59v2evpdx">184</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Pye, K.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Mottershead, D. N.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Postgrad Rsch Inst for Sedimentology, Univ of Reading, Whiteknights, Reading, UK</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Honeycomb weathering of Carboniferous sandstone in a sea wall at Weston-super-Mare, UK</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Quarterly Journal of Engineering Geology</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Quarterly Journal of Engineering Geology</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">333-347</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">28</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">4</style></number><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1995</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Blocks of Forest of Dean stone, an arkosic, clay-rich sandstone of Lower Carboniferous age, which were used in the construction of a sea wall at Weston-super-Mare in the 1880s, now display extensive honeycomb weathering features. Spatial variations in the degree of weathering, together with geochemical evidence, suggest that marine salt spray as played a key role in the development of the honeycombs. Petrographic microscope and SEM studies indicate that the principal weathering mechansims involved are granular disintegration and micro de-lamination induced by chemical alteration along inter-grain boundaries and differential swelling and contraction of clays within the rock. -from Authors</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 17&#xD;Export Date: 23 December 2011&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-0029478420&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=25aa7507728907f5304240305ca94c7d</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://qjegh.lyellcollection.org/content/28/4/333.full.pdf</style></url></related-urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Pye-1995-Honeycomb weathering-2419491841/Pye-1995-Honeycomb weathering.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl">147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>188</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="2s50ds55250591ewrto5ztd7zwz59v2evpdx">188</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Rhodes, E. J.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Research Laboratory for Archaeology and History of Art, 6 Keble Road, Oxford, OX1 3QJ, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Methodological considerations in the optical dating of quartz</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Quaternary Science Reviews</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Quaternary Science Reviews</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">395-400</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">7</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">3-4</style></number><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1988</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">The optically-stimulated luminescence from quartz grains extracted from sediments at two archaeological sites has been studied. The sites were the Upper Palaeolithic site at Hengistbury Head, Dorset, U.K. and the Upper Aterian site at Chaperon Rouge, Morocco. Problems associated with the technique of optical dating are discussed, particularly the thermal treatment that is necessary to remove thermally unstable charge following artificial irradiation, and the extrapolation of growth curves to estimate the equivalent dose. The technique used is described and some preliminary dates are presented. © 1988.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 75&#xD;Export Date: 9 January 2012&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-0024257531&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=e2a55bc7a5f91c644acee86a32b8b04c</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.sciencedirect.com.ezproxy.liv.ac.uk/science/article/pii/0277379188900352</style></url></related-urls></urls></record><record><database name="147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl">147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>198</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="2s50ds55250591ewrto5ztd7zwz59v2evpdx">198</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Schürch, M.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Edmunds, W. M.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Buckley, D.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">British Geological Survey, Maclean Building, Crowmarsh Gifford, Wallingford, Oxon OX10 8BB, United Kingdom&#xD;Federal Office for Water and Geology, Swiss Geological Survey, CH-3003 Bern-Ittigen, Switzerland</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Three-dimensional flow and trace metal mobility in shallow Chalk groundwater, Dorset, United Kingdom</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Journal of Hydrology</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Journal of Hydrology</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">229-248</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">292</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1-4</style></number><keywords><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Borehole logging</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Chalk</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Hydrogeochemistry</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Shallow groundwater</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Trace elements</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">United Kingdom</style></keyword></keywords><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2004</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">The three-dimensional groundwater flow and the hydrogeochemical regime have been determined in the Bere Stream valley, North Dorset Downs, southern England. The dual porosity characteristics of the Portsdown Chalk have been established using geophysical and hydrochemical borehole logging. Chemical properties have been established using major and trace element analyses of depth samples and groundwaters. The study site is located at the unconfined-confined boundary of the Chalk aquifer, where it is overflowing in the observation boreholes. The Chalk dips locally at about 5 m/km to the south-east under Palaeogene confining beds and three distinctive flow horizons may be recognised. The Chalk groundwater is of Ca-HCO3 type and three separate geochemical groundwater zones were also determined with depth, having different oxygen levels and trace element characteristics. (1) A shallow O 2-rich zone with around 80% dissolved O2 and low trace element concentrations. (2) A mixing and transition zone with significant concentrations of trace elements and high trace metal concentrations at its base: manganese 29 μg/l, nickel 55 μg/l, cadmium 146 μg/l, and zinc 214 μg/l. (3) A deeper zone with depleted oxygen (5-20% dissolved O2) and with longer water residence times shown by higher Mg/Ca and K/Na ratios as well as higher Sr and F. The groundwater geochemistry in the Chalk aquifer is dominated by incongruent reactions with the fine-grained carbonate sediments, which release trace element impurities to the water. Some of the metals are co-precipitated with Mn- and Fe-oxide phases on fissure surfaces, whilst producing a purer calcite. During subsequent recrystallisation to purer iron- and manganese-oxides on fissure surfaces under specific geochemical and hydrodynamic conditions, trace metals are released into the fissure water. The results demonstrate the need to monitor quality stratification and the changes in the groundwater baseline chemistry in areas close to the redox boundary which, in the dual porosity Chalk is likely to be a diffuse zone with exchange between oxygen poor matrix waters and more oxic water flowing through the fissures. © 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 9&#xD;Export Date: 9 January 2012&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-2342501975&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=570d91cc1932b21e5b034a1b892e4394</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.sciencedirect.com.ezproxy.liv.ac.uk/science/article/pii/S0022169404000149</style></url></related-urls></urls></record><record><database name="147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl">147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>202</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="2s50ds55250591ewrto5ztd7zwz59v2evpdx">202</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Swetnam, R. D.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Mountford, J. O.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Armstrong, A. C.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Gowing, D. J. G.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Brown, N. J.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Manchester, S. J.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Treweek, J. R.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Inst. of Terrestrial Ecology, M., Huntingdon, St. Ives PE17 2LS, United Kingdom&#xD;ADAS, Gleadthorpe Land Res. Centre, M., Mansfield, Nottinghamshire NG20 9PF, United Kingdom&#xD;Silsoe College, Cranfield University, Silsoe, Bedfordshire MK45 4DT, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Spatial relationships between site hydrology and the occurrence of grassland of conservation importance: A risk assessment with GIS</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Journal of Environmental Management</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Journal of Environmental Management</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">189-203</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">54</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">3</style></number><keywords><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cynosurus cristatus-Caltha palustris (MG8)</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Environmentally Sensitive Areas</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Geographic Information Systems</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Hydrological modelling</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">National Vegetation Classification</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Spatial patterns</style></keyword></keywords><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1998</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">The UK&apos;s Environmentally Sensitive Area (ESA) scheme provides financial incentives for farmers to undertake management which is compatible with the conservation of landscapes and wildlife species. Lowland wet grassland is an important component of a number of these ESAs. Management prescriptions relate to farming practices like grazing and weed management. For lowland wet grasslands, they may also include options to raise water levels for the benefit of species, many of which have declined following widespread drainage of agricultural land. This paper focuses on Southlake Moor in Somerset, south-west England, where raised water-level prescriptions have operated since 1992 and where an increased incidence of late spring flooding appears to be threatening important areas of nationally scarce Cynosurus cristatus-Caltha palustris grassland. A methodology is presented which makes use of a GIS to quantify the distribution of the nature conservation resource and link this to a hydrological model and a database of plant water-regime requirements. The model predicts water-tables on a field-by-field basis for each 10 day period throughout the year allowing flood maps to be constructed. The database quantifies the water regime requirements for individual species on Southlake Moor. Using individual fields as the unit of study these two are linked within the GIS to permit the extent of spring flooding to be identified and its potential impact assessed in terms of suitability for key species/communities. The paper describes how this approach could be used to determine whether deliberate management to raise water levels might be placing characteristic and scarce vegetation communities at risk.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 16&#xD;Export Date: 23 December 2011&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-0032213208&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=a7c18688001cadfd8ea6c661d15ff9d0</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.sciencedirect.com.ezproxy.liv.ac.uk/science/article/pii/S0301479798902274</style></url></related-urls></urls></record><record><database name="147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl">147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>209</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="2s50ds55250591ewrto5ztd7zwz59v2evpdx">209</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Viles, H.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Dept of Geography, University College London, 26 Bedford Way, London, WC1H 0AP, UK</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">A quantitative scanning electron microscope study of evidence for lichen weathering of limestone, Mendip Hills, Somerset</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Earth Surface Processes &amp; Landforms</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Earth Surface Processes &amp; Landforms</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">467-473</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">12</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">5</style></number><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1987</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">A simple method of producing quantitative descriptions of lichen material and petrographic evidence of weathering using the SEM has been developed and tested on samples from the Mendip Hills, England. The technique reveals a variable and often sparse distribution of lichen material and associated weathering effects below a thin, clearly defined lichen thallus. -from Author</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 18&#xD;Export Date: 23 December 2011&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-0023470057&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=ac24d30a1a6941a606a0334106fffd05</style></url></related-urls></urls></record><record><database name="147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl">147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>210</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="2s50ds55250591ewrto5ztd7zwz59v2evpdx">210</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Voulgaris, G.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Wilkin, M. P.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Collins, M. B.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Department of Oceanography, The University, Southampton, SO17 1BJ, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">The in situ passive acoustic measurement of shingle movement under waves and currents: instrument (TOSCA) development and preliminary results</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Continental Shelf Research</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Continental Shelf Research</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1195-1211</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">15</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">10</style></number><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1995</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">An instrumented platform (TOSCA) is described for monitoring coarse-grained sediment transport in high (wave and tidal) energy environments. The system consists of a number of sensors which measure: instantaneous current velocities at three levels; sea surface elevation; and self-generated noise (SGN) caused by intercollision of particles in transit. SGN is related to transport rates, on the basis of laboratory calibration; this, in turn, allows a correlation with simultaneous near-bed shear stress to be established. During the field measurements, PC-based real-time data transmission is realised through the use of a (buoyed) radio telemetry system. TOSCA has been deployed in eastern Christchurch Bay, southern England. Burst data were collected every 2 h, over 10 min, with a sampling frequency of 5 Hz. The data sets obtained permit detailed investigations into near-bed flow structure and shingle movement, on time-scales comparable to those of the turbulence. © 1995 Elsevier Science Ltd.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 5&#xD;Export Date: 9 January 2012&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-0028977813&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=76c76a877bef400f05416b90874b3255</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.sciencedirect.com.ezproxy.liv.ac.uk/science/article/pii/027843439400074W</style></url></related-urls></urls></record><record><database name="147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl">147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>214</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="2s50ds55250591ewrto5ztd7zwz59v2evpdx">214</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Walling, D. E.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Amos, C. M.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Department of Geography, University of Exeter, Exeter, Devon, EX4 4RJ, United Kingdom&#xD;Environment Agency, South West Region, Manley House, Kestrel Way, Exeter, Devon, EX2 7LQ, United Kingdom&#xD;Department of Geography, University of Exeter, Amory Building, Rennes Drive, Exeter, Devon, EX4 4RJ</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Source, storage and mobilisation of fine sediment in a chalk stream system</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Hydrological Processes</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Hydrological Processes</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">323-340</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">13</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">3</style></number><keywords><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Chalk stream</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Sediment sources</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Sediment storage</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Sedimentation</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Suspended sediment</style></keyword></keywords><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1999</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Concern for sediment problems in the Upper River Piddle, Dorset, including accumulation of fine sediment on the channel bed and elevated turbidity levels during periods of stable flow, provided the stimulus for a detailed field investigation of the sediment dynamics of this chalk stream system undertaken during the period November 1991 to April 1993. Two monitoring stations were established at South Farm, Piddletrenthide and Lawrence Mede, Piddlehinton and estimates of suspended sediment load were obtained for these two sites. In addition, suspended sediment concentrations and bed sediment loadings were regularly sampled at several other sites, sediment traps were deployed at ten representative sites along the river channel, field observations of sediment sources and pathways were made during storm events and a sediment source fingerprinting study was undertaken. Estimates of annual suspended sediment yield provided values of 9-12 t km-2 year-1, which must be seen as low by UK standards. Elevated suspended sediment concentrations were not restricted to storm events, but occurred throughout the monitoring period in response to remobilisation of sediment stored in the channel. The evidence provided by the sediment loads recorded at the two monitoring stations, by the sediment traps and by the measurements of bed sediment loading, indicated that substantial amounts of sediment accumulated in the channel of the upper and middle reaches of the river during the winter months and that this &apos;slug&apos; of sediment was slowly transmitted downstream during the following summer. Fingerprinting of the transported sediment and of potential sources indicated that the dominant source of suspended sediment was likely to be surface soil from cultivated areas. Field reconnaissance surveys undertaken during storm events indicated that substantial inputs of surface runoff and suspended sediment entered the stream. Much of this sediment is, however, stored within the channel system and slowly transmitted downstream. Copyright ©1999 John Wiley &amp;amp; Sons, Ltd.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 50&#xD;Export Date: 9 January 2012&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-0033077259&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=615d5c0035f10e24a230b16e964ef32c</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/store/10.1002/(SICI)1099-1085(19990228)13:3&lt;323::AID-HYP741&gt;3.0.CO;2-K/asset/741_ftp.pdf?v=1&amp;t=h02h4gja&amp;s=a5234f09b2ad4c6622d49a7975570d8db4ccab17</style></url></related-urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Walling-1999-Source, storage and-0238427137/Walling-1999-Source, storage and.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl">147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>215</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="2s50ds55250591ewrto5ztd7zwz59v2evpdx">215</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Walling, D. E.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">He, Q.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Department of Geography, University of Exeter, Exeter EX4 4RJ, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Use of fallout 137Cs in investigations of overbank sediment deposition on river floodplains</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Catena</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Catena</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">263-282</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">29</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">3-4</style></number><keywords><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Caesium-137</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Floodplain</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Overbank deposition</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Sedimentation rates</style></keyword></keywords><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1997</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">River floodplains have been recognised as important sinks for storing suspended sediment and associated contaminants mobilised from the upstream catchment. However, information on contemporary rates of overbank sedimentation is difficult to obtain using conventional methods. Measurements of the 137Cs content of floodplain sediments provide an alternative approach to obtaining estimates of medium-term rates (ca. 40 years) of overbank sediment deposition. The 137Cs approach requires only a single site visit and minimum sample preparation. Furthermore, it is capable of providing information on spatial patterns of sediment deposition on floodplains, which is needed to improve our understanding of the processes involved in overbank flow and sediment deposition. This paper reviews the basis for using 137Cs measurements in floodplain sedimentation studies and presents improved procedures for interpreting 137Cs profiles in floodplain sediments and for obtaining estimates of sedimentation rates from single measurements of the total 137Cs inventories of bulk sediment cores. The results obtained from a case study undertaken on the floodplain of the River Stour, Dorset, UK, are presented.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 80&#xD;Export Date: 9 January 2012&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-0030794348&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=1c7f39109fa00db3ebff5c7f98912e12</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.sciencedirect.com.ezproxy.liv.ac.uk/science/article/pii/S0341816296000720</style></url></related-urls></urls></record><record><database name="147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl">147_Blackdowns_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>219</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="2s50ds55250591ewrto5ztd7zwz59v2evpdx">219</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Wharton, G.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cotton, J. A.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Wotton, R. S.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Bass, J. A. B.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Heppell, C. M.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Trimmer, M.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Sanders, I. A.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Warren, L. L.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Centre for Aquatic and Terrestrial Environments, Department of Geography, Queen Mary and Westfield College, London, E1 4NS, United Kingdom&#xD;Department of Biology, University College London, United Kingdom&#xD;Centre for Ecology and Hydrology, Dorset, United Kingdom&#xD;Centre for Aquatic and Terrestrial Environments, Biological Sciences, Queen Mary, University of London, London, E1 4NS, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Macrophytes and suspension-feeding invertebrates modify flows and fine sediments in the Frome and Piddle catchments, Dorset (UK)</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Journal of Hydrology</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Journal of Hydrology</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">171-184</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">330</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1-2</style></number><keywords><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Chalk rivers</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Ecosystem engineering</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Fine sediment</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Macrophytes</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">River flows</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Suspension feeders</style></keyword></keywords><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2006</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">This research investigated the ecosystem engineering by in-stream macrophytes, dominated by Ranunculus spp., and associated suspension-feeding blackfly larvae (Diptera: Simuliidae) for five reaches in the Frome and Piddle catchments, Dorset (UK) over one annual growth cycle (2003). This paper focuses on the modification of flow velocities and the trapping of fine sediment (particles &amp;lt;2 mm in diameter) by in-stream macrophytes and the processing of dissolved organic matter (DOM), fine particulate organic matter (FPOM) and fine inorganic particles into faecal pellets by blackfly larvae attached to the leaves of Ranunculus plants. In-stream macrophyte growth was extensive, with maximum percentage cover of 80% recorded in September and October 2003. The macrophyte cover significantly altered flow patterns and flow velocities within and between the macrophyte stands. The reduced flow velocities within the plants promoted sediment trapping, reaching volumes of 0.085 m3 of fine sediment trapped per metre square of vegetation at one site. The effective particle sizes of the sediments trapped within Ranunculus stands were dominated by the 250-500 μm fraction from March to July 2003 whereas a higher proportion of smaller fractions occurred from October to December. Faecal pellets were highly abundant in the sediments trapped within Ranunculus stands (up to 2.2 × 108 faecal pellets per m2) and their dimensions (total size range 25-400 μm) fall within the dominant size fraction of the trapped sediments. Our findings demonstrate the need to consider the biogenic component of the fine sediments in chalk streams in future studies of sediment and nutrient dynamics. © 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 29&#xD;Export Date: 9 January 2012&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-33749511239&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=46e8aa08b6470ad169987c820ffeb569</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.sciencedirect.com.ezproxy.liv.ac.uk/science/article/pii/S0022169406001995</style></url></related-urls></urls></record></records></xml>