<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><xml><records><record><database name="19_South_Cumbria_Low_Fells_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\19_South_Cumbria_Low_Fells_Shortlist.enl">19_South_Cumbria_Low_Fells_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>1</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="dpfap2wee2fep9ezrxjpffeqvdafpe0e0xd5">1</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Bishop, P.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Department of Geology, University College, London, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">The palaeomagnetism of muddy sediment cores from the Inner Sound, Northwest Scotland, and the glacial and post-glacial history of sedimentation in the area</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Earth and Planetary Science Letters</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Earth and Planetary Science Letters</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">51-56</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">27</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1</style></number><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1975</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">The direction of declination of remanent magnetisation of five sediment cores from the Inner Sound, Northwest Scotland has been determined. The data reveal variations in declination with an amplitude of about 30°, which have been tentatively correlated with declination curves from Lake Windermere, England. The thickness of sediment deposited in the last 2575 years is 150 cm in the north of the area, but only between 60 and 80 cm in the south. This indicates that the recent sediment was derived from the north in a way concordant with the water circulation pattern of the Inner Sound. Geophysical evidence reveals earlier, glacial sedimentation to have been at a maximum to the south, hence there was a reversal in the direction of sediment inflow to the Inner Sound at the start of the post-glacial phase. The measurement of the secular variation of magnetic declination as recorded in cores of sediment is, therefore, shown to be a technique capable of aiding sedimentological studies on the continental shelf as well as in deep-ocean or lake environments. © 1975.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Export Date: 2 November 2011&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-49549138047&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=8155fda7573bdfc0b42998fbd816bc70</style></url></related-urls></urls></record><record><database name="19_South_Cumbria_Low_Fells_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\19_South_Cumbria_Low_Fells_Shortlist.enl">19_South_Cumbria_Low_Fells_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>18</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="dpfap2wee2fep9ezrxjpffeqvdafpe0e0xd5">18</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">George, D. G.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Centre for Ecology and Hydrology, Lancaster, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">The impact of the North Atlantic oscillation on the development of ice on Lake Windermere</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Climatic Change</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Climatic Change</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">455-468</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">81</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">3-4</style></number><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2007</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Windermere, the largest lake in England, seldom freezes over but the sheltered bays are usually covered with ice for several days every year. Here I analyse the meteorological factors influencing the development of ice on the lake between 1933 and 2000 and relate these to the regional and global changes in the weather. The results demonstrate that the methods used to describe the development of ice at high latitudes can also be used to predict the formation of ice on this temperate lake. The best indicator of change was the number of ice-days recorded every winter. Regression analyses based on a Poisson model showed that there were significant negative correlations between the number of ice-days and the local air temperature, the Central England Temperature and the North Atlantic Oscillation Index (NAOI). The relationship with the NAOI was particularly pronounced and explained 50% of the observed inter-annual variations. A hindcasting model based on the NAOI correctly predicted the most severe winters reported in the area between 1864 and 1910. The observed and predicted numbers of ice-days were also correlated with an index of sea ice in the Baltic. The results demonstrate that the number of ice-days reported on Windermere} can be used as a proxy indicator of climate change and show that the NAO has had a major effect on the development of ice on this lake for at least a hundred and thirty years. © 2007 Springer Science+Business Media, Inc.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 7&#xD;Export Date: 23 February 2012&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-33847676901&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=0f000d0ae4e84831c604f882fe86ef71</style></url></related-urls></urls></record><record><database name="19_South_Cumbria_Low_Fells_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\19_South_Cumbria_Low_Fells_Shortlist.enl">19_South_Cumbria_Low_Fells_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>19</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="dpfap2wee2fep9ezrxjpffeqvdafpe0e0xd5">19</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">George, D. G.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Järvinen, M.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Arvola, L.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Centre for Ecology and Hydrology, Lancaster Environment Centre, Library Avenue, Bailrigg, Lancaster, LA1 4AP, United Kingdom&#xD;Lammi Biological Station, University of Helsinki, Pääjärventie 320, FIN-16900, Lammi, Finland</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">The influence of the North Atlantic Oscillation on the winter characteristics of Windermere (UK) and Pääjärvi (Finland)</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Boreal Environment Research</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Boreal Environment Research</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">389-399</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">9</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">5</style></number><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2004</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">The atmospheric pressure gradient known as the North Atlantic Oscillation (NAO) has been shown to influence the dynamics of lakes in a number of European regions. Here, we compare the impact of the NAO on the winter dynamics of Windermere, a lake located in the north-west of England, and Pääjärvi, a lake situated in southern Finland. At both sites, the variations in the NAO index had a significant effect on the winter weather and the physical and chemical characteristics of the lakes. At Windermere, the strongest correlations were those noted for the air temperature, precipitation, the number of days when ice was recorded on the lake and the de-trended concentration of nitrate. At Pääjärvi the strongest correlations were with the air temperature and the de-trended concentrations of nitrate. One striking difference between the sites was the sign of the correlations noted between the NAO index and the de-trended nitrate. At Windermere, this correlation was negative and appeared to be driven by the enhanced terrestrial uptake of nitrate in mild winters. At Pääjärvi, the correlation was positive and was associated with the earlier &apos;flush&apos; of melt water from the catchment. The results are discussed in relation to the regional effects of climate change and the sensitivity of boreal lakes to subtle changes in the &apos;centre of action&apos; of the NAO.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 12&#xD;Export Date: 23 February 2012&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-8344246305&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=d21565d0fcdb2ccfbec3ec3a08f13787</style></url></related-urls></urls></record><record><database name="19_South_Cumbria_Low_Fells_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\19_South_Cumbria_Low_Fells_Shortlist.enl">19_South_Cumbria_Low_Fells_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>15</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="dpfap2wee2fep9ezrxjpffeqvdafpe0e0xd5">15</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Turner, G. M.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Thompson, R.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Geophysics Dept., Univ of Edinburgh, UK.</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Lake sediment record of the geomagnetic secular variation in Britain during Holocene times</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Geophysical Journal, Royal Astronomical Society</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Geophysical Journal, Royal Astronomical Society</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">703-725</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">65</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">3</style></number><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1981</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">A palaeomagnetic record of the geomagnetic secular variation during the last 10 000 years has been obtained from 10 cores of sediment from Loch Lomond, Scotland, Lake Windermere, North England, and Llyn Geirionydd, North Wales. A time-scale is provided by 30 radiocarbon age determinations and pollen analyses on several of the cores. The main swings and much fine detail of both declination and inclination records repeat well between cores and between lakes, and the overall record is much more detailed than previous European records. The new record shows that neither declination nor inclination swings have been periodic over the past 10 000 years, but that the main swings have become progressively shorter in duration during that time. Each swing is characterized by fine detail which enables use of the record as a secondary method of dating other European sediments. The motion of the geomagnetic vector has been predominantly clockwise throughout the time period spanned, but confirms a period of anticlockwise motion from 1100 to 600 BP first discovered by British archaeomagnetic investigations. The record agrees with British and Czechoslovakian archaeomagnetic records, but not with Japanese archaeomagnetic or North American lake sediment records. This suggests that the secular changes are controlled by local growing and decaying, drifting sources, rather than by wobbling of the main geomagnetic dipole. -Author.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 74&#xD;Export Date: 2 November 2011&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-0019697752&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=53ae2757ecc0133793c6bc8ebd0a8d4e</style></url></related-urls></urls></record><record><database name="19_South_Cumbria_Low_Fells_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\19_South_Cumbria_Low_Fells_Shortlist.enl">19_South_Cumbria_Low_Fells_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>16</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="dpfap2wee2fep9ezrxjpffeqvdafpe0e0xd5">16</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Vardy, Mark E.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Pinson, Luke J. W.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Bull, Jonathan M.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Dix, Justin K.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Henstock, Timothy J.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Davis, John W.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Gutowski, Martin</style></author></authors></contributors><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">3D seismic imaging of buried Younger Dryas mass movement flows: Lake Windermere, UK</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Geomorphology</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Geomorphology</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">176-187</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">118</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1-2</style></number><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2010</style></year><pub-dates><date><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">May 15</style></date></pub-dates></dates><isbn><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">0169-555X</style></isbn><accession-num><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">WOS:000278424700014</style></accession-num><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Windermere is a glacially overdeepened lake located in the southeastern Lake District, UK. Using the three-dimensional (3D) Chirp subbottom profiler, we image mass movement deposits related to the Younger Dryas (YD) within a decimetre-resolution 3D seismic volume, documenting their internal structure and interaction with preexisting deposits in unprecedented detail. Three distinct flow events are identified and mapped throughout the 3D survey area. Package structures and seismic attributes classify them as: a small (total volume of c. 1500 m(3)) debris flow containing deformed translated blocks; a large (inferred total volume of c. 500,000 m(3)), homogeneous fine-grained mass flow deposit; and a debris flow (inferred total volume of c. 60,000 m(3)) containing small (c. 8.0 x 2.0 m) deformed translated blocks. Geomorphological mapping of their distribution and interaction with preexisting sediments permit the reconstruction of a depositional history for the stratigraphic units identified in the seismic volume. Crown Copyright (C) 2010 Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Times Cited: 1</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">&lt;Go to ISI&gt;://WOS:000278424700014</style></url></related-urls></urls><electronic-resource-num><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">10.1016/j.geomorph.2009.12.017</style></electronic-resource-num></record></records></xml>