<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><xml><records><record><database name="36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl">36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>89</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="0xrewz0z5t90fke005vp0tf6zwdexvtxdrt5">89</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Daniels, S. M.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Agnew, C. T.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Allott, T. E. H.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Evans, M. G.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Upland Environments Research Unit, Geography, School of Environment and Development, Oxford Road, Manchester, M13 9PL, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Water table variability and runoff generation in an eroded peatland, South Pennines, UK</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Journal of Hydrology</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Journal of Hydrology</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">214-226</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">361</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1-2</style></number><keywords><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Erosion</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Macropore</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Peat hydrology</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Pipeflow</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Runoff</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Water table variability</style></keyword></keywords><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2008</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Hydrological monitoring in an eroded South Pennine peatland shows that persistent and frequent water table drawdowns occur at gully edge locations, defining a deeper and thicker acrotelm than is observed in intact peatlands (an erosional acrotelm). Antecedent water table elevation is a key control on the hydrological response to precipitation events, in particular runoff percent, the timing of peak discharges and maximum water table elevations. Significant discharge is generated whilst water table elevations are relatively low at gully edge locations, and this has a strong influence on flow pathways. Four characteristics of runoff response are recognised: (i) the rapid development of macropore/pipe flow at the start of the storm; (ii) peat rewetting, water table elevation increase and continued macropore/pipe flow; (iii) maximum water table elevations and peak stream discharge with throughflow occurring within the erosional acrotelm and rapid flow through the subsurface macropore/pipe network; (iv) rapidly declining water table elevations and stream flow following the cessation of rainfall. Gully edge peats provide a key linkage between the hillslope hydrological system and channel flow so that their influence on the hydrological functioning of the peatlands is disproportionate to their aerial extent within the catchment. Future climate change may lead to further degradation of the bogs and a reinforcement of the importance of erosion gullies to runoff generation and water quality. © 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 7&#xD;Export Date: 20 December 2011&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-52949116033&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=e5e0258b620a1463ec0429fa20b9b059</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.sciencedirect.com.ezproxy.liv.ac.uk/science/article/pii/S0022169408003995</style></url></related-urls></urls></record><record><database name="36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl">36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>90</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="0xrewz0z5t90fke005vp0tf6zwdexvtxdrt5">90</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Daniels, S. M.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Evans, M. G.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Agnew, C. T.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Allott, T. E. H.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Upland Environments Research Unit, Geography, School of Environment and Development, Oxford Road, Manchester, M13 9PL, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Sulphur leaching from headwater catchments in an eroded peatland, South Pennines, U.K</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Science of the Total Environment</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Science of the Total Environment</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">481-496</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">407</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1</style></number><keywords><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Acidity</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">DOC</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Erosion</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Headwater catchments</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Hydrology</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Peat</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Pollution</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">South Pennines</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Sulphur</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Water table</style></keyword></keywords><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2008</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">A detailed investigation into sulphur leaching in peatland headwater catchments in the South Pennines, UK shows that, despite significant reductions in sulphur emissions, sulphur remains a key acidifier. This sulphur can be considered as legacy atmospheric pollution, stored within the peat by processes of dissimilatory sulphate reduction and now being leached into the region&apos;s surface waters. Persistently lower water tables at gully edge locations define a thick erosional acrotelm that is vulnerable to aeration, oxidation and flushing throughout the year, and not solely confined to periods of drought. Stream discharge behaves as a two-end member system, whereby pre-event water, rich in DOC and sulphate, is diluted by event water as a result of event water flowing through fast flow pathways such as macropores and overland flow. A rapid increase in water table elevation during the storm and a decrease in elevation after the storm indicate that event water has infiltrated the peat and has then been released into the stream. Streamwaters in peat dominated upland catchments with high densities of gullying have high concentrations of sulphate and low concentrations of DOC, whereas the reverse is true for those catchments with low densities of gullying. This is consistent with the concept that high concentrations of sulphate can suppress the solubility of DOC. A significant store of sulphate exists within South Pennine peats, and continued gully erosion will enhance sulphur leaching meaning that the timescale involved for any depletion is uncertain. It is therefore important that models predicting recovery from acidification in these upland systems include an understanding of how this stored sulphur is being leached, especially with respect to gully erosion, climate change and reduced precipitation. © 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 4&#xD;Export Date: 20 December 2011&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-56249141427&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=7d51fd1616d69907fface125d6292f55</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.sciencedirect.com.ezproxy.liv.ac.uk/science/article/pii/S0048969708008486</style></url></related-urls></urls></record><record><database name="36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl">36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>92</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="0xrewz0z5t90fke005vp0tf6zwdexvtxdrt5">92</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Davies, B. J.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Roberts, D. H.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Bridgland, D. R.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Ó Cofaigh, C.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Riding, J. B.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Demarchi, B.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Penkman, K. E. H.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Pawley, S. M.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Department of Geography, Durham University, Science Laboratories, South Road, Durham, DH1 3LE, UK&#xD;Centre for Glaciology, The Institute of Geography and Earth Sciences, Aberystwyth University, Llandinam Building, Penglais Campus, Aberystwyth, SY23 3DB, UK&#xD;British Geological Survey, Kingsley Dunham Centre, Keyworth, Nottingham, NG12 5GG, UK&#xD;BioArCh, Departments of Biology, Archaeology and Chemistry, University of York, York, YO10 5DD, UK&#xD;Department of Geography, Royal Holloway, University of London, Egham, Surrey, TW20 0EX, UK</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Timing and depositional environments of a Middle Pleistocene glaciation of northeast England: New evidence from Warren House Gill, County Durham</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Quaternary Science Reviews</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Quaternary Science Reviews</style></full-title></periodical><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2010</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">At various times during the Quaternary, north-eastern England was a zone of confluence between dynamic ice lobes sourced from the Pennines, northern Scotland, the Cheviots, and Scandinavia. The region thus has some of the most complex exposures of Middle to Late Pleistocene sediments in Britain, with both interglacial and glacial sediments deposited in terrestrial and marine settings. We investigated sedimentary sequences exposed on the coastline of County Durham at Warren House Gill, and present a new model of British and Fennoscandian Ice Sheet interaction in the North Sea Basin during the Middle Pleistocene. The stratigraphy at Warren House Gill consists of a lower diamicton and upper estuarine sediments, both part of the Warren House Formation. They are separated from the overlying Weichselian Blackhall and Horden tills by a substantial unconformity. The lower diamicton of the Warren House Formation is re-interpreted here as an MIS 8 to 12 glaciomarine deposit containing ice-rafted lithics from north-eastern Scotland and the northeast North Sea, and is renamed the &apos;Ash Gill Member&apos;. It is dated by lithological comparison to the Easington Raised Beach, Middle Pleistocene Amino Acid Racemisation values, and indirectly by optically stimulated luminescence. The overlying shallow subaqueous sediments were deposited in an estuarine environment by suspension settling and bottom current activity. They are named the &apos;Whitesides Member&apos;, and form the uppermost member of the Warren House Formation. During glaciation, ice-rafted material was deposited in a marine embayment. There is no evidence of a grounded, onshore Scandinavian ice sheet in County Durham during MIS 6, which has long been held as the accepted stratigraphy. This has major implications for the currently accepted British Quaternary Stratigraphy. Combined with recent work on the Middle Pleistocene North Sea Drift from Norfolk, which is now suggested to have been deposited by a Scottish ice sheet, the presence of a Scandinavian ice sheet in eastern England at any time during the Quaternary is becoming increasingly doubtful. © 2010 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Export Date: 20 December 2011&#xD;Source: Scopus&#xD;Article in Press</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-77950588522&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=8bd724b86319075b5f5252a2b9523c33</style></url></related-urls></urls></record><record><database name="36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl">36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>93</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="0xrewz0z5t90fke005vp0tf6zwdexvtxdrt5">93</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Davis, J. D.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Davis, G. A.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Department of Geography and Human Environmental Studies, San Francisco State University, San Francisco, CA 94132, United States&#xD;Beckman Coulter, Chaska, MN 55318, United States</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Transport and dispersal of organic debris (Peat blocks) in upland fluvial systems</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Earth Surface Processes and Landforms</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Earth Surface Processes and Landforms</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1087-1102</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">26</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">10</style></number><keywords><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Abrasion</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Deposition</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Flotation</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Peat</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Sediment transport</style></keyword></keywords><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2001</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">This paper assesses the mechanisms and pathways by which peat blocks are eroded and transported in upland fluvial systems. Observations and experiments from the north Pennines (UK) have been carried out on two contrasting river systems. Mapping of peat block distributions and appraisal of reach-based sediment budgets clearly demonstrates that macro-size peat is an important stream load component. In small streams block sizes can approximate the channel width and much of the peat is transported overbank. Local &apos;peat jams&apos; and associated mineral deposition may provide an important component of channel storage. In larger systems peat blocks rapidly move down-channel and undergo frequent exchanges between bed and bank storage. Results of peat block tracing using painted blocks indicate that once submerged, blocks of all sizes are easily transported and blocks break down rapidly by abrasion. Vegetation and bars play an important role in trapping mobile peat. In smaller streams large block transport is limited by channel jams. Smaller blocks are transported overbank but exhibit little evidence of downstream fining. In larger rivers peat blocks are more actively sorted and show downstream reduction in size from source. A simple model relating peat block diameter (Dp) to average flow depth (d) suggests three limiting transport conditions: Flotation (Dp &amp;lt; d), rolling (d &amp;lt; Dp &amp;gt; d/2) and deposition (Dp &amp;gt; d/2). Experiments demonstrate that peat block transport occurs largely by rolling and floating and the transport mechanism is probably controlled by relative flow depth (d/Dp ratio). Transport velocity varies with transport mechanism (rolling is the slowest mode) and transport lengths increase as flow depth increases. Abrasion rates vary with the transport mechanism. Rolling produces greater abrasion rates and more rounded blocks. Abrasion rates vary from O to 10 g m-1 for blocks ranging in mass from 10 to 6000 g. Copyright © 2001 John Wiley and Sons, Ltd.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 12&#xD;Export Date: 20 December 2011&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-0035447847&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=533dd5760fc0a5346d20d9ee29ee7de8</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/store/10.1002/esp.256/asset/256_ftp.pdf?v=1&amp;t=h03nrez0&amp;s=36764e8850c019cb612f5f6db34d699fa15fc2a8</style></url></related-urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Davis-2001-Transport and disper-2438200576/Davis-2001-Transport and disper.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl">36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>94</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="0xrewz0z5t90fke005vp0tf6zwdexvtxdrt5">94</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">de Rance, C. E.</style></author></authors></contributors><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">On the glacial phenomena of western Lancashire and Cheshire</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Quarterly Journal of the Geological Society of London</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Quarterly Journal of the Geological Society of London</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">641-655</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">26</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1-2</style></number><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1870</style></year></dates><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 3&#xD;Export Date: 20 December 2011&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-0004984922&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=73e15f9e5d5e68fb2a78083731666a6c</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://jgslegacy.lyellcollection.org/content/26/1-2/641.full.pdf</style></url></related-urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://de Rance-1870-On the glacial pheno-1096021504/de Rance-1870-On the glacial pheno.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl">36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>95</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="0xrewz0z5t90fke005vp0tf6zwdexvtxdrt5">95</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Dennis, I. A.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Coulthard, T. J.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Brewer, P.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Macklin, M. G.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Royal Haskoning, Burns House, Harlands Road, Haywards Heath, West Sussex RH16 1PG, United Kingdom&#xD;Department of Geography, University of Hull, Hull, United Kingdom&#xD;Institute of Geography and Earth Sciences, University of Wales, Aberystwyth, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">The role of floodplains in attenuating contaminated sediment fluxes in formerly mined drainage basins</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Earth Surface Processes and Landforms</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Earth Surface Processes and Landforms</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">453-466</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">34</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">3</style></number><keywords><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Floodplain storage</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Historical mining</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Metal contamination</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Sediment budget</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Tributary storage</style></keyword></keywords><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2009</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Many upland river catchments in the UK have been historically mined for metals such as lead (Pb) and zinc (Zn), and as part of the mining process large quantities of metal contaminated sediment were released into the river system. The levels of sediment associated heavy metal contamination in river systems are largely controlled by the volumes of contaminated sediment released into the river and fluvial processes (e.g. erosion and deposition). As a consequence, the contamination patterns are often highly variable, which can make it difficult to create accurate assessments of the volumes of contaminated sediment remaining within the system. This paper uses a combination of techniques to establish the volumes of metal contaminated sediment remaining within the River Swale, UK. Firstly, using detailed field sampling and a geographical information system (GIS), it estimates the volumes of sediment remaining within one formerly mined tributary (Gunnerside Beck) which is then extrapolated to represent the contaminant volumes on other tributaries of the River Swale. Secondly, combining fresh field data with a range of existing data, volumes of contaminated sediment on the main stream of the River Swale are established. This two tier approach shows that significant volumes of contaminated sediment remain within the River Swale, with over 32 000 tonnes of Pb within the mined tributaries and 123 000 tonnes within the main channel belt of the River Swale itself. This represents approximately 28% of the Pb produced in the Swale catchment. Given these volumes and present day rates of removal, it may take over 5000 years for all of the metal rich sediment to be removed from the catchment. If the contaminated sediment is used as a tracer, present day rates of reworking of floodplain sediment can be calculated to be 0.02% per year. Copyright © 2008 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 7&#xD;Export Date: 20 December 2011&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-66149154325&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=155b978ca77c90b65a34d546d1bd661d</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/store/10.1002/esp.1762/asset/1762_ftp.pdf?v=1&amp;t=h03nrmw3&amp;s=4cfd22cca806c0885fa20505adde10334e80a80f</style></url></related-urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Dennis-2009-The role of floodpla-2018781184/Dennis-2009-The role of floodpla.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl">36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>96</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="0xrewz0z5t90fke005vp0tf6zwdexvtxdrt5">96</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Dennis, I. A.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Macklin, M. G.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Coulthard, T. J.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Brewer, P. A.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">River Basin Dynamics/Hydrology Res., Inst. of Geography/Earth Sciences, University of Wales, Aberystwyth, Ceredigion SY23 3DB, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">The impact of the October-November 2000 floods on contaminant metal dispersal in the River Swale catchment, North Yorkshire, UK</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Hydrological Processes</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Hydrological Processes</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1641-1657</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">17</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">8</style></number><keywords><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Autumn 2000 floods</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Contaminant metals</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Historical metal mining</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">River Swale</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Sediment remobilization</style></keyword></keywords><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2003</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">During the autumn of 2000, large areas of England and Wales were affected by severe flooding, which caused widespread disruption and significant damage to property. This study attempts to determine the impact of these flood events on contaminated sediment dispersal and deposition in the River Swale catchment, Yorkshire, UK, where lead and zinc were extracted and processed in large quantities during the nineteenth century. Seventy samples of overbank and channel-edge sediments were collected at 35 sites along the River Swale. Inductively coupled plasma-mass spectrometry was used to measure contaminant metal concentrations in the 2000-63 μm (sand) and &lt;63 μm (silt and clay) size fractions. In both the channel-edge and overbank sediments collected from the upper and middle reaches of the River Swale, concentrations of lead, zinc and cadmium were found to exceed MAFF guidelines. Highest concentrations correspond to the input of contaminated material from intensively mined tributaries, and elevated levels can be observed 5-10 km downstream of these inputs. This indicates that the remobilization of contaminated material during major flood events is potentially a serious problem for activities such as agriculture that utilize the Swale floodplain. Copyright © 2003 John Wiley and Sons, Ltd.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 27&#xD;Export Date: 20 December 2011&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-0037928465&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=f7e8fd697388d3d3eb8a5879c84b56b5</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/store/10.1002/hyp.1206/asset/1206_ftp.pdf?v=1&amp;t=h03nrvx8&amp;s=b475053d7e4941cbca4b516daa926e0de4355761</style></url></related-urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Dennis-2003-The impact of the Oc-1448365312/Dennis-2003-The impact of the Oc.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl">36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>101</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="0xrewz0z5t90fke005vp0tf6zwdexvtxdrt5">101</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Donnelly, L. J.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Halcrow Group Ltd., Deanway Technology Centre, Wilmslow Road, Handforth SK9 3FB, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Subsidence and associated ground movements on the Pennines, northern England</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Quarterly Journal of Engineering Geology and Hydrogeology</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Quarterly Journal of Engineering Geology and Hydrogeology</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">315-332</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">41</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">3</style></number><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2008</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">The Pennines form a range of hills in northern England. The elevated parts are known locally as &apos;the moors&apos;, and these run from the Scottish border in the north, southwards to the Midlands. The area is dominated by elevated moorland plateaux, which have been incised by glacial and alluvial valleys. The plateaux are capped by strong, massive, cross-bedded Kinderscout Grit of Late Carboniferous (Namurian) age (known also as the Millstone Grit). Interbedded weak shales, mudstones and siltstones crop out on the valley floor, lower slopes and middle slopes, which have been eroded by landslides. The moorland is covered by a veneer of head and peat deposits that may be up to 4 m thick. Two types of subsidence, with associated ground movements, have been observed: (1) the large-scale regional tilting, landsliding and apparent lateral spreading of periglacial moorland plateaux with associated fault scarps and fissures; (2) &apos;sinkholes&apos; in peat, which occur as distinct subsidence depressions up to 2 m in diameter. As these &apos;sinkholes&apos; are not generated by mining subsidence or by the dissolution of (for example, karst or gypsiferous) bedrock, the term pseudo-sinkhole has been introduced, for the purpose of this paper. Pseudo-sinkholes may be occasionally associated with peat slides, bog bursts, subsidence depressions and concentric ring fissures on peat scars. The extent and magnitude of the subsidence and ground movements vary considerably. These may affect small, localized peat-covered slopes, no more than a few metres wide, or influence the morphology of entire moorland slopes. Because of the relative remoteness of &apos;the moors&apos; these types of ground movements do not influence structures, or affect people, and therefore tend to have not been previously investigated, documented or reported. Similar features have been reported in the South Wales Coalfield, where there is a long, complex mining legacy. Since the Kinderscout (Millstone) Grit and associated interbedded sedimentary rocks do not contain any minerals of economic significance, the observed ground movements cannot be attributed to mining subsidence. The Pennine moors therefore provide a unique opporunity to investigate subsidence (tilt), scarps and fissures in the absence of mining (or other human) influences. Subsidence in peat is likely to have been generated by the subsurface fluvial erosion of layered fibrous and amorphous peat deposits. This leads to the generation of subsurface voids (pipes), which subsequently undergo collapse, followed by the migration of the collapsed zone towards the ground surface. This results in the generation of crescent-shaped, concentric fissures, subsidence depressions, graben and pseudo-sinkholes. The mechanism for the large-scale regional tilting and subsidence of moorland plateaux is more difficult to determine and still not fully understood. These ground movements are complex and are associated with deep-seated landslides, complex fissure networks and, in the study area, a reactivated fault-scarp that is up to 4 m high and over 700 m long. This paper suggests that these movements were possibly generated under conditions of periglacial erosion and weathering, during glacier retreat, deglaciation and gravitational stress relief of valley sides. This is most likely to have occurred during the closing stages of the Pleistocene ice age. This may have initiated the lateral spreading of moorland plateaux, subsequently resulting in fissuring, fault reactivation, tilting and subsidence. The aim of this paper is to document and draw attention to the different types of subsidence and associated ground movements on Pennine moorland, and to suggest causal mechanisms. © 2008 Geological Society of London.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 1&#xD;Export Date: 20 December 2011&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-51949110927&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=88d464646ea9370963edf514429c01b8</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://qjegh.geoscienceworld.org/content/41/3/315.full.pdf</style></url></related-urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Donnelly-2008-Subsidence and assoc-2320791552/Donnelly-2008-Subsidence and assoc.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl">36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>102</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="0xrewz0z5t90fke005vp0tf6zwdexvtxdrt5">102</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Donnelly, L. J.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Northmore, K. J.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Siddle, H. J.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">IMC Group Consulting Ltd., British Geological Survey, PO Box 18, Sutton-in-Ashfield, Notts NG17 2NS, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Block movements in the Pennines and South Wales and their association with landslides</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Quarterly Journal of Engineering Geology and Hydrogeology</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Quarterly Journal of Engineering Geology and Hydrogeology</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">33-39</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">35</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1</style></number><keywords><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Discontinuities</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Geological hazards</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Geomorphology</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Landslides</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Mining geology</style></keyword></keywords><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2002</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Fault scarps and graben features indicative of slope deformation have been observed adjacent to the rear scarps of landslides and on moorland plateaux in the Pennines. The scarps are distinct, up to 2 m high and can be traced for a maximum distance of approximately 400 m. These severely reduce the strength of the rock mass, enable groundwater to be channelled onto the upper valley slopes and may have played an important role in the initiation of first-time slope failures, and in the reactivation of older landslides. These features are similar to those recently described on the interfluves of the South Wales Coalfield valleys, and are consistent with those described as &apos;block movements&apos; elsewhere in the world. Those in South Wales have been interpreted, by some previous investigators, as being generated during mining subsidence. However, in the Pennines, the slope and plateaux movements occur in the Namurian (Upper Carboniferous) sedimentary sequences where there has been no mining and it is therefore evident that other mechanisms are involved. In both South Wales and the Pennines steep-sided valleys have incised the moorland plateaux which in both cases are capped by strong, well-jointed cap rocks. These have exposed the underlying, much weaker, fissile mudstones which form the middle and lower slopes. These block movements in the Pennines are documented, discussed and compared with those in South Wales.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 4&#xD;Export Date: 20 December 2011&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-0036170493&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=398c56e1dbde3dc20dc93e84334c4ad5</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://qjegh.geoscienceworld.org/content/35/1/33.full.pdf</style></url></related-urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Donnelly-2002-Block movements in t-1347720960/Donnelly-2002-Block movements in t.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl">36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>105</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="0xrewz0z5t90fke005vp0tf6zwdexvtxdrt5">105</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Douglas, I.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">School of Geography, University of Manchester, Manchester M13 9PL, UK.</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Plate tectonics, palaeoenvironments and limestone geomorphology in west-central Britain</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Earth Surface Processes &amp; Landforms</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Earth Surface Processes &amp; Landforms</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">481-495</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">12</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">5</style></number><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1987</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">The variety of active, exhumed, and buried limetone landforms of northern England, North Wales, and the Isle of Man arises in part from the way in which Dinantian (Lower Carboniferous) sedimentation was affected by a tilt-block basement structure evolved during the closure of the Iapetus Ocean suture to the north, and partly to subsequent plate tectonic movements associated with the closure of the proto-Tethys ocean, the opening of the Atlantic Ocean and the Alpine orogeny. Landforms created during the Dinantian now form important exhumed and buried landscape features. The Permian half-graben structures of the eastern Irish Sea-Cheshire-Worcester Basins account for many of the contrasts between the upland karsts of the Pennines and the lowland karsts of coastal areas.-Author</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 1&#xD;Export Date: 20 December 2011&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-0023479644&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=e85c2237d3f0b4dd0d179c6c9bbdeb02</style></url></related-urls></urls></record><record><database name="36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl">36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>107</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="0xrewz0z5t90fke005vp0tf6zwdexvtxdrt5">107</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Dutton, J. W. R.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Ministry of Agriculture, Fisheries and Food, Fisheries Radiobiological Laboratory, Hamilton Dock, Lowestoft, Suffolk, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Detection of thorium-234/protactinium-234m in sediments from the Ribble Estuary, Lancashire, England [13]</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Nature</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Nature</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1395-1396</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">211</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">5056</style></number><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1966</style></year></dates><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 1&#xD;Export Date: 20 December 2011&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-6744273231&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=77503d8e48f3262471359f207a99ab6c</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.nature.com.ezproxy.liv.ac.uk/nature/journal/v211/n5056/pdf/2111395a0.pdf</style></url></related-urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Dutton-1966-Detection of thorium-2085917952/Dutton-1966-Detection of thorium.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl">36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>112</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="0xrewz0z5t90fke005vp0tf6zwdexvtxdrt5">112</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Evans, C. D.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Jenkins, A.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Institute of Hydrology, OX10 8BB, Wallingford, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Surface water acidification in the South Pennines. II. Temporal trends</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Environmental Pollution</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Environmental Pollution</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">21-34</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">109</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1</style></number><keywords><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Seasonal Kendall test</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">South Pennines</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Surface water acidification</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Temporal trends</style></keyword></keywords><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2000</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Data for eight reservoirs in the South Pennines covering the period 1980-98, and for 1988-98 at the River Etherow Acid Waters Monitoring Network site, have been analysed for temporal trends using the Seasonal Kendall test. Rising trends in pH were identified at seven of the eight reservoirs, generally accompanied by declining aluminium levels. Nitrate concentrations have, however, increased sharply at the two reservoirs for which adequate data were available. Data for a wider range of determinands at the Etherow suggest that pH increases in the region can be attributed to declining sulphate concentrations, as a result of reductions in sulphur deposition. Nitrate concentrations have again increased at this site. Results are significant in a national context in that pH recovery, although widely believed to have taken place in the UK since the 1970s, has rarely been shown to have occurred. For the South Pennine region, which has been severely acidified by historically high acid deposition levels, there have clearly been improvements over the last 18 years, although many surface waters remain acidic. Observed trends for nitrate suggest that some of the pH recovery resulting from reduced sulphur deposition may have been offset by nitrogen saturation in the region, due in part to continued high levels of nitrogen deposition. Copyright (C) 2000 Elsevier Science Ltd.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 17&#xD;Export Date: 20 December 2011&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-0033627442&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=8157759e397f5d81c4d0288fa7fc23fc</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.sciencedirect.com.ezproxy.liv.ac.uk/science/article/pii/S0269749199002420</style></url></related-urls></urls></record><record><database name="36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl">36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>113</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="0xrewz0z5t90fke005vp0tf6zwdexvtxdrt5">113</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Evans, C. D.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Jenkins, A.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Helliwell, R. C.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Ferrier, R.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Institute of Hydrology, Wallingford, Oxon, OX10 8BB, United Kingdom&#xD;Macaulay Land Use Research Institute, Aberdeen, AB15 8QH, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Predicting regional recovery from acidification; the MAGIC model applied to Scotland, England and Wales</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Hydrology and Earth System Sciences</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Hydrology and Earth System Sciences</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">543-554</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">4</style></number><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1998</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">A dynamic, process-based model of surface water acidification, MAGIC, has been applied to over a thousand sites across the UK. The model is calibrated to surface water samples collected during a survey for the Critical Loads programme, and utilises the best available and consistent estimates of soil physical and chemical properties rainfall and runoff volumes, and deposition chemistry. A total of 698 sites were calibrated successfully. At these sites, surface water chemistry was reconstructed from 1850 to the present day, and forecast to 2050 based on future decreases in sulphur (S) deposition in response to the Second S Protocol. Model outputs capture distinct regional patterns of acidification and recovery. The most acidic present-day conditions are found in acid-sensitive regions of Northern England (the Pennines, Lake District and North York Moors). Although a significant proportion of sites in these areas failed to calibrate, those that did are predicted to have experienced severe historic decreases in acid neutralising capacity (ANC) in response to high levels of acidic deposition. The model also indicates significant acidification in the moderate deposition areas of Wales and Galloway, whereas in the low deposition region of northern Scotland, acidification has been minor even in areas of acid-sensitive geology. ANC is forecast to recover at virtually all sites, with the greatest recovery predicted for areas currently subject to high deposition. The model indicates that the Second S Protocol, however, will not be sufficient to produce full recovery, with average ANC increases to 2050 counteracting just 27% of the simulated decline from 1850 to present day. Acidic conditions (ANC &lt;0) are predicted to persist intil 2050 at a significant number of sites in Northern England, Wales and Galloway.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 16&#xD;Export Date: 20 December 2011&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-0032426199&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=08ebe12db5f7f190a28a0520339504a2</style></url></related-urls></urls></record><record><database name="36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl">36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>114</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="0xrewz0z5t90fke005vp0tf6zwdexvtxdrt5">114</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Evans, C. D.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Jenkins, A.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Wright, R. F.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Institute of Hydrology, OX10 8BB, Wallingford, United Kingdom&#xD;Norwegian Inst. for Water Research, Box 173 Kjelsås, 0411, Oslo, Norway</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Surface water acidification in the South Pennines. I. Current status and spatial variability</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Environmental Pollution</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Environmental Pollution</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">11-20</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">109</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1</style></number><keywords><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Acidification</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">South Pennines</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Surface water</style></keyword></keywords><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2000</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">The South Pennines, an area of acid-sensitive geology at the centre of a major industrial region, have undergone perhaps the most severe historic exposure to sulphur and nitrogen deposition in the UK. This study addresses a lack of existing research on the region by presenting the findings of a survey of 62 surface waters sampled during a 1-week period in April 1998. Results indicate that acidification in the region is acute; 27 of the sampled surface waters had a negative acid neutralising capacity (ANC) and 28 had a pH below 5.0. Minimum recorded pH values were below 4.0. Non-marine sulphate levels were extremely high (median 222 μeq/1), and widespread high nitrate concentrations (median 41 μeq/1) suggest that soils in the region as a whole may be at an advanced stage of nitrogen saturation. A consistent relationship was identified between site acidity and the balance between the major weathering-derived cations, calcium and magnesium, and sulphate. This could in turn be linked to catchment soil type and land use, with the most acidic conditions occurring in peat-dominated catchments, where weathering is minimal and the influence of atmospheric deposition most pronounced. Percentage of peat in each catchment was the single best predictor of surface water acidity. Nitrate concentrations, although not a dominant control on acidity, varied significantly according to land use. Elevated concentrations were observed in catchments containing forestry, due to enhanced deposition inputs, and in catchments containing improved land, linked to fertiliser use. Ammonium concentrations, although low at most catchments, were a significant component of the inorganic nitrogen total in a number of surface waters draining waterlogged peat catchments. Copyright (C) 2000 Elsevier Science Ltd.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 20&#xD;Export Date: 20 December 2011&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-0033627443&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=a0569db4b34be5679dd102b0e10af74a</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.sciencedirect.com.ezproxy.liv.ac.uk/science/article/pii/S0269749199002419</style></url></related-urls></urls></record><record><database name="36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl">36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>117</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="0xrewz0z5t90fke005vp0tf6zwdexvtxdrt5">117</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Evans, M.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Lindsay, J.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Upland Environments Research Unit, School of Environment and Development, University of Manchester, Manchester M19 3PL, United Kingdom&#xD;Department of Geography, University of Guelph, 50 Stone Road East, Guelph, ON N1G 2W1, Canada</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Impact of gully erosion on carbon sequestration in blanket peatlands</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Climate Research</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Climate Research</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">31-41</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">45</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1</style></number><keywords><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Blanket peat</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Carbon balance</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Carbon sequestration</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Gully erosion</style></keyword></keywords><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2010</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Over 50% of UK soil carbon is stored in peatland systems and 75% of these peatlands are upland blanket bog. The upland blanket bogs of the UK have suffered severe erosion over the last millennium so that they are widely dissected by gully systems. Gully erosion entails primary removal of particulate carbon from the peatland system but also has secondary effects in that it enhances drainage and lowers water tables, potentially enhancing decomposition of surface peats. This paper exploits recent high resolution mapping of the gully erosion on the Bleaklow Plateau in the southern Pennines and existing data on peat growth rates in the area to assess the impact of gully erosion on peatland carbon balance and the relative importance of primary and secondary impacts of gullying on carbon sequestration. The results indicate that gully erosion during the last millennium has shifted the Bleaklow Plateau from being a net sink of carbon (-20.3 gC m-2 yr-1) to a net source (29.4 gC m-2 yr-1). The relative importance of gullying impacts can be expressed as follows: particulate organic carbon (POC) flux &amp;gt; change in gully net ecosystem exchange ≫ loss of gully margin carbon sequestration. The implication of these findings is that the magnitude of the potentially reversible impacts of gully erosion (reduced carbon fixation due to vegetation loss and ongoing erosional loss of POC) far exceed the effects associated with irreversible morphological change (enhanced peat decomposition in gully margin locations). © Inter-Research 2010.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 3&#xD;Export Date: 20 December 2011&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-79551522620&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=da7424cf777b595b0e786a6e96f07efe</style></url></related-urls></urls></record><record><database name="36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl">36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>118</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="0xrewz0z5t90fke005vp0tf6zwdexvtxdrt5">118</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Evans, M.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Warburton, J.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Yang, J.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Upland Environments Research Unit, School of Environment and Development, University of Manchester, Oxford Road, M13 9PL, United Kingdom&#xD;Earth Surface Systems Research Group, Department of Geography, University of Durham, South Road, Durham, DH1 3LE, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Eroding blanket peat catchments: Global and local implications of upland organic sediment budgets</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Geomorphology</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Geomorphology</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">45-57</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">79</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1-2</style></number><keywords><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Carbon flux</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Erosion control</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Peat</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Sediment budget</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Sediment yield</style></keyword></keywords><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2006</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Globally, peatlands account for circa 50% of terrestrial carbon storage containing as much carbon as is present in the atmosphere. The uplands of the UK have an extensive cover of blanket peat but much of it is actively eroding. This paper presents a detailed organic sediment budget for a blanket peat catchment in the north Pennines and comparative data from a catchment in the southern Pennines. The catchments have total sediment yields (organic and mineral) of 44 and 267 t km- 2 a- 1 and organic sediment yields 31 and 195 t km- 2 a- 1, respectively. They represent two extremes of a spectrum of eroded peat catchments. It is demonstrated that the lower sediment yields in the north Pennines are associated with extensive natural revegetation of the catchment and consequent reductions in slope-channel linkage. Construction of a carbon budget for the north Pennine catchment demonstrates that particulate carbon losses associated with the fluvial suspended sediment load are the largest single carbon loss from the system. The system is currently close to carbon neutral but much higher carbon losses associated with actively eroding systems such as the south Pennine site would make these systems a major carbon source. The possibility that enhanced summer temperatures and winter storminess will accelerate erosion of upland mires means there is a risk that physical degradation of peatlands could become a significant positive feedback on global warming. Mitigation of these potential global effects will depend on local management informed by a clear understanding of peatland sediment dynamics. The sediment budget data here suggest that in gullied peatlands revegetation of gully floors is an effective control on sediment flux so that techniques such as gully blocking are likely to be effective approaches to erosion control. © 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 36&#xD;Export Date: 20 December 2011&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-33746961198&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=a98cde1682dca7d0547e7b92dc4da5ce</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://ac.els-cdn.com.ezproxy.liv.ac.uk/S0169555X06000687/1-s2.0-S0169555X06000687-main.pdf?_tid=12dac8dca9242b133250c99085fa3ef7&amp;acdnat=1332412364_5957835aa6cdb22cc57536870100ed04</style></url></related-urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Evans-2006-Eroding blanket peat-0710228224/Evans-2006-Eroding blanket peat.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl">36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>119</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="0xrewz0z5t90fke005vp0tf6zwdexvtxdrt5">119</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Evans, M. G.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Burt, T. P.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Holden, J.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Adamson, J. K.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">School of Geography, Univ. Manchester, M13 9PL, M., Manchester, United Kingdom&#xD;Department of Geography, University of Durham, DH1 3LE, Durham, United Kingdom&#xD;Environmental Change Network, Inst. Terrestrial Ecol., M., Grange-over-Sands, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Runoff generation and water table fluctuations in blanket peat: Evidence from UK data spanning the dry summer of 1995</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Journal of Hydrology</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Journal of Hydrology</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">141-160</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">221</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">3-4</style></number><keywords><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Blanket peat hydrology</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Drought</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">North Pennines</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Runoff</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Water table</style></keyword></keywords><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1999</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Understanding of the hydrology of upland blanket peatlands has been limited both by the logistical difficulties of obtaining data from such environments and by technical difficulties with plot scale investigations of peat hydrology. The relative importance of infiltration-excess and percolation-excess as runoff generating mechanisms as opposed to the saturation-excess mechanism remains unclear. This study uses catchment-scale runoff data, in combination with monitoring of water table levels, to identify the relative importance of these mechanisms for an upland peat catchment within the Moor House National Nature Reserve in the UK. Mean runoff coefficients for the catchment are 0.4 and the flood hydrographs are flashy. Monitored water table in the catchment is within 5 cm of the surface (i.e. within the acrotelm) 93% of the time. High stream flows always occur at times of high water table suggesting that overland and near surface runoff is controlled by saturation of the catotelm rather than by infiltration capacity. Depressed rates of water table recovery at the end of a prolonged period of low water table in 1995 suggest possible physical changes once the peat has dried out. The likelihood that such periods of low water table will become more common under global warming scenarios raises concern over the impact of such changes: increased erosion, water discoloration, and increased CO2 flux may result. Understanding of the hydrology of upland blanket peatlands has been limited both by the logistical difficulties of obtaining data from such environments and by technical difficulties with plot scale investigations of peat hydrology. The relative importance of infiltration-excess and percolation-excess as runoff generating mechanisms as opposed to the saturation-excess mechanism remains unclear. This study uses catchment-scale runoff data, in combination with monitoring of water table levels, to identify the relative importance of these mechanisms for an upland peat catchment within the Moor House National Nature Reserve in the UK. Mean runoff coefficients for the catchment are 0.4 and the flood hydrographs are flashy. Monitored water table in the catchment is within 5 cm of the surface (i.e. within the acrotelm) 93% of the time. High stream flows always occur at times of high water table suggesting that overland and near surface runoff is controlled by saturation of the catotelm rather than by infiltration capacity. Depressed rates of water table recovery at the end of a prolonged period of low water table in 1995 suggest possible physical changes once the peat has dried out. The likelihood that such periods of low water table will become more common under global warming scenarios raises concern over the impact of such changes: increased erosion, water discoloration, and increased CO2 flux may result.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 97&#xD;Export Date: 20 December 2011&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-0033618850&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=2bb34d1ceb277846abb2464e3b1f24ac</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.sciencedirect.com.ezproxy.liv.ac.uk/science/article/pii/S0022169499000852</style></url></related-urls></urls></record></records></xml>