<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><xml><records><record><database name="36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl">36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>254</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="0xrewz0z5t90fke005vp0tf6zwdexvtxdrt5">254</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Naden, P. S.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">McDonald, A. T.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Institute of Hydrology, Crowmarsh Gifford, Wallingford, OX10 8BB, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Statistical modelling of water colour in the uplands: The Upper Nidd catchment 1979-1987</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Environmental Pollution</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Environmental Pollution</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">141-163</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">60</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1-2</style></number><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1989</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">The increasing colour of raw water from the uplands is a matter of concern to water managers. The colour record for the period 1979-1987 is examined for the catchments of Upper Nidderdale, North Yorkshire. The variation in colour shows a marked seasonality with peaks occuring during the autumn months. No long-term sustained increase in colour is found, although colour levels were high in 1980, 1985 and 1987. Colour is found to be highly correlated with iron and, more particularly, aluminium. There is no relationship between colour and turbidity which suggests that there is no direct link between colour levels and erosion on the catchments. Colour increases appear to relate to large soil moisture deficits in months immediately prior to the colour flush and to high soil moisture deficits in the previous year. Complementary relationships are found between monthly rainfall totals and colour. In the light of these findings, it is suggested that high colour is associated with water table lowering and aerobic decomposition of the upper organic peat layers.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 33&#xD;Export Date: 20 December 2011&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-0024472291&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=002b54dafa4e7c1dfc4bf1f119570a27</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.sciencedirect.com.ezproxy.liv.ac.uk/science/article/pii/0269749189902248</style></url></related-urls></urls></record><record><database name="36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl">36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>255</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="0xrewz0z5t90fke005vp0tf6zwdexvtxdrt5">255</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Nash, D. J.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Earth and Environ. Sci. Res. Unit, University of Brighton, Mithras House, Lewes Road, Brighton, BN2 4AT, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Groundwater sapping and valley development in the Hackness Hills, North Yorkshire, England</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Earth Surface Processes and Landforms</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Earth Surface Processes and Landforms</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">781-795</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">21</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">9</style></number><keywords><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Groundwater sapping</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Groundwater seepage</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Hackness Hills</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">North Yorkshire</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Valley development</style></keyword></keywords><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1996</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">This paper describes evidence for the role of groundwater sapping and seepage erosion processes in the development of valleys which cut the southern edge of the Hackness Hills plateau in North Yorkshire, England. The development of drainage in this region has previously been suggested to relate to erosion by Late Devensian sub-aerial glacial meltwater channels. The role of groundwater erosion is investigated through a combination of geomorphological studies, lithological logging and X-ray diffraction (XRD) analyses. The geology of the region consists of a series of permeable Middle and Upper Jurassic lithologies (the Corallian sequence and Lower Calcareous Grit) which overlie the impermeable Upper Oxford Clay. The rocks dip gently to the south at between 1° and 4° and are relatively unfolded. Valleys exhibit many characteristic features of groundwater sapping networks. They rise abruptly at the edge of the plateau with amphitheatre-like valley heads, alcoves in headwalls, steep bedrock side walls, flat floors, spring sites and seepage zones in many valley flanks. Lithological logging indicates that sites of groundwater emergence usually occur either at or slightly above the boundary of the Upper Oxford Clay and Lower Calcareous Grit. XRD analyses of bedrock samples indicate that seepage occurs within siltstones which contain no clay but a variable percentage of calcite. The cause of groundwater emergence is attributed to decreasing grain size and increasing calcite cementation within bedrock which combine to reduce permeability. Development of valleys in the Hackness Hills is suggested to have occurred by a combination of headward erosion by groundwater sapping processes operating in an up-dip direction superimposed onto a valley morphology shaped by surface fluvial erosion.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 10&#xD;Export Date: 20 December 2011&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-0030461176&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=100e718f3c8d308a775cf53ec07bd602</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/store/10.1002/(SICI)1096-9837(199609)21:9&lt;781::AID-ESP616&gt;3.0.CO;2-O/asset/616_ftp.pdf?v=1&amp;t=h03o1pl1&amp;s=0cae0d2b3bdc7633888323f4b186a393dcd1e8e3</style></url></related-urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Nash-1996-Groundwater sapping-3109769472/Nash-1996-Groundwater sapping.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl">36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>264</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="0xrewz0z5t90fke005vp0tf6zwdexvtxdrt5">264</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">O&apos;Donnell, G.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Ewen, J.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">O&apos;Connell, P. E.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">School of Civil Engineering and Geosciences, Newcastle University, Cassie Building, Newcastle Upon Tyne, NE1 7RU, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Sensitivity maps for impacts of land management on an extreme flood in the Hodder catchment, UK</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Physics and Chemistry of the Earth</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Physics and Chemistry of the Earth</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">630-637</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">36</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">13</style></number><keywords><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Adjoint modelling</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Catchment modelling</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Flooding</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Land use management</style></keyword></keywords><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2011</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">It is increasingly recognised that the management of land and the management of water are strongly interdependent, and that integrated management approaches are needed. There is evidence that modern land management practices have an effect on runoff generation in rural upland areas, so there is the potential to use land management control as a tool in flood risk mitigation programmes. Flooding from historical extreme rainfall events must be considered when designing mitigation programmes, especially if the designs have to take into account the possibility that such events will become more frequent in the future.The largest 90min rainfall ever recorded in the UK was 117mm, recorded in 1967 in the Dunsop tributary (25km2) of the Hodder catchment, northwest England. Extensive land management changes have recently been made in the catchment, including peat restoration, tree planting and reductions in sheep stocking density, and the analysis of the flooding in 1967 has been undertaken as part of a wider study on the potential impact of the recent changes.A method is demonstrated in which maps of sensitivity are plotted which show how peak flows for extreme events are affected by spatial patterns of changes in runoff generation. This method uses a gridded model for runoff generation containing an embedded hydraulic model of the river network which can calculate sensitivities efficiently and accurately using reverse algorithmic differentiation. The modelling examines the sensitivity of the hydrograph peak at the catchment outlet to changes in flashy runoff generation, which can be affected by land management practices including the blocking of open drainage channels in peat moorland. It is concluded that, as a result of hydraulic and geomorphologic dispersion in the network, changes in land management that affect the flashiness of runoff generation at small scales would probably have had only a relatively minor effect on the flow peaks at the outlet from the catchment during the 1967 extreme event. © 2011 Elsevier Ltd.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 1&#xD;Export Date: 20 December 2011&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-80053109436&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=19b989156d5967d129fe5287465f3bec</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.sciencedirect.com.ezproxy.liv.ac.uk/science/article/pii/S1474706511001100</style></url></related-urls></urls></record><record><database name="36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl">36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>268</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="0xrewz0z5t90fke005vp0tf6zwdexvtxdrt5">268</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Ostrander, R.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Clark, S. C.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Department of Biology, Central Connecticut State University, New Britain, CT 06050, United States</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Soil heavy metal concentrations and erosion damage in upland grasslands in the Pennines, England</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Water, Air, and Soil Pollution</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Water, Air, and Soil Pollution</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">81-94</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">59</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1-2</style></number><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1991</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">The relationship between grassland stability and soil concentrations of Pb, Zn and Cd and soil pH were determined at two abandoned heavy metal mine complexes in the Yorkshire Pennines, England. A process of vegetation change, in which degenerative stages are currently predominant occurs on the finer textured spoils, which are physically and chemically extremely heterogeneous. Physical disruption of closed grassland and floristic changes are involved in this process. There was little evidence that soil heavy metal concentrations, with the possible exception of Zn, were involved in initiating the process. Soil pH was unrelated to metal concentrations or to the disruption. Causes of initiation are not yet known, but these results indicate that more than one factor is involved. There was evidence that later stages of the disruptive process are powered by frost-heave and water erosion. The relationship between grassland stability and soil concentrations of Pb, Zn and Cd and soil pH were determined at two abandoned heavy metal mine complexes in the Yorkshire Pennines, England. A process of vegetation change, in which degenerative stages are currently predominant occurs on the finer textured spoils, which are physically and chemically extremely heterogeneous. Physical disruption of closed grassland and floristic changes are involved in this process. There was little evidence that soil heavy metal concentrations, with the possible exception of Zn, were involved in initiating the process. Soil pH was unrelated to metal concentrations or to the disruption. Causes of initiation are not yet known, but these results indicate that more than one factor is involved. There was evidence that later stages of the disruptive process are powered by frost-heave and water erosion.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 3&#xD;Export Date: 20 December 2011&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-0026223351&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=6c84f198109af8ac1110e21823c0bd90</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.springerlink.com.ezproxy.liv.ac.uk/content/q85723m2151g22l7/fulltext.pdf</style></url></related-urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Ostrander-1991-Soil heavy metal con-1734039808/Ostrander-1991-Soil heavy metal con.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl">36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>285</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="0xrewz0z5t90fke005vp0tf6zwdexvtxdrt5">285</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Price, L. E.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Fawcett, C. P.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Young, P. C.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Rowan, J. S.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Ctr. Res. Environ. Syst. Stat., Inst. of Environ. and Nat. Sciences, Lancaster University, Lancaster LA1 4YQ, United Kingdom&#xD;Department of Geography, University of Dundee, Dundee, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Modelling reservoir sedimentation and estimating historical deposition rates using a data-based mechanistic (DBM) approach</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Hydrological Sciences Journal</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Hydrological Sciences Journal</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">237-248</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">45</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2</style></number><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2000</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">The data-based mechanistic (DBM) modelling methodology is applied to the study of reservoir sedimentation. A lumped-parameter, discrete-time model has been developed which directly relates rainfall to suspended sediment load (SSL) at the reservoir outflow from the two years of measured data at Wyresdale Park Reservoir (Lancashire, UK). This nonlinear DBM model comprises two components: a rainfall to SSL model and a second model, relating the SSL at the reservoir inflow to the SSL at the reservoir spillway. Using a daily measured rainfall series as the input, this model is used to reconstruct daily deposition rates between 1911 and 1996. This synthetic sediment accretion sequence is compared with the variations in sand content within sediment cores collected from the reservoir floor. These profiles show good general agreement, reflecting the importance of low reoccurrence, high magnitude events. This preliminary study highlights the potential of this DBM approach, which could be readily applied to other sites. The data-based mechanistic (DBM) modelling methodology is applied to the study of reservoir sedimentation. A lumped-parameter, discrete-time model has been developed which directly relates rainfall to suspended sediment load (SSL) at the reservoir outflow from the two years of measured data at Wyresdale Park Reservoir (Lancashire, UK). This nonlinear DBM model comprises two components: a rainfall to SSL model and a second model, relating the SSL at the reservoir inflow to the SSL at the reservoir spillway. Using a daily measured rainfall series as the input, this model is used to reconstruct daily deposition rates between 1911 and 1996. This synthetic sediment accretion sequence is compared with the variations in sand content within sediment cores collected from the reservoir floor. These profiles show good general agreement, reflecting the importance of low recoccurrence, high magnitude events. This preliminary study highlights the potential of this DBM approach, which could be readily applied to other sites.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 3&#xD;Export Date: 20 December 2011&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-0034071134&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=06abf00c00b23ac32860a130f23f6d80</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.tandfonline.com.ezproxy.liv.ac.uk/doi/pdf/10.1080/02626660009492322</style></url></related-urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Price-2000-Modelling reservoir-3630146560/Price-2000-Modelling reservoir.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl">36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>286</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="0xrewz0z5t90fke005vp0tf6zwdexvtxdrt5">286</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Price, L. E.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Goodwill, P.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Young, P. C.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Rowan, J. S.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Lancaster University (CRES), Lancaster LA1 4YQ, United Kingdom&#xD;Environment Agency, Southern Region, HQ, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">A data-based mechanistic modelling (DBM) approach to understanding dynamic sediment transmission through Wyresdale Park Reservoir, Lancashire, UK</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Hydrological Processes</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Hydrological Processes</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">63-78</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">14</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1</style></number><keywords><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Continuous time</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Data-based mechanistic model</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Sediment dynamics</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Time-series analysis</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Transfer function model</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Trap efficiency</style></keyword></keywords><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2000</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">This paper outlines the application of a new data-based mechanistic (DBM) modeling methodology to the characterization of the sediment transmission dynamics in a small upland reservoir, Wyresdale Park, Lancashire. The DBM modelling strategy exploits advanced statistical procedures to infer the dynamic model structure and its associated parameters directly from the instrumental data, producing a parametrically efficient, continuous time, transfer function model which relates suspended sediment load at the reservoir inflow to the outflow at the event scale. The associated differential equation model parameters have physical attributes which can be interpreted in terms of sediment transmission processes and associated reservoir trap efficiency. Sedigraph analysis suggests that wind-induced resuspension episodically supplies an additional load to the reservoir outlet. The stochastic nature of the DBM model makes it deal for evaluating the effects of uncertainty through Monte Carlo simulations (MCS) for discharge and sediment transmission. Copyright (C) 2000 John Wiley and Sons, Ltd. This paper outlines the application of a new data-based mechanistic (DBM) modelling methodology to the characterization of the sediment transmission dynamics in a small upland reservoir, Wyresdale Park, Lancashire. The DBM modelling strategy exploits advanced statistical procedures to infer the dynamic model structure and its associated parameters directly from the instrumented data, producing a parametrically efficient, continuous time, transfer function model which relates suspended sediment load at the reservoir inflow to the outflow at the event scale. The associated differential equation model parameters have physical attributes which can be interpreted in terms of sediment transmission processes and associated reservoir trap efficiency. Sedigraph analysis suggests that wind-induced resuspension episodically supplies an additional load to the reservoir outlet. The stochastic nature of the DBM model makes it ideal for evaluating the effects of uncertainty through Monte Carlo simulations (MCS) for discharge and sediment transmission.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 7&#xD;Export Date: 20 December 2011&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-0034017227&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=83329939a2a0a8b6d8396d2cbbed8850</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/store/10.1002/(SICI)1099-1085(200001)14:1&lt;63::AID-HYP910&gt;3.0.CO;2-H/asset/910_ftp.pdf?v=1&amp;t=h03o2xve&amp;s=0d992d44492c75793f3f518e062aaf428c5aed4a</style></url></related-urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Price-2000-A data-based mechani-1331440640/Price-2000-A data-based mechani.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl">36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>288</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="0xrewz0z5t90fke005vp0tf6zwdexvtxdrt5">288</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Proctor, M. C. F.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Maltby, E.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Department of Biological Sciences, University of Exeter, Hatherly Laboratories, Prince of Wales Road, Exeter EX4 4PS, United Kingdom&#xD;Roy. Holloway Inst. of Environ. Res., Department of Geography, University of London, Huntersdale, Callow Hill, Virginia Water, Surrey GU25 4LN, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Relations between acid atmospheric deposition and the surface pH of some ombrotrophic bogs in Britain</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Journal of Ecology</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Journal of Ecology</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">329-340</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">86</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2</style></number><keywords><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Acid rain</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Air pollution</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Dry deposition</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Non-marine sulphate</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Sulphur content of peat</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Water chemistry</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Wet deposition</style></keyword></keywords><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1998</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1 Analyses are presented of major ion concentrations in surface water samples, and exchangeable cations in peats, collected in November-December 1992 from 16 ombrotrophic bogs in England and Wales and one in Scotland, spanning most of the range from the lowest (Dartmoor, west Wales, west Highlands) to the highest (south Pennines, north Yorkshire) of the mean 1986-88 rainwater concentrations of hydrogen ions and non-marine sulphate (NMS). 2 There was a strong positive correlation (r = +0.89) between surface water pH and mean rainwater pH, and a less close correlation (r = +0.71) between surface water pH and total hydrogen ion deposition. 3 The correlation between surface water pH and mean concentration of rainwater NMS (which may be taken as a surrogate measure of acid deposition) was r = -0.85, and that between surface water pH and total deposition of NMS was r = -0.65. 4 The intercept of the regression of surface water pH on NMS is at pH 4.40 (95% confidence limits 4.22-4.58), suggesting this as the winter pH of an ombrotrophic bog surface in the absence of acid atmospheric pollution. 5 Total sulphur content of intact surface peats from 11 sites correlated well (r = +0.90) with mean rainwater total sulphate concentration. 6 The H+ ion concentration in wet deposition, plus the net H+ input resulting from metabolism of deposited NO3 and NH4+, is insufficient to account for the difference between the inferred pH of an unpolluted bog surface and pH values (up to 0.8 pH units lower) measured in the field in polluted sites. Analogy with deposition of NMS suggests that this discrepancy is accounted for quantitatively by seeder-feeder enhancement, cloudwater deposition, and dry deposition of acidity. 7 Ombrotrophic bog surface waters are buffered by the cation-exchange properties of the peat. They are likely to be less sensitive to moderate acid deposition than weakly bicarbonate-buffered near-neutral peats, soils and fresh waters.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 24&#xD;Export Date: 20 December 2011&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-0031862536&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=2dc034f0adfb9d04e2b3c875d96e52cd</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.jstor.org.ezproxy.liv.ac.uk/stable/pdfplus/2648556.pdf?acceptTC=true</style></url></related-urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Proctor-1998-Relations between ac-2958849792/Proctor-1998-Relations between ac.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl">36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>290</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="0xrewz0z5t90fke005vp0tf6zwdexvtxdrt5">290</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Rainey, M. P.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Tyler, A. N.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Gilvear, D. J.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Bryant, R. G.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">McDonald, P.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Department of Environmental Science, University of Stirling, Stirling, FK9 4LA, United Kingdom&#xD;Department of Geography, University of Sheffield, Sheffield S10 2TN, United Kingdom&#xD;Westlakes Scientific Consulting Ltd., Westlakes Sci. and Technology Park, Moor Row, Cumbria CA24 3LN, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Mapping intertidal estuarine sediment grain size distributions through airborne remote sensing</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Remote Sensing of Environment</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Remote Sensing of Environment</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">480-490</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">86</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">4</style></number><keywords><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Airborne remote sensing</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Estuaries</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Linear mixture modelling</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Sediments</style></keyword></keywords><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2003</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">The intertidal environments of estuaries represent critical exchange environments of sediment and sediment bound contaminants. Ecological and sedimentological related investigations of these environments require monitoring methods that provide rapid spatially representative data on sediment grain size distribution. Remote sensing has the potential to provide synoptic information of intertidal environments. Previous in situ and laboratory-based reflectance investigations have demonstrated that for effective quantification of sediment grain size distributions, remote sensing platforms must include measurements within the short-wave infrared (SWIR). In addition, the timing of image acquisition, in relation to tidal cycles and sediment moisture content, is critical in optimising the spectral differences between the coarser sand and finer &apos;mud&apos; fraction of sediments. Daedalus 1268 Airborne Thematic Mapper (ATM) has been identified as an appropriate platform and sensor for providing accurate synoptic maps of estuarine sediment distributions. This paper presents the results from the application of ATM 1.75 m resolution data to the mapping of surface sediment grain-size distributions across intertidal areas of Ribble Estuary, Lancashire, UK. ATM imagery was acquired after the intertidal area was exposed to strong summer drying conditions. Pre-processing and linear unmixing of the imagery collected of the intertidal zone following a period of drying allowed accurate sub-pixel determinations (1.75 m resolution) of sediment clay (r2=0.79) but less accurate for sand (r2=0.60). The results also demonstrate deterioration in the image calibration with increasing sediment moisture content and microphytobenthos cover. However, recombining the subpixel end member abundances through multivariate regression analysis improved the image calibration significantly for both sediment clay and sand content (r2&amp;gt;0.8) for imagery collected in both dryer and wetter conditions. These results demonstrate that ATM data, or similar, can be used to gain quantitative information on intertidal sediment distributions and such data has application to a wide variety of estuarine research. © 2003 Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 50&#xD;Export Date: 20 December 2011&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-0141680397&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=187d70ff4549fd0e9014ce72b908cd84</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.sciencedirect.com.ezproxy.liv.ac.uk/science/article/pii/S0034425703001263</style></url></related-urls></urls></record><record><database name="36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl">36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>292</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="0xrewz0z5t90fke005vp0tf6zwdexvtxdrt5">292</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Ratto, M.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Young, P. C.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Romanowicz, R.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Pappenberge, F.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Saltelli, A.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Pagano, A.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Institute for the Protection and Security of the Citizens, Joint Research Center European Community, Ispra, Italy&#xD;Centre for Research on Environmental Systems and Statistic, Lancaster University, Lancaster, United Kingdom&#xD;Centre for Resource and Environmental Studies, Australian National University, Canberra, Australia</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Uncertainty, sensitivity analysis and the role of data based mechanistic modeling in hydrology</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Hydrology and Earth System Sciences Discussions</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Hydrology and Earth System Sciences Discussions</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">3099-3146</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">3</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">5</style></number><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2006</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">In this paper, we discuss the problem of calibration and uncertainty estimation for hydrologic systems from two points of view: a bottom-up, reductionist approach; and a top-down, data-based mechanistic (DBM) approach. The two approaches are applied to the modelling of the River Hodder catchment in North-West England. The bottom-up approach is developed using the TOPMODEL, whose structure is evaluated by global sensitivity analysis (GSA) in order to specify the most sensitive and important parameters; and the subsequent exercises in calibration and validation are carried out in the light of this sensitivity analysis. GSA helps to improve the calibration of hydrological models, making their properties more transparent and highlighting mis-specification problems. The DBM model provides a quick and efficient analysis of the rainfall-flow data, revealing important characteristics of the catchment-scale response, such as the nature of the effective rainfall nonlinearity and the partitioning of the effective rainfall into different flow pathways. TOPMODEL calibration takes more time and it explains the flow data a little less well than the DBM model. The main differences in the modelling results are in the nature of the models and the flow decomposition they suggest. The &quot;quick&quot; (63%) and &quot;slow&quot; (37%) components of the decomposed flow identified in the DBM model show a clear partitioning of the flow, with the quick component apparently accounting for the effects of surface and near surface processes; and the slow component arising from the displacement of groundwater into the river channel (base flow). On the other hand, the two output flow components in TOPMODEL have a different physical interpretation, with a single flow component (95%) accounting for both slow (subsurface) and fast (surface) dynamics, while the other, very small component (5%) is interpreted as an instantaneous surface runoff generated by rainfall falling on areas of saturated soil. The results of the exercise show that the two modelling methodologies have good synergy; combining well to produce a complete modelling approach that has the kinds of checks-and-balances required in practical data-based modelling of rainfall-flow systems. Such a combined approach also produces models that are suitable for different kinds of application. As such, the DBM model can provides an immediate vehicle for flow and flood forecasting; while TOPMODEL, suitably calibrated (and perhaps modified) in the light of the DBM and GSA results, immediately provides a simulation model with a variety of potential applications, in areas such as catchment management and planning.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Export Date: 20 December 2011&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-34250029796&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=06f2b142a2f95999495843a75bc02034</style></url></related-urls></urls></record><record><database name="36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl">36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>298</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="0xrewz0z5t90fke005vp0tf6zwdexvtxdrt5">298</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Rose, J.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Moorlock, B. S. P.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Hamblin, R. J. O.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Department of Geography, Royal Holloway, University of London, Egham, Surrey TW20 0EX, United Kingdom&#xD;British Geological Survey, Keyworth, Nottingham NG12 5GG, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Pre-Anglian fluvial and coastal deposits in Eastern England: Lithostratigraphy and palaeoenvironments</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Quaternary International</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Quaternary International</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">5-22</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">79</style></volume><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2001</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Clast lithology and derived microflora are used to provide a basis for correlating pre-Anglian fluvial and coastal deposits in eastern England and to provide a lithostratigraphic framework for these Early and early Middle Pleistocene sediments. Three fluvial systems are recognised. (i) The Thames, which drained an area from Wales through midland England to the Thames basin and southern East Anglia. The catchment was truncated over the period concerned and the western headwaters diverted to other river systems. (ii) The Bytham river which drained midland England and the southern Pennines and reached the southern North Sea delta in the region of north central East Anglia. This river extended its catchment over the period concerned. (iii) The Ancaster river which drained the southern Pennines and received sediment from northeast England. Each of these catchments contributed sediment to the southern North Sea delta/estuary and contributed to the lithologies of the Red, Norwich, and Wroxham Crag formations. The lithostratigraphic subdivisions are based on the fact that: (i) the Pliocene and Early Pleistocene rivers and the equivalent Red and Norwich Crags are characterised by far-travelled microflora which was transported in suspension and a locally derived clast assemblage transported as bedload, and (ii) the later Early and early Middle Pleistocene rivers and the equivalent Wroxham Crag are characterised by a far-travelled microflora and a far-travelled clast assemblage. Variations in the amount and composition of far-travelled materials is determined by the relative importance of the three river systems. This provides a basis for identifying different formations of the Thames river sediments (older Sudbury Formation and younger Colchester Formation) and different members of the Wroxham Formation (Dobb&apos;s Plantation Member: local material with minor components of Thames and Ancaster river sediments; How Hill Member: local material with major components of Thames and Ancaster river sediments; Mundesley Member with major components of Bytham river sediments). These lithostratigraphic units are related to established North European biostratigraphy and Oxygen Isotope stratigraphy. The factors forcing the changes in river energetics are explained in terms of the relative importance of geomorphic processes operating within the river catchments determined by the patterns of Milankovitch orbital forcing. © 2001 Elsevier Science Ltd and INQUA. All rights reserved.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 50&#xD;Export Date: 20 December 2011&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-0035002839&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=6ef69d4d16fb608ae74d6649384e0477</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.sciencedirect.com.ezproxy.liv.ac.uk/science/article/pii/S1040618200001191</style></url></related-urls></urls></record><record><database name="36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl">36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>299</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="0xrewz0z5t90fke005vp0tf6zwdexvtxdrt5">299</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Rothwell, J. J.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Dise, N. B.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Taylor, K. G.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Allott, T. E. H.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Scholefield, P.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Davies, H.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Neal, C.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Department of Environmental and Geographical Sciences, Manchester Metropolitan University, Manchester, M1 5GD, United Kingdom&#xD;Geography, School of Environment and Development, The University of Manchester, Manchester, M13 9PL, United Kingdom&#xD;Centre for Ecology and Hydrology, Lancaster Environment Centre, Library Avenue, Bailrigg, Lancaster, LA1 4AP, United Kingdom&#xD;Centre for Ecology and Hydrology, Wallingford, Oxfordshire OX10 8BB, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">A spatial and seasonal assessment of river water chemistry across North West England</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Science of the Total Environment</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Science of the Total Environment</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">841-855</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">408</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">4</style></number><keywords><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Catchment</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Diffuse source</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">GIS</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Metals</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Nitrate</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Nutrients</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Orthophosphate</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Point source</style></keyword></keywords><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2010</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">This paper presents information on the spatial and seasonal patterns of river water chemistry at approximately 800 sites in North West England based on data from the Environment Agency regional monitoring programme. Within a GIS framework, the linkages between average water chemistry (pH, sulphate, base cations, nutrients and metals) catchment characteristics (topography, land cover, soil hydrology, base flow index and geology), rainfall, deposition chemistry and geo-spatial information on discharge consents (point sources) are examined. Water quality maps reveal that there is a clear distinction between the uplands and lowlands. Upland waters are acidic and have low concentrations of base cations, explained by background geological sources and land cover. Localised high concentrations of metals occur in areas of the Cumbrian Fells which are subjected to mining effluent inputs. Nutrient concentrations are low in the uplands with the exception sites receiving effluent inputs from rural point sources. In the lowlands, both past and present human activities have a major impact on river water chemistry, especially in the urban and industrial heartlands of Greater Manchester, south Lancashire and Merseyside. Over 40% of the sites have average orthophosphate concentrations &amp;gt; 0.1 mg-P l- 1. Results suggest that the dominant control on orthophosphate concentrations is point source contributions from sewage effluent inputs. Diffuse agricultural sources are also important, although this influence is masked by the impact of point sources. Average nitrate concentrations are linked to the coverage of arable land, although sewage effluent inputs have a significant effect on nitrate concentrations. Metal concentrations in the lowlands are linked to diffuse and point sources. The study demonstrates that point sources, as well as diffuse sources, need to be considered when targeting measures for the effective reduction in river nutrient concentrations. This issue is clearly important with regards to the European Union Water Framework Directive, eutrophication and river water quality. © 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 7&#xD;Export Date: 20 December 2011&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-71849115055&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=0a6084accaedc5be8b975f4022e473e8</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.sciencedirect.com.ezproxy.liv.ac.uk/science/article/pii/S0048969709010225</style></url></related-urls></urls></record><record><database name="36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl">36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>300</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="0xrewz0z5t90fke005vp0tf6zwdexvtxdrt5">300</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Rothwell, J. J.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Evans, M. G.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Allott, T. E. H.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Upland Environments Research Unit, School of Environment and Development, The University of Manchester, Oxford Road, Manchester M13 9PL, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Sediment-water interactions in an eroded and heavy metal contaminated peatland catchment, Southern Pennines, UK</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Water, Air, and Soil Pollution: Focus</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Water, Air, and Soil Pollution: Focus</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">669-676</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">6</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">5-6</style></number><keywords><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Acidic water</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Desorption</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">In-stream processing</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Lead</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Peat erosion</style></keyword></keywords><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2006</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Atmospherically deposited lead in the upper layer of the heavily eroded peatlands of the Peak District, southern Pennines, UK, reaches concentrations in excess of 1,000 mg kg-1. Erosion of the upper peat layer in this region is releasing lead, associated with eroded peat particles, into the fluvial system. Understanding the process mechanisms that control dissolved lead concentrations in contaminated peatland streams is vital for understanding lead cycling and transport in peatland streams. Many headwater streams of the southern Pennines recharge drinking water reservoirs. Measurements in the Upper North Grain (UNG) study catchment show that mean sediment-associated and dissolved lead concentrations are 102±39.4 mg kg-1 and 5.73±2.16 μg l-1, respectively. Experimental evidence demonstrates that lead can desorb from suspended sediments, composed of contaminated peat, into stream waters. In-stream processing could therefore account for the elevated dissolved lead concentrations in the fluvial system of UNG. © Springer Science+Business Media B.V. 2006.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 4&#xD;Export Date: 20 December 2011&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-33845928491&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=d3313fabd143503742bbf040b4078e86</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.springerlink.com.ezproxy.liv.ac.uk/content/fn3u71210p8477n3/fulltext.pdf</style></url></related-urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Rothwell-2006-Sediment-water inter-1633480960/Rothwell-2006-Sediment-water inter.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl">36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>301</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="0xrewz0z5t90fke005vp0tf6zwdexvtxdrt5">301</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Rothwell, J. J.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Evans, M. G.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Allott, T. E. H.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Upland Environments Research Unit, School of Environment and Development, The University of Manchester, Manchester, M13 9PL, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Lead contamination of fluvial sediments in an eroding blanket peat catchment</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Applied Geochemistry</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Applied Geochemistry</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">446-459</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">22</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2</style></number><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2007</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Over the last few years there has been growing concern over the mobilisation of anthropogenically derived, atmospherically deposited Pb from upland blanket peat soils to receiving surface waters. The near-surface layer of blanket peat soils of the Peak District, southern Pennines, UK, is severely contaminated with high concentrations of Pb. Erosion of peat soils in this upland area may be releasing large quantities of previously deposited Pb into the fluvial system. Samples of fluvial sediments (suspended, floodplain, streamside fan, trash-line and channel bed) were collected from a severely eroding blanket peat catchment in the Peak District in order to investigate Pb contamination of fluvial sediments, to determine the mechanism for fluvial Pb transport and to determine if erosion of contaminated peat soils in the catchment is releasing Pb into the fluvial system. Concentrations of Pb associated with fluvial sediments are considerably higher than those in the catchment geology, but not as high as those in peat soils in the catchment. Intra- and inter-storm variability in the Pb content of suspended sediments can be explained by differences in organic matter content of these sediments and differences in erosion processes operating within the catchment. High Pb concentrations are associated with suspended sediments that have a high organic matter content. The results of this study suggest that organic matter is the principle vector for sediment-associated Pb in the fluvial system. Erosion of contaminated peat soils in the Peak District is releasing Pb into the fluvial system. The extent to which this is a problem in other peatland environments is an area requiring further research. © 2007 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 11&#xD;Export Date: 20 December 2011&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-33846634654&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=0422eccdf8dfb8a4cfd0c50e261eca0c</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.sciencedirect.com.ezproxy.liv.ac.uk/science/article/pii/S0883292706003155</style></url></related-urls></urls></record><record><database name="36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl">36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>302</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="0xrewz0z5t90fke005vp0tf6zwdexvtxdrt5">302</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Rothwell, J. J.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Evans, M. G.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Daniels, S. M.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Allott, T. E. H.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Upland Environments Research Unit, School of Environment and Development, The University of Manchester, Manchester, M13 9PL, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Peat soils as a source of lead contamination to upland fluvial systems</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Environmental Pollution</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Environmental Pollution</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">582-589</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">153</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">3</style></number><keywords><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Climate change</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Lead</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Particulates</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Peat erosion</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">pH</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Southern Pennines</style></keyword></keywords><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2008</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Upland peat soils are generally regarded as effective sinks of atmospherically deposited lead. However, the physical process of erosion has the potential to transform peat soils from sinks to sources of lead contamination. Lead input and fluvial lead outputs (dissolved + particulate) were estimated for a contaminated and severely eroding peatland catchment in the southern Pennines, UK. Lead input to the catchment is 30.0 ± 6.0 g ha-1 a-1 and the output from the catchment is 317 ± 22.4 g ha-1 a-1. Suspended particulate matter accounts for 85% of lead export. Contaminated peat soils of the catchment are a significant source of lead to the fluvial system. This study has demonstrated strong coupling between the physical process of erosion and the mobilization of lead into the fluvial system. The process of peat erosion should therefore be considered when estimating lead outputs from peatland catchments, especially in the context of climate change. © 2007 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 9&#xD;Export Date: 20 December 2011&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-43549093987&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=a3d37d8e49c54b82927888fbe1791546</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.sciencedirect.com.ezproxy.liv.ac.uk/science/article/pii/S0269749107004642</style></url></related-urls></urls></record><record><database name="36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl">36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>303</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="0xrewz0z5t90fke005vp0tf6zwdexvtxdrt5">303</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Rothwell, J. J.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Evans, M. G.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Liddaman, L. C.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Allott, T. E. H.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Upland Environments Research Unit, School of Environment and Development, The University of Manchester, Manchester, M13 9PL, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">The role of wildfire and gully erosion in particulate Pb export from contaminated peatland catchments in the southern Pennines, U.K</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Geomorphology</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Geomorphology</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">276-284</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">88</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">3-4</style></number><keywords><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Climate change</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Pb inventory</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Peak District</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Peat erosion</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Suspended sediment</style></keyword></keywords><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2007</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">The near-surface layer of peatlands of the Peak District, southern Pennines, UK, is severely contaminated with atmospherically deposited Pb. Contemporary catchment soil Pb inventories at Upper North Grain and Torside Clough reveal that ∼ 23% and ∼ 54%, respectively, of the potential store of Pb in each catchment has been lost through erosion of the contaminated near-surface peat layer. Soil Pb inventories and the Pb content of suspended sediments reveal that, in both catchments, the main mechanism for contemporary particulate Pb export is gully erosion. Historical sheet erosion on bare peat flats at Torside Clough has released significant quantities of Pb into the fluvial system, triggered by the exposure of the near-surface peat during an accidental wildfire in 1970. Up to 32% of the total Pb export from the catchment may have been released during a discrete erosion event soon after the wildfire. Accidental wildfires and the subsequent release of highly contaminated peat into the southern Pennine fluvial system may increase under predicted climate change scenarios. © 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 3&#xD;Export Date: 20 December 2011&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-34249892464&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=5efa36e25b149bbfe6979d977c66f827</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.sciencedirect.com.ezproxy.liv.ac.uk/science/article/pii/S0169555X06005277</style></url></related-urls></urls></record><record><database name="36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl">36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>304</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="0xrewz0z5t90fke005vp0tf6zwdexvtxdrt5">304</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Rothwell, J. J.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Robinson, S. G.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Evans, M. G.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Yang, J.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Allott, T. E. H.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Upland Environments Research Unit, School of Environment and Development, The University of Manchester, Oxford Road, Manchester M13 9PL, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Heavy metal release by peat erosion in the Peak District, southern Pennines, UK</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Hydrological Processes</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Hydrological Processes</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2973-2989</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">19</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">15</style></number><keywords><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Atmospheric pollution</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Environmental magnetism</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Fingerprinting</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Heavy metals</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Peat erosion</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Southern Pennines</style></keyword></keywords><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2005</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Upper North Grain (UNG) is a heavily eroding blanket peat catchment in the Peak District, southern Pennines, UK. Concentrations of lead in the near-surface peat layer at UNG are in excess of 1000 mg kg-1. For peatland environments, these lead concentrations are some of the highest globally. High concentrations of industrially derived, atmospherically transported magnetic spherules are also stored in the near-surface peat layer. Samples of suspended sediment taken during a storm event that occurred on 1 November 2002 at UNG, and of the potential catchment sources for suspended sediments, were analysed for lead content and the environmental magnetic properties of anhysteretic remanent magnetization (ARM) and saturation isothermal remanent magnetization (SIRM). At the beginning of the storm event, there is a peak in both suspended sediment and associated lead concentration. SIRM/ ARM values for suspended sediment samples throughout the storm reveal that the initial &apos;lead flush&apos; is associated with a specific sediment source, namely that of organic sediment eroded from the upper peat layer. Using the magnetic &apos;fingerprinting&apos; approach to discrimination of sediment sources, this study reveals that erosion of the upper peat layer at UNG is releasing high concentrations of industrially derived lead (and, by inference, other toxic heavy metals associated with industrial particulates) into the fluvial systems of the southern Pennines. Climate-change scenarios for the UK, involving higher summer temperatures and stormier winters, may result in an increased flux both of sediment-associated and dissolved heavy metals from eroding peatland catchments in the southern Pennines, adversely affecting the quality of sediment and water entering reservoirs of the region. Copyright © 2005 John Wiley &amp;amp; Sons, Ltd.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 22&#xD;Export Date: 20 December 2011&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-27144459032&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=6a9198decc84780ed6b2e73cf9049fa0</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/store/10.1002/hyp.5811/asset/5811_ftp.pdf?v=1&amp;t=h03o4vhh&amp;s=74acdc3bdd8d0b18d7ccb0f7c5bfe64c2e9031af</style></url></related-urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Rothwell-2005-Heavy metal release-1012764160/Rothwell-2005-Heavy metal release.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl">36_Southern_Pennines_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>305</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="0xrewz0z5t90fke005vp0tf6zwdexvtxdrt5">305</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Rowan, J. S.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Goodwill, P.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Greco, M.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Environmental Science Division, IEBS, Lancaster University, Lancaster, LA1 4YQ, United Kingdom&#xD;Department of Environmental Physics and Engineering, Basilicata University, Via della Tecnica, 3, 85100 Potenza, Italy</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Temporal variability in catchment sediment yield determined from repeated bathymetric surveys: Abbeystead Reservoir, U.K</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Physics and Chemistry of the Earth</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Physics and Chemistry of the Earth</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">199-206</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">20</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2</style></number><keywords><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">bathymetric survey</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Reservoir</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">sediment yield</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">sedimentation</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">trap efficiency</style></keyword></keywords><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1995</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Situated an upland area of Northwest England, Abbeystead Reservoir has experienced severe sedimentation problems. Presently, only 6 % of the original capacity and 30 % of the original surface area remains and the deposition process is considered to have reached a quasi-equilibrium condition. Temporal variations in storage capacity losses were determined from morphometric analysis of 7 bathymetric surveys (1851-1991) and indirectly using a time-dependent relationship between storage capacity and water surface area. The sediment yield between successive surveys was obtained by gravimetric conversion of storage capacity losses, corrected for untrapped sediment lost directly over the spillway. The analysis highlights uncertainties in the use of empirical trap efficiency relationships, particularly in very dynamic systems. The long-term (140 years) sediment yield of the Upper Wyre catchment was estimated as 192 t km-2 yr-1, containing a mean organic matter content of 18.5 %. Decadal-scale variations in sediment yield ranged from 78 to 390 t km-2 yr-1. Two periods with elevated yields were distinguished and linked to phases of construction and land drainage within the catchment. © 1995.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 10&#xD;Export Date: 20 December 2011&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-0029544245&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=37aafa411e56d81b23d1f60ca3124158</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.sciencedirect.com.ezproxy.liv.ac.uk/science/article/pii/0079194695000224</style></url></related-urls></urls></record></records></xml>