<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><xml><records><record><database name="97_Arden_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\97_Arden_Shortlist.enl">97_Arden_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>3</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="zvxw9f0wq0tvteeeev5xewt4parw95ezef9e">3</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Rivett, Michael O.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Ellis, Paul A.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Mackay, Rae</style></author></authors></contributors><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Urban groundwater baseflow influence upon inorganic river-water quality: The River Tame headwaters catchment in the City of Birmingham, UK</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Journal of Hydrology</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Journal of Hydrology</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">206-222</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">400</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1-2</style></number><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2011</style></year><pub-dates><date><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Mar 30</style></date></pub-dates></dates><isbn><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">0022-1694</style></isbn><accession-num><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">WOS:000289325100018</style></accession-num><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Understanding the linkage between urban land, groundwater, baseflow and river contamination at the city scale is lacking. This study evaluates the influence of inorganic (major/minor ions and metals) groundwater contamination in the Triassic sandstone-Quaternary deposits aquifer system underlying the City of Birmingham, UK upon the baseflow and water quality of the river Tame. Baseflow water-quality data have been collected from a riverbed piezometer network installed in the 7.4 km reach crossing the effluent unconfined sandstone aquifer and compared to river and aquifer water-quality data. Overall, the inorganic chemical quality of the baseflow was not as poor as potentially surmised from the urbanisation present. Baseflow impact upon river-water quality was also low. These conclusions were underpinned by evidences of: limited river-water quality changes along the reach; some river concentrations being diluted by better quality baseflow; only occasional breaching of water-quality criteria; limited impact upon river-reach quality local to elevated baseflow dicharges; natural attenuation occurrence within the riverbed; and, modest, albeit somewhat uncertain, baseflow mass fluxes. Baseflow fluxes to the reach were in the ranges 100-3500 t/yr for major ions, 1-50 t/yr for minor ions and 1-500 kg/yr for toxic metals with zinc and nickel most prominent. The sporadic occurrence of elevated baseflow concentrations was ascribed to discrete groundwater plume discharges. More detailed sub-reach studies would be required to fully resolve discrete plume baseflow contributions and improve mass flux estimates. Not uncommonly, the urban river studied was already contaminated and hence persistent baseflow fluxes may assume more importance if the river became cleaner through other control measures. Future research should hence consider the emergent significance of urban baseflows. There are needs to: conduct similar studies to investigate if city-scale baseflow impacts are comparable elsewhere; research the importance of spatially and temporally dynamic attenuation in the riverbed; and, develop improved baseflow mass flux estimation methods. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Times Cited: 0</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">&lt;Go to ISI&gt;://WOS:000289325100018</style></url></related-urls></urls><electronic-resource-num><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">10.1016/j.jhydrol.2011.01.036</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="97_Arden_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\97_Arden_Shortlist.enl">97_Arden_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>9</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="zvxw9f0wq0tvteeeev5xewt4parw95ezef9e">9</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Shepherd, K. A.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Ellis, P. A.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Rivett, M. O.</style></author></authors></contributors><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Integrated understanding of urban land, groundwater, baseflow and surface-water quality - The City of Birmingham, UK</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Science of the Total Environment</style></secondary-title></titles><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">180-195</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">360</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1-3</style></number><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2006</style></year><pub-dates><date><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">May 1</style></date></pub-dates></dates><isbn><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">0048-9697</style></isbn><accession-num><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">WOS:000237870500014</style></accession-num><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Integrated understanding of urban land, groundwater (shallow and deep), baseflow and surface-water quality relationships is required for effective urban water-quality management. Chemical quality data from across these media have been collected for the Birmingham (UK) aquifer-River Tame conurbation to assess chemical transport from contaminated land to groundwater to baseflow to surface water. Although metals concentrations were high in soils, low leachability and attenuation caused concentrations in groundwaters and baseflow discharging to surface water to be generally low with only sporadic elevated concentrations attributed to localised point sources. Hydrocarbon VOCs (volatile organic compounds) were similarly absent or at low concentration attributable to their ready natural attenuation. Chlorinated VOCs, however, were widely encountered in groundwater, discharging as baseflow to surface water and impacting surface-water quality. This is attributed to their DNAPL (dense nonaqueous-phase liquid) properties and relative recalcitrance although there was some evidence of biodegradation, albeit insufficient to protect surface water and groundwater abstraction receptors. Some inorganic trends were evident across the various media; nitrate was the most significant quality concern. Generic conclusions are drawn on urban water-quality management and the need for risk-based management strategies to optimise use of urban, sporadically contaminated groundwater in conjunction with surface water highlighted. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Times Cited: 17</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">&lt;Go to ISI&gt;://WOS:000237870500014</style></url></related-urls></urls><electronic-resource-num><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">10.1016/j.scitotenv.2005.08.052</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="97_Arden_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\97_Arden_Shortlist.enl">97_Arden_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>8</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="zvxw9f0wq0tvteeeev5xewt4parw95ezef9e">8</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Thomas, A.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Tellam, J.</style></author></authors></contributors><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Modelling of recharge and pollutant fluxes to urban groundwaters</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Science of the Total Environment</style></secondary-title></titles><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">158-179</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">360</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1-3</style></number><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2006</style></year><pub-dates><date><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">May 1</style></date></pub-dates></dates><isbn><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">0048-9697</style></isbn><accession-num><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">WOS:000237870500013</style></accession-num><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Urban groundwater resources are of considerable importance to the long-term viability of many cities world-wide, yet prediction of the quantity and quality of recharge is only rarely attempted at anything other than a very basic level. This paper describes the development of UGIf, a simple model written within a GIS, designed to provide estimates of spatially distributed recharge and recharge water quality in unconfined but covered aquifers. The following processes (with their calculation method indicated) are included: runoff and interception (curve number method); evapotranspiration (Penman-Grindley); interflow (empirical index approach); volatilization (Henry&apos;s law); sorption (distribution coefficient); and degradation (first order decay). The input data required are: meteorological data, landuse/cover map with event mean concentration attributes, geological maps with hydraulic and geochemical attributes, and topographic and water table elevation data in grid form. Standard outputs include distributions of: surface runoff, infiltration, potential recharge, ground level slope, interflow, actual recharge, pollutant fluxes in surface runoff, travel times of each pollutant through the unsaturated zone, and the pollutant fluxes and concentrations at the water table. The process of validation has commenced with a study of the Triassic Sandstone aquifer underlying Birmingham, UK. UGIf predicts a similar average recharge rate for the aquifer as previous groundwater flow modelling studies, but with significantly more spatial detail: in particular the results indicate that recharge through paved areas may be more important than previously thought. The results also highlight the need for more knowledge/data on the following: runoff estimation; interflow (including the effects of lateral flow and channelling on flow times and therefore chemistry); evapotranspiration in paved areas; the nature of unsaturated zone flow below paved areas; and the role of the pipe network. Although considerably more verification is needed, UGIf shows promise for use: in providing input for regional groundwater solute transport models; in identifying gaps in knowledge and data; in determining which processes are the most important influences on urban groundwater quantity and quality; in evaluating existing recharge models; in planning, for example in investigation of the effects of landuse or climate change; and in assessing groundwater vulnerability. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Times Cited: 9</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">&lt;Go to ISI&gt;://WOS:000237870500013</style></url></related-urls></urls><electronic-resource-num><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">10.1016/j.scitotenv.2005.08.050</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="97_Arden_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\97_Arden_Shortlist.enl">97_Arden_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>84</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="zvxw9f0wq0tvteeeev5xewt4parw95ezef9e">84</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Thomas, G. N.</style></author></authors></contributors><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Late Middle Pleistocene pollen biostratigraphy in Britain: pitfalls and possibilities in the separation of interglacial sequences</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Quaternary Science Reviews</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Quaternary Science Reviews</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1621-1630</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">20</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">16-17</style></number><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2001</style></year><pub-dates><date><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Nov</style></date></pub-dates></dates><isbn><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">0277-3791</style></isbn><accession-num><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">WOS:000171907400005</style></accession-num><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Recent work on late Middle Pleistocene interglacials in Britain has shown that sites formerly attributed to the Hoxnian include representatives of two different interglacials, which have been correlated with Oxygen Isotope Stages 11 and 9. Palynology has long been used to characterize and correlate temperate sequences in Britain. However, the quality of the palynological record is considerably better in lacustrine sequences than in fluvial and estuarine sediments; the former have longer sequences and higher resolution, whereas more rapid deposition in fluvial and estuarine environments leads to sequences representing only fragments of interglacials. The latter type of site, however, is more likely to have multi-proxy evidence and to be readily fitted into a stratigraphical framework. The problems are reviewed in the light of new work in the West Midlands, where some of the most complete British late Middle Pleistocene lacustrine sequences are preserved, Lacustrine sites here have a strong affinity with &apos;Hoxnian&apos; sites of the &apos;type&apos; area in East Anglia. A critical question remains as to whether the two interglacials conflated under the term Hoxnian can be separately characterized in terms of their pollen assemblages. Details of lacustrine sequences in the North Birmingham area and East Anglia show remarkable similarities, perhaps suggesting that the same interglacial is recorded in all of them. As many of these sites are thought to be kettle holes or glacially overdeepened basins, the first interglacial following the Anglian glaciation is the most likely to be represented, suggesting that all the lacustrine &apos;Hoxnian&apos; sites might date from OIS 11. In areas not glaciated since the Anglian, interglacials after OIS I I are likely to be represented only by fragmentary, non-lacustrine sequences, difficult if not impossible to separate using palynology alone. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science Ltd. All rights reserved.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Times Cited: 27</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">&lt;Go to ISI&gt;://WOS:000171907400005</style></url></related-urls></urls><electronic-resource-num><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">10.1016/s0277-3791(01)00026-9</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="97_Arden_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\97_Arden_Shortlist.enl">97_Arden_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>123</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="zvxw9f0wq0tvteeeev5xewt4parw95ezef9e">123</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Walling, D. E.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Webb, B. W.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Russell, M. A.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Dept of Geography, Univ of Exeter, Exeter EX4 4RJ, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Sediment-associated nutrient transport in UK rivers</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Freshwater contamination. Proc. international symposium, Rabat, Morocco, 1997&#xD;IAHS-AISH Publication</style></secondary-title></titles><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">69-81</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">243</style></volume><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1997</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Monitoring programmes established to document river nutrient loads have commonly focused on quantifying total loads, without distinguishing between the dissolved and particulate components. There is now a growing recognition of the need to distinguish these two components which may exhibit contrasting behaviour and reflect different sources and controls. Few reliable data are currently available with which to assess the role of sediment-associated transport in nutrient transport by British rivers and this contribution reports the results of a study aimed at assessing this role for four contrasting river basins in Britain. The study rivers were selected to embrace a range of basin characteristics and include the River Severn, the Warwickshire Avon, the River Exe and its tributary the River Dart. Detailed monitoring of the N and P loads transported by these four rivers was undertaken during the period January to December 1995, and the dissolved and sediment-associated components of the total N and P flux were determined with a view to assessing the significance of the latter component. Significant differences existed between the four rivers in terms of both specific N and P yields and the relative contribution of the particulate component. These contrasts reflected variations in the magnitude of the specific suspended sediment yields and in the relative importance of point and non-point sources as well as other basin characteristics. In the case of phosphorus, sediment-associated transport accounted for between 26.3% and 75.4% of the annual total P load of the study rivers, whereas for N the sediment-associated contribution was much less and ranged between 3.3% and 8.0%. The magnitude of the sediment-associated contribution varied through the year in response to a number of controls, including the seasonal pattern of suspended sediment transport.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 13&#xD;Export Date: 7 November 2011&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-0031402524&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=58c8482ab7b47626993f98ae1fcd4650</style></url></related-urls></urls></record><record><database name="97_Arden_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\97_Arden_Shortlist.enl">97_Arden_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>36</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="zvxw9f0wq0tvteeeev5xewt4parw95ezef9e">36</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Webster, P.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">West, J. R.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Gurnell, A. M.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Petts, G. E.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Sadler, J. P.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Forster, C. F.</style></author></authors></contributors><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Development, flood risk and the urban environment experiences from the River Tame</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Journal of the Chartered Institution of Water and Environmental Management</style></secondary-title></titles><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">167-173</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">15</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">3</style></number><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2001</style></year><pub-dates><date><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Jul-Aug</style></date></pub-dates></dates><isbn><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">0951-7359</style></isbn><accession-num><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">WOS:000170790800003</style></accession-num><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Experience and knowledge of river-restoration schemes are generally available at the reach scale. However, there are problems with the application of this knowledge at the scale of large urbanised catchments which relate to understanding the system and predicting the impact of management strategies. This paper considers problems of developing a perceptive and efficient rehabilitation strategy for a large urbanised catchment, with specific reference to the River Tame in the West Midlands. Consideration is given to (a) rainfall-runoff relationships, (b) assessment of water quality and ecological status, and (c) predicting the impact of various management strategies.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Times Cited: 6&#xD;Rivers-and-Coastal-Group Winter Meeting of the Chartered Institution of Water and Environmental Managament&#xD;Jan 28, 2000&#xD;London zoo, england&#xD;Charter Inst Water &amp; Environm Managment</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">&lt;Go to ISI&gt;://WOS:000170790800003</style></url></related-urls></urls></record><record><database name="97_Arden_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\97_Arden_Shortlist.enl">97_Arden_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>26</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="zvxw9f0wq0tvteeeev5xewt4parw95ezef9e">26</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Whitehead, P. G.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Wade, A. J.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Butterfield, D.</style></author></authors></contributors><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Potential impacts of climate change on water quality and ecology in six UK rivers</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Hydrology Research</style></secondary-title></titles><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">113-122</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">40</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2-3</style></number><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2009</style></year><pub-dates><date><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">May</style></date></pub-dates></dates><isbn><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1998-9563</style></isbn><accession-num><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">WOS:000266439000003</style></accession-num><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">A modelling study has been undertaken to assess the likely impacts of climate change on water quality across the UK. A range of climate change scenarios have been used to generate future precipitation, evaporation and temperature time series at a range of catchments across the UK. These time series have then been used to drive the Integrated Catchment (INCA) suite of flow, water quality and ecological models to simulate flow, nitrate, ammonia, total and soluble reactive phosphorus, sediments, macrophytes and epiphytes in the Rivers Tamar, Lugg, Tame, Kennet, Tweed and Lambourn. A wide range of responses have been obtained with impacts varying depending on river character, catchment location, flow regime, type of scenario and the time into the future. Essentially upland reaches of river will respond differently to lowland reaches of river, and the responses will vary depending on the water quality parameter of interest.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Times Cited: 5</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">&lt;Go to ISI&gt;://WOS:000266439000003</style></url></related-urls></urls><electronic-resource-num><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">10.2166/nh.2009.078</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="97_Arden_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\97_Arden_Shortlist.enl">97_Arden_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>88</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="zvxw9f0wq0tvteeeev5xewt4parw95ezef9e">88</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Wilby, R. L.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Dalgleish, H. Y.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Foster, I. D. L.</style></author></authors></contributors><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">The impact of weather patterns on historic and contemporary catchment sediment yields</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Earth Surface Processes and Landforms</style></secondary-title></titles><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">353-363</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">22</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">4</style></number><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1997</style></year><pub-dates><date><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Apr</style></date></pub-dates></dates><isbn><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">0197-9337</style></isbn><accession-num><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">WOS:A1997WZ40900004</style></accession-num><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Lake sediment-based estimates of sediment yield have frequently been used to reconstruct changing patterns of sediment supply arising from environmental change. Such analyses have often emphasized the importance of anthropogenic factors and, in particular, changing land use of management practices over timescales beyond the scope of direct process monitoring. This paper examines several U.K. sediment yield chronologies within the context of mesoscale atmospheric circulation patterns. Changes in the frequency of the winter cyclonic Lamb weather type since 1861 were found to account for a significant proportion of the variation in sediment yields. The results also have implications for future sediment accumulation rates given the potential geomorphological consequences of global climate change. (C) 1997 by John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Times Cited: 30</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">&lt;Go to ISI&gt;://WOS:A1997WZ40900004</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/store/10.1002/(SICI)1096-9837(199704)22:4&lt;353::AID-ESP692&gt;3.0.CO;2-G/asset/692_ftp.pdf?v=1&amp;t=guplvpt2&amp;s=cb2d1370dcabf8ae05e86a30d97e20a2695794b2</style></url></related-urls></urls><electronic-resource-num><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">10.1002/(sici)1096-9837(199704)22:4&lt;353::aid-esp692&gt;3.0.co;2-g</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="97_Arden_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\97_Arden_Shortlist.enl">97_Arden_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>91</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="zvxw9f0wq0tvteeeev5xewt4parw95ezef9e">91</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Woods, D. R.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Green, M. B.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Parish, R. C.</style></author></authors></contributors><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">LEA MARSTON PURIFICATION LAKE - OPERATIONAL AND RIVER-QUALITY ASPECTS</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Water Pollution Control</style></secondary-title></titles><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">226-242</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">83</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2</style></number><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1984</style></year><pub-dates><date><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1984</style></date></pub-dates></dates><isbn><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">0043-129X</style></isbn><accession-num><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">WOS:A1984SX27900009</style></accession-num><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Times Cited: 2</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">&lt;Go to ISI&gt;://WOS:A1984SX27900009</style></url></related-urls></urls></record></records></xml>