<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><xml><records><record><database name="97_Arden_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\97_Arden_Shortlist.enl">97_Arden_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>72</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="zvxw9f0wq0tvteeeev5xewt4parw95ezef9e">72</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Harkness, N.</style></author></authors></contributors><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">THE RIVER TAME - A SHORT HISTORY OF WATER-POLLUTION AND CONTROL WITHIN AN INDUSTRIAL RIVER BASIN</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Water Science and Technology</style></secondary-title></titles><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">153-165</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">14</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1-2</style></number><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1982</style></year><pub-dates><date><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1982</style></date></pub-dates></dates><isbn><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">0273-1223</style></isbn><accession-num><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">WOS:A1982NE21200011</style></accession-num><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Times Cited: 12</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">&lt;Go to ISI&gt;://WOS:A1982NE21200011</style></url></related-urls></urls></record><record><database name="97_Arden_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\97_Arden_Shortlist.enl">97_Arden_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>48</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="zvxw9f0wq0tvteeeev5xewt4parw95ezef9e">48</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Hoffmann, C. C.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Pedersen, M. L.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Kronvang, B.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Ovig, L.</style></author></authors></contributors><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Restoration of the rivers Brede, Cole and Skerne: a joint Danish and British EU-LIFE demonstration project, IV - Implications for nitrate and iron transformation</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Aquatic Conservation-Marine and Freshwater Ecosystems</style></secondary-title></titles><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">223-240</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">8</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1</style></number><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1998</style></year><pub-dates><date><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Jan-Feb</style></date></pub-dates></dates><isbn><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1052-7613</style></isbn><accession-num><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">WOS:000073321900019</style></accession-num><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1. The possible effects on the hydrological and biogeochemical processes in the River Brede valley were studied from August 1994 to August 1996 based on measurements in piezometers installed along four transects across the river valley and two river monitoring stations located immediately upstream and downstream of the restored reach. 2. Groundwater discharge to the river varied considerably both along the restored river reach and from bankside to bankside. Comparison of the water balance derived from two river monitoring stations and the groundwater balance for the restored part of the river valley, based on Darcy&apos;s equation, indicated that a deep-lying regional aquifer probably discharges to the river in the restored area. 3. The nitrate balance for the floodplain revealed that 92 kg NO3-N ha(-1) year(-1) was removed during passage through the river valley, probably as a result of pyrite oxidation. In contrast, iron leaked from the floodplain to the river at the rate of 400 kg Fe ha(-1) year(-1). 4. A prolonged dry period, starting four months after completion of the restoration work and lasting for the remainder of the study period, makes it difficult to conclude whether the results obtained are reflective of river and floodplain restoration. Nitrate concentration measurements at the two river monitoring stations revealed no overall significant changes when comparing a pre-restoration period with two similar post-restoration periods. However, comparison of nitrate losses from an upstream control catchment and the restored reach catchment indicated enhanced removal of nitrate along the restored river reach during a three month period of flooding immediately following completion of restoration work (January to March 1995). (C) 1998 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Times Cited: 9&#xD;International Conference on River Restoration 96&#xD;Sep, 1996&#xD;Silkeborg, denmark&#xD;European Ctr River Restorat; Natl Environm Res Inst; Dept Streams &amp; Riparian Areas; Danish Minist Environm Energy</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">&lt;Go to ISI&gt;://WOS:000073321900019</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/store/10.1002/(SICI)1099-0755(199801/02)8:1&lt;223::AID-AQC270&gt;3.0.CO;2-V/asset/270_ftp.pdf?v=1&amp;t=gupcpocp&amp;s=03be5d0f078baa4010e0c0fbc384322dc94fda73</style></url></related-urls></urls><electronic-resource-num><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">10.1002/(sici)1099-0755(199801/02)8:1&lt;223::aid-aqc270&gt;3.0.co;2-v</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="97_Arden_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\97_Arden_Shortlist.enl">97_Arden_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>133</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="zvxw9f0wq0tvteeeev5xewt4parw95ezef9e">133</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Keen, D. H.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Department of Geography, Coventry Polytechnic, Coventry, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Significance of the record provided by Pleistocene fluvial deposits and their included molluscan faunas for palaeoenvironmental reconstruction and stratigraphy: case studies from the English Midlands</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Palaeogeography, Palaeoclimatology, Palaeoecology</style></secondary-title></titles><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">25-34</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">80</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1</style></number><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1990</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">The vast majority of Pleistocene fluvial deposits in northwest Europe are of cold climate origin with the most important sediment type being coarse sands and gravels formed under nival regimes. Less Commonly, sands and silts of interglacial deposition are preserved in the lower levels of major aggradations or in channels preserved beneath them. Molluscan faunas are common in both types of deposit, although the fine-grained temperate sediments show the best preservation and the most diverse assemblages. This paper will discuss the types of molluscan faunas found in fluvial deposits and assess their suitability for both climatic reconstruction and stratigraphic studies. While it has been clear for many years that reliable local environmental reconstructions can be made using Mollusca they have been less used for regional climatic assessment. Work in England over the past thirty years shows that faunas obtained from fluvial sediments, particularly if they contain both freshwater and terrestrial species, can provide a basis for regional climatic reconstruction. Mollusca may also allow the separation from each other of interglacials and interstadials, and permit these episodes to be more precisely defined than is allowed by other means such as palynology. Molluscan faunas may offer potential for the identification of temperature episodes which may have the same climatic status as interglacials, but which are not recognised as such by other palaeontological evidence such as pollen. The use of molluscan faunas for biostratigraphy has been firmly rejected by previous authors. However, recent work concentrating on sites of similar facies within single catchments has shown that both presence and absence of individual species, particularly those now exotic to the British Isles, [e.g. Belgrandia marginata (Michaud) and Corbicula fluminalis (Müller)] can be a useful guide to relative age. Examples illustrating the significance of these faunas in the stratigraphic record are largely taken from the fluvial deposits of the major rivers of the English Midlands (Warwickshire Avon, Great Ouse, Nene), but reference is also made to other studies on the deposits of the Thames. The ages of the faunas described range from the Cromerian Interglacial to the Devensian Glacial stage and includes data from sites in integlacials identified in the stratigraphic record but so far not formally named. © 1990.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 47&#xD;Export Date: 7 November 2011&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-0025658052&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=ffc829b4c712541d4422e5c1e2120d8e</style></url></related-urls></urls></record><record><database name="97_Arden_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\97_Arden_Shortlist.enl">97_Arden_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>85</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="zvxw9f0wq0tvteeeev5xewt4parw95ezef9e">85</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Keen, D. H.</style></author></authors></contributors><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Towards a late Middle Pleistocene non-marine molluscan biostratigraphy for the British Isles</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Quaternary Science Reviews</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Quaternary Science Reviews</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1657-1665</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">20</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">16-17</style></number><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2001</style></year><pub-dates><date><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Nov</style></date></pub-dates></dates><isbn><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">0277-3791</style></isbn><accession-num><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">WOS:000171907400008</style></accession-num><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">The fossils of non-marine Mollusca are among the most prominent in Pleistocene deposits. They were one of the first fossil groups to be noted in the literature, as early as the beginning of the 18th century. With the stabilisation of taxonomies in the 19th century numerous publications appeared with faunal lists of interglacial taxa, but few attempts were made to use the data for interpretation. Work from 1950 onwards, especially by Sparks and Kerney in Britain, Puissegur in France, and by Lozek in Central Europe, used a quantitative approach to sorting, counting and interpreting assemblages. Despite the adoption of this rigorous methodology to molluscan studies, interglacial faunas were used primarily to reconstruct past environments, and although faunal changes through the Pleistocene were recognised, it was thought that non-marine Mollusca were inherently badly fitted for use as tools for dating in the classic geological sense. Recent work, coupled with the re-evaluation of sites described in the literature, has allowed non-marine molluscan faunas to be used as biostratigraphic indicators. Biostratigraphic schemes evolved from this work are comparable with parallel investigations using Mammalia, Coleoptera and lithostratigraphy calibrated by a number of geochronometric methods, but may be at variance with pollen biostratigraphies. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science Ltd. All rights reserved.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Times Cited: 25</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">&lt;Go to ISI&gt;://WOS:000171907400008</style></url></related-urls></urls><electronic-resource-num><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">10.1016/s0277-3791(01)00030-0</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="97_Arden_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\97_Arden_Shortlist.enl">97_Arden_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>125</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="zvxw9f0wq0tvteeeev5xewt4parw95ezef9e">125</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Keen, D. H.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Coope, C. R.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Jones, R. L.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Field, M. H.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Griffiths, H. I.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Lewis, S. G.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Bowen, D. Q.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Centre for Quaternary Science, Coventry University, Priory Street, Coventry CV1 5FB, United Kingdom&#xD;Centre for Quaternary Research, Royal Holloway College, University of London, Egham, Surrey TW20 OEX, United Kingdom&#xD;Sub-Dept. of Quaternary Research, Botany School, University of Cambridge, Downing Street, Cambridge CB2 3EA, United Kingdom&#xD;Res. Inst. Environ. Sci. and Mgmt., University of Hull, Cottingham Road, Kingston-upon-Hull HU6 7RX, United Kingdom&#xD;Department of Geology and Geography, Cheltenham Gloucester Coll. H., Francis Close Hall, Swindon Road, Cheltenham, Gloucestershire GL50 4AZ, United Kingdom&#xD;Department of Geology, University of Cardiff, PO Box 914, Cardiff CF 3YE, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Middle pleistocene deposits at Frog Hall Pit, stretton-on-dunsmore, Warwickshire, English Midlands, and their implications for the age of the type Wolstonian</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Journal of Quaternary Science</style></secondary-title></titles><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">183-208</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">12</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">3</style></number><keywords><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Coleoptera</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">English Midlands</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Hoxnian</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Mollusca</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Ostracoda</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Plant macro-fossils</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Pollen</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Wolstonian</style></keyword></keywords><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1997</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Organic sediment from Frog Hall Pit, near Coventry, has produced pollen, plant macrofossil, insect, ostracod and molluscan data indicative of the early part of a temperate episode in the Middle Pleistocene. The regional stratigraphy and clast lithological characteristics of the gravels underlying the temperate deposits show that the whole sequence at the site post- dates the major glaciation (the Wolstonian sensu Mitchell et al., 1973) of the Midlands. Aminoacid D/L ratios from molluscan shells give mean values of 0.24, which is consistent with an age in Oxygen Isotope Stage 9 and comparable with those from the Hoxnian Interglacial of East Anglia. This age-estimate for the Frog Hall organic deposit places a minimum age on the Wolstonian Glaciation of the Midlands in Oxygen Isotope Stage 10, and therefore close in time to the Anglian (Oxygen Isotope Stage 12) Cold Stage.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 25&#xD;Export Date: 7 November 2011&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-0031422629&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=9a0e01e058847f988eda27ff4522b5c9</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/store/10.1002/(SICI)1099-1417(199705/06)12:3&lt;183::AID-JQS298&gt;3.0.CO;2-Q/asset/298_ftp.pdf?v=1&amp;t=gupnd12h&amp;s=f4f106cf90f4e9ff65021e3e66e7ad200b03f1d0</style></url></related-urls></urls></record><record><database name="97_Arden_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\97_Arden_Shortlist.enl">97_Arden_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>103</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="zvxw9f0wq0tvteeeev5xewt4parw95ezef9e">103</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Keen, D. H.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Hardaker, T.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Lang, A. T. O.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Institute of Archaeology and Antiquity, University of Birmingham, Birmingham B15 2TT, United Kingdom&#xD;79 Millwood End, Long Hanborough, Witney, Oxford OX29 8BP, United Kingdom&#xD;Department of Archaeology, University of Oxford, 36 Beaumont Street, Oxford OX1 2PG, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">A Lower Palaeolithic industry from the Cromerian (MIS 13) Baginton Formation of Waverley Wood and Wood Farm Pits, Bubbenhall, Warwickshire, UK</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Journal of Quaternary Science</style></secondary-title></titles><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">457-470</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">21</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">5</style></number><keywords><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Bytham river</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cromerian</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Handaxe</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Lower Palaeolithic</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">MIS 13</style></keyword></keywords><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2006</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Artefacts of Cromerian (MIS 13) age recovered from extensions to the classic site of Waverley Wood Farm Pit, Warwickshire, give new insights into the Lower Palaeolithic and Pleistocene geological record of the English Midlands. The Baginton Formation in the area to the south and southwest of Coventry has been the major source of Lower Palaeolithic artefacts in the Midlands since the first discoveries in the 1930s. Current sand and gravel workings at Waverley Wood and Wood Farm Pits near the village of Bubbenhall, have provided artefacts of quartzite, andesite and flint together with sparse large mammal material. Some of the Lower Palaeolithic finds were in situ in the succession providing, for the first time, firm evidence of their geological provenance. The variety and number of the artefacts allows detailed evaluation of the largest group of Lower Palaeolithic tools to be found in the West Midlands. The petrology of some of the tools and associated clasts in the gravels at the base of the Baginton Formation allow speculation on the origin of the rock types from northwest and eastern England which may have been brought to the West Midlands by a pre-Anglian glaciation or just possibly by human transport. Copyright © 2006 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 13&#xD;Export Date: 7 November 2011&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-33746138504&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=2dab4a38f8fe5effb6b53524dc40eaeb</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/store/10.1002/jqs.1047/asset/1047_ftp.pdf?v=1&amp;t=gupndbju&amp;s=1125f08be4abedba4a76b1fb7cf3e1aa722c2b6f</style></url></related-urls></urls></record><record><database name="97_Arden_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\97_Arden_Shortlist.enl">97_Arden_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>47</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="zvxw9f0wq0tvteeeev5xewt4parw95ezef9e">47</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Kronvang, B.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Svendsen, L. M.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Brookes, A.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Fisher, K.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Moller, B.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Ottosen, O.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Newson, M.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Sear, D.</style></author></authors></contributors><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Restoration of the rivers Brede, Cole and Skerne: a joint Danish and British EU-LIFE demonstration project, III - Channel morphology, hydrodynamics and transport of sediment and nutrients</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Aquatic Conservation-Marine and Freshwater Ecosystems</style></secondary-title></titles><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">209-222</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">8</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1</style></number><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1998</style></year><pub-dates><date><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Jan-Feb</style></date></pub-dates></dates><isbn><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1052-7613</style></isbn><accession-num><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">WOS:000073321900018</style></accession-num><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1. A comprehensive monitoring programme was initiated for the Brede, Cole and Skerne river restoration projects in order to elucidate the impact of re-meandering on flood levels, floodplain inundation, adjustment of river morphology, sediment transport and overbank sediment deposition. 2. Reducing the bankfull capacity, raising the bed level and lowering the bank level allowed an increase in flooding frequency and in the amount of water passing onto the floodplain in all three rivers. In the river Brede, restoration of the natural hydrological contact between the river and its floodplain resulted in high deposition of sediment (189 t year(-1)) and sediment-associated phosphorus (770 kg P year(-1)). 3. Construction work caused excessive downstream loss of sediment and phosphorus as documented from sediment mass balances for the River Brede and River Cole. Short-term adjustments in river morphology were recorded in the River Cole based on the fluvial auditing procedure. Post-restoration morphology changed compared with that before restoration in terms of both total diversity and the type of features recorded. (C) 1998 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Times Cited: 24&#xD;International Conference on River Restoration 96&#xD;Sep, 1996&#xD;Silkeborg, denmark&#xD;European Ctr River Restorat; Natl Environm Res Inst; Dept Streams &amp; Riparian Areas; Danish Minist Environm Energy</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">&lt;Go to ISI&gt;://WOS:000073321900018</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/store/10.1002/(SICI)1099-0755(199801/02)8:1&lt;209::AID-AQC271&gt;3.0.CO;2-C/asset/271_ftp.pdf?v=1&amp;t=gupcpuh6&amp;s=c6b870a92d5d80ec7784afe6e648815e5caf80a9</style></url></related-urls></urls><electronic-resource-num><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">10.1002/(sici)1099-0755(199801/02)8:1&lt;209::aid-aqc271&gt;3.0.co;2-c</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="97_Arden_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\97_Arden_Shortlist.enl">97_Arden_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>32</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="zvxw9f0wq0tvteeeev5xewt4parw95ezef9e">32</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Book Section">5</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Lawler, D. M.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Foster, I. D. L.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Petts, G. E.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Harper, S.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Morrissey, I. P.</style></author></authors><secondary-authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Rowan, J. S. Duck R. W. Werritty A.</style></author></secondary-authors></contributors><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Suspended sediment dynamics for June storm events in the urbanized River Tame, UK</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Sediment Dynamics and the Hydromorphology of Fluvial Systems</style></secondary-title><tertiary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Iahs Publication</style></tertiary-title></titles><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">96-103</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">306</style></volume><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2006</style></year></dates><isbn><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">0144-7815&#xD;978-1-901502-68-8</style></isbn><accession-num><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">WOS:000248525200012</style></accession-num><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Few studies of urban water quality storm-event dynamics have been conducted at the sub-catchment scale, though most models assume a &quot;first-flush&quot;, positive hysteresis response. This paper reflects on the appropriateness of the first-flush model for summer (June) storms, using high-resolution flow, turbidity and water quality data from the highly urbanized River Tame headwater system, central England. Discharge responded very quickly to storm precipitation, and turbidity events exceed 500 FTU 60 times per annum. However, &quot;first-flush&quot; responses were rare, and turbidity normally peaked after the flow maximum, leading to anticlockwise hysteresis, reinforced by lengthy turbidity &quot;tails&quot;. This suggests limited sediment exhaustion. Many responses probably relate to triggering of Combined Sewer Overflows and/or Waste Water Treatment Works, which occur late in storms when capacities are exceeded, and is consistent with concurrent ammonia increases and DO decreases. Prolonged turbidity responses can raise suspended solids loads above predicted levels, increase ecological stress, and lead to complications for sediment budget studies. A re-examination of the first-flush model is overdue.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Times Cited: 2&#xD;Symposium on Sediment Dynamics and the Hydromorphology of Fluvial Systems&#xD;Jul 02-07, 2006&#xD;Dundee, SCOTLAND&#xD;Int Assoc Hydrol Sci, Int Commiss Continental Eros</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">&lt;Go to ISI&gt;://WOS:000248525200012</style></url></related-urls></urls></record><record><database name="97_Arden_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\97_Arden_Shortlist.enl">97_Arden_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>29</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="zvxw9f0wq0tvteeeev5xewt4parw95ezef9e">29</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Lawler, D. M.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Petts, G. E.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Foster, I. D. L.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Harper, S.</style></author></authors></contributors><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Turbidity dynamics during spring storm events in an urban headwater river system: The Upper Tame, West Midlands, UK</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Science of the Total Environment</style></secondary-title></titles><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">109-126</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">360</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1-3</style></number><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2006</style></year><pub-dates><date><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">May 1</style></date></pub-dates></dates><isbn><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">0048-9697</style></isbn><accession-num><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">WOS:000237870500010</style></accession-num><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Turbidity is an important water quality variable, through its relation to light suppression, BOD impact, sediment-associated contaminant transport, and suspended sediment effects on organisms and habitats. Yet few published field investigations of wet-weather turbidity dynamics, through several individual and sequenced rainstorms in extremely urbanised headwater basins, have emerged. This paper aims to address this gap through a turbidity analysis of multiple storm events in spring 2001 in an urban headwater basin (57 km(2)) of the River Tame, central England, the most urbanised basin for its size in the UK (similar to 42%). Data were collected at 15-min frequency at automated monitoring stations for rainfall, streamflow and six water quality variables (turbidity, EC, temperature, DO, pH, ammonia). Disturbance experiments also allowed estimates of bed sediment storage to be obtained. Six important and unusual features of the storm event turbidity response were apparent: (1) sluggish early turbidity response, followed by a turbidity &apos;rush&apos;; (2) quasi-coincident flow and turbidity peaks; (3) anti-clockwise hysteresis in the discharge-turbidity relationship on all but one event, resulting from Falling-LImb Turbidity Extensions (FLITEs); (4) increases in peak turbidity levels through storm sequences; (5) initial micro-pulses (IMP) in turbidity; and (6) secondary turbidity peaks (STP) or &apos;turbidity shoulders&apos; (TS). These features provided very little evidence of a true &apos;first-flush&apos; effect: instead, substantial suspended solids transport continued right through the flow recessions, and little storm-event sediment exhaustion was evident. A new, dimensionless, hysteresis index, HI(mid), is developed to quantify the magnitude and direction of hysteresis in a simple, clear, direct and intuitive manner. This allowed the degree of departure from the classic &apos;first-flush&apos;, clockwise hysteresis models to be assessed. Of the 15 turbidity events considered, 10 coincided with ammonia spikes of up to 6.25 mg 1(-1) at Water Orton (the downstream station): this suggests that spills from combined sewer overflows (CSO) or waste water treatment works (WwTWs) are significant in the throughput of turbid waters here. Substantial ammonia peaks related most strongly to total storm rainfall receipt, of four rainfall variables considered, and significant ammonia peaks were generated even from low-magnitude storms (rainfall totals &lt; 4 mm), indicating that spills are a frequent occurrence. Local bed sediment stores appear to be limited, suggesting that other distal sediment sources, such as road networks and old mineworkings are possibly more important. Biofilms may also play a part in delaying sediment release until late in the hydrograph, and in suppressing late spring turbidity levels. Existing first-flush models appear to be an oversimplification here. Such urban headwater basin responses can provide useful insights into the generation of contaminant waves, and offer vital early-warning systems for pollution events propagating downstream. (c) 2006 Published by Elsevier B.V.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Times Cited: 29</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">&lt;Go to ISI&gt;://WOS:000237870500010</style></url></related-urls></urls><electronic-resource-num><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">10.1016/j.scitotenv.2005.08.032</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="97_Arden_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\97_Arden_Shortlist.enl">97_Arden_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>63</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="zvxw9f0wq0tvteeeev5xewt4parw95ezef9e">63</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Lerner, D. N.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Gosk, E.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Bourg, A. C. M.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Bishop, P. K.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Burston, M. W.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Mouvet, C.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Degranges, P.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Jakobsen, R.</style></author></authors></contributors><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">POSTSCRIPT - SUMMARY OF THE COVENTRY GROUNDWATER INVESTIGATION AND IMPLICATIONS FOR THE FUTURE</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Journal of Hydrology</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Journal of Hydrology</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">257-272</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">149</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1-4</style></number><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1993</style></year><pub-dates><date><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Aug</style></date></pub-dates></dates><isbn><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">0022-1694</style></isbn><accession-num><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">WOS:A1993LQ11800015</style></accession-num><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">The broader implications of the Coventry Groundwater Investigation are discussed in this postscript. The complex interbedded sandstone and mudstone sequence under Coventry is seriously polluted by chlorinated hydrocarbon solvents. Investigations in such terrain will require much greater expenditure than was available for this project if they are to describe the distribution and movement of pollutants in enough detail to evaluate, quantitatively, options for aquifer clean-up. It is not realistic to consider clean-up of Coventry&apos;s groundwater at the present time because of the lack of detailed knowledge. It is probable, at least for the present, that clean-up is not feasible, because of hydrogeological constraints arising from the extreme variability of permeability in the system and an absence of operational techniques for clean-up. Stronger, more pro-active protection of groundwater is needed. A major recommendation for future investigations is a procedure to avoid open boreholes, which can allow pollution to penetrate deeper into the aquifer, and may confuse the results of sampling.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Times Cited: 6</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">&lt;Go to ISI&gt;://WOS:A1993LQ11800015</style></url></related-urls></urls><electronic-resource-num><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">10.1016/0022-1694(93)90109-m</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="97_Arden_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\97_Arden_Shortlist.enl">97_Arden_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>138</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="zvxw9f0wq0tvteeeev5xewt4parw95ezef9e">138</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Lloyd, J. W.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Rushton, K. R.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Jones, P. A.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Department of Geological Sciences, University of Birmingham, P.O. Box 363, Birmingham, B15 2TT, United Kingdom&#xD;Department of Civil Engineering, University of Birmingham, P.O. Box 363, Birmingham, B15 2TT, United Kingdom&#xD;Geological Branch, South Midlands Area, National Coal Board, Cole Orton, Leicester, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">An assessment of groundwater inflow into a proposed shaft and drift in the warwickshire coalfield using packer test data in an electrical analogue model</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">International Journal of Mine Water</style></secondary-title></titles><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1-18</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">4</style></number><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1983</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">The assessment was carried out in multilayered permeability ground using packer testing techniques to ascertain permeability. Borehole instability occurred through using water as a drilling fluid in the variable lithologies. This resulted in some difficulty in obtaining good packer seating with foundation engineering equipment. Oil industry drill stem test strings proved more effective. Reliable permeabilities were, however, eventually obtained and a permeability assessment was carried out using various weighting techniques to provide a complete vertical distribution on which analogue models of potential inflows were based. The analogue models allowed a detailed investigation of the flow patterns around both the proposed shaft and drift. Very high inflows were predicted at certain depths and therefore neither the shaft nor the drift were constructed. © 1983 Springer-Verlag.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Export Date: 7 November 2011&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-0020995125&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=66cff20a9e6871c17dcd2953cf313a94</style></url></related-urls></urls></record><record><database name="97_Arden_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\97_Arden_Shortlist.enl">97_Arden_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>16</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="zvxw9f0wq0tvteeeev5xewt4parw95ezef9e">16</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Maddy, D.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Green, C. P.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Lewis, S. G.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Bowen, D. Q.</style></author></authors></contributors><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">PLEISTOCENE GEOLOGY OF THE LOWER SEVERN VALLEY, UK</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Quaternary Science Reviews</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Quaternary Science Reviews</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">209-222</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">14</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">3</style></number><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1995</style></year><pub-dates><date><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1995</style></date></pub-dates></dates><isbn><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">0277-3791</style></isbn><accession-num><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">WOS:A1995RN23800001</style></accession-num><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">The lower Severn valley contains a sequence of fluvial, glaciofluvial and glaciogenic deposits of Pleistocene age which is divided into two formations. Glaciogenic sediments are correlated with members of the Wolston Formation (Anglian). A new formation, the Severn Valley Formation, which consists of fluvial deposits, is defined. It is sub-divided into six members, the four oldest of which are considered in this paper. The oldest deposits in the lower Severn basin are the till and glaciofluvial outwash gravels of the Woolridge Member. The till is correlated with the Thrussington Member of the Wolston Formation which is correlated with the Lowestoft Formation of the Anglian Stage (Oxygen Isotope Stage 12). The oldest member of the Severn Valley Formation, the Spring Hill Member, is provisionally correlated with OI Stage 10. The Bushley Green Member represents deposition during OI Stages 9 and 8, the basal fossiliferous sediments (Bushley Green Fossil Bed) are correlated with OI Stage 9 by amino acid geochronology. The Kidderminster Station Member records a significant input of lithologies not seen in quantity in the higher members, and evidence is presented which suggests that this is a response to renewed glaciation in the upper basin. This glaciation was responsible for the deposition of the Ridgacre Formation of the Birmingham area. Amino acid geochronology and Chlorine-36 ages from erratic boulders show that the Kidderminster Station Member and Ridgacre Formation are of OI Stage 6 (Warthe) age. The basal deposits of the Holt Heath Member include the Stourbridge Fossil Bed, with a temperate fauna believed to be Ipswichian (&apos;last interglacial&apos;, OI Substage 5e), and the Upton Warren Fossil Bed (OI Substa,ge 5a). Most of the Holt Heath Member consists of outwash from an Irish Sea ice sheet which entered the Severn basin during the Late Devensian (OI Stage 2).</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Times Cited: 22</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">&lt;Go to ISI&gt;://WOS:A1995RN23800001</style></url></related-urls></urls><electronic-resource-num><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">10.1016/0277-3791(95)00001-6</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="97_Arden_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\97_Arden_Shortlist.enl">97_Arden_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>132</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="zvxw9f0wq0tvteeeev5xewt4parw95ezef9e">132</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Maddy, D.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Keen, D. H.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Bridgland, D. R.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Green, C. P.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Centre for Quaternary Research, Department of Geography, RHBNC, University of London, Egham, Surrey Tw200EX, United Kingdom&#xD;Department of Geography, Coventry Polytechnic, Coventry CV1 5FB, United Kingdom&#xD;Nature Conservancy Council, Northminster House, Peterborough PE1 lUA, United Kingdom</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">A revised model for the Pleistocene development of the River Avon, Warwickshire</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Journal of the Geological Society</style></secondary-title></titles><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">473-484</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">148</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">3</style></number><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1991</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">A re-examination of the Pleistocene river deposits in the valley of the Midland Avon indicates that the conventional post-Hoxnian model for their development has to be revised. Reinvestigation of two key localities, Cropthorne in the Lower Avon valley and Ailstone on the Warwickshire Stour, a left bank tributary of the Avon, shows that the deposits of at least two separate temperate episodes are represented within the sequence. Amino-acid ratios on non-marine Mollusca from the temperate deposits allow these episodes to be correlated with oxygen isotope stages 5 and 7. Since the stage 7 temperate deposit lies within sediments which post-date the Wolston glacial seauence. an older aee is indicated for that sequence than is proposed in the conventional strati- I graphic succession of the British Pleistocene.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Cited By (since 1996): 35&#xD;Export Date: 7 November 2011&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-0000326624&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=c97a67691f79ac80f1da4c5a23fba729</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://jgs.geoscienceworld.org/cgi/reprint/148/3/473.pdf</style></url></related-urls></urls></record><record><database name="97_Arden_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\97_Arden_Shortlist.enl">97_Arden_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>162</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="zvxw9f0wq0tvteeeev5xewt4parw95ezef9e">162</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Maddy, D.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Lewis, S. G.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Keen, D. H.</style></author></authors></contributors><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Pleistocene palaeomeanders of the River Avon, Warwickshire</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Proceedings of the Geologists Association</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Proceedings of the Geologists Association</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">163-172</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">110</style></volume><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1999</style></year><pub-dates><date><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1999</style></date></pub-dates></dates><isbn><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">0016-7878</style></isbn><accession-num><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">WOS:000080037400007</style></accession-num><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">The river terrace record of the Warwickshire Avon contains a number of palaeomeander remnants. Sediments preserved within palaeomeanders at Cropthorne and Eckington underlie the No. 3 terrace of the Avon and have been shown to contain faunas of Ipswichian Interglacial age (Oxygen isotope Substage (OIS) 5e). They are considered to represent deposition at that time in a meandering river. At Cropthorne the meander was &apos;cut-off&apos; before the incision that preceeded the formation of the No. 2 terrace. A similar abandonment of a former meander is confirmed by clast lithological evidence from sediments around Broom near the Avon/Arrow confluence. Here the &apos;cut-off&apos; is shown by molluscan evidence to have occurred after the establishment of cold climate conditions in the Devensian, and during the deposition of the sediments that underlie the No. 2 terrace. These adjustments of channel pattern are interpreted as response to change in discharge and sediment supply accompanying deterioration of climate at the end of the last interglacial. Palaeomeander remnants have been preserved by migration of the active valley floor away from them during the Devensian.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Times Cited: 3&#xD;Part 2</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">&lt;Go to ISI&gt;://WOS:000080037400007</style></url></related-urls></urls><electronic-resource-num><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">10.1016/s0016-7878(99)80067-4</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="97_Arden_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\97_Arden_Shortlist.enl">97_Arden_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>70</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="zvxw9f0wq0tvteeeev5xewt4parw95ezef9e">70</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Martin, J. R.</style></author></authors></contributors><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">WATER-QUALITY IMPROVEMENTS IN THE TRENT CATCHMENT (UK) - A VIEW OF THEIR RELATIONSHIP TO MANAGEMENT AND LEGISLATIVE CHANGES</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Water Science and Technology</style></secondary-title></titles><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">167-176</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">30</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">5</style></number><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1994</style></year><pub-dates><date><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1994</style></date></pub-dates></dates><isbn><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">0273-1223</style></isbn><accession-num><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">WOS:A1994QE54200018</style></accession-num><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">This paper outlines the improvements in water quality which have occurred in the River Trent catchment since about 1960 and the strategies by which they have been achieved. During this period there have also been several major changes in the structure of water quality management, in pollution control legislation and in the use of river and effluent quality standards. The links between quality trends, legislation, management structures and investment in sewerage and sewage treatment are considered. Prospects for the future under the current management regime are discussed.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Times Cited: 3&#xD;17th Biennial Conference of the International-Association-on-Water-Quality&#xD;Jul 24-30, 1994&#xD;Budapest, hungary&#xD;Int assoc water qual</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">&lt;Go to ISI&gt;://WOS:A1994QE54200018</style></url></related-urls></urls></record><record><database name="97_Arden_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\97_Arden_Shortlist.enl">97_Arden_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>163</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="zvxw9f0wq0tvteeeev5xewt4parw95ezef9e">163</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">McEwen, L.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Hall, T.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Hunt, J.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Dempsey, M.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Harrison, M.</style></author></authors></contributors><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Flood warning, warning response and planning control issues associated with caravan parks: the April 1998 floods on the lower Avon floodplain, Midlands region, UK</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Applied Geography</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Applied Geography</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">271-305</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">22</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">3</style></number><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2002</style></year><pub-dates><date><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Jul</style></date></pub-dates></dates><isbn><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">0143-6228</style></isbn><accession-num><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">WOS:000178284100004</style></accession-num><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Times Cited: 3</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">&lt;Go to ISI&gt;://WOS:000178284100004</style></url></related-urls></urls><electronic-resource-num><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">10.1016/s0143-6228(02)00008-5</style></electronic-resource-num></record><record><database name="97_Arden_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\97_Arden_Shortlist.enl">97_Arden_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>53</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="zvxw9f0wq0tvteeeev5xewt4parw95ezef9e">53</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Millier, Helen K. G. R.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Hooda, Peter S.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Downward, Stuart R.</style></author></authors></contributors><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">The impact of treated sewage wastewater discharges on the phosphorus levels and hydrology of two second order rivers flowing into the Thames</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Journal of Environmental Monitoring</style></secondary-title></titles><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1307-1314</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">12</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">6</style></number><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2010</style></year><pub-dates><date><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2010</style></date></pub-dates></dates><isbn><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">1464-0325</style></isbn><accession-num><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">WOS:000278588400011</style></accession-num><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Rivers Bourne and Hogsmill, urban tributaries of the Thames, were sampled up and downstream of sewage treatment works (STWs) wastewaters outflows. River water was analysed for total phosphorus (TP) and soluble reactive phosphorus (SRP) and, in conjunction with river flow data, this study aimed to assess the impact of treated wastewaters on P concentrations in rivers where wastewater volumes frequently exceed those of the underlying river and to consider whether these rivers are likely to achieve &quot;good ecological status&quot; under the Water Framework Directive (WFD). P concentrations downstream of the STW discharge points were generally an order of magnitude greater than upstream, the flow weighted mean concentration in the River Bourne increased from 0.078 mg SRP l(-1) to 0.45 mg SRP l(-1) downstream of the input source. In the Hogsmill, the flow weighted mean concentration rose from 0.19 mg SRP l(-1) to 1.78 mg SRP l(-1) downstream of the input source prior to the introduction of P removal at the STW. Once P removal commenced, flow weighted mean concentrations downstream of the STW reduced to 0.56 mg SRP l(-1). Headwaters in the River Bourne, upstream of the STW outflow showed evidence of irregular, minor, diffuse inputs but overall mean figures indicate that the proposed UK Technical Advisory Group (UK TAG) for the WFD limit of 0.12 mg SRP l(-1) would be met. Headwaters in the Hogsmill are subject to small, continuous discharges of sewage effluent, sufficient to raise SRP levels above the UK TAG limit. Downstream, neither river meets the UKTAG recommendations in terms of P, despite the use of P-stripping processes at both STWs, an indication that current discharge consents for P concentrations in wastewaters are too high.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Times Cited: 2</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">&lt;Go to ISI&gt;://WOS:000278588400011</style></url><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://pubs.rsc.org/en/content/articlepdf/2010/em/b923263j</style></url></related-urls></urls><electronic-resource-num><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">10.1039/b923263j</style></electronic-resource-num></record></records></xml>