<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><xml><records><record><database name="28_Vale_of_York_Shortlist.enl" path="Z:\BSG project\Shortlist\28_Vale_of_York_Shortlist.enl">28_Vale_of_York_Shortlist.enl</database><source-app name="EndNote" version="15.0">EndNote</source-app><rec-number>129</rec-number><foreign-keys><key app="EN" db-id="e0spaz5dezwapgete2455wzjaedsr90swwvp">129</key></foreign-keys><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Wang, J.</style></author><author><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Pant, H. K.</style></author></authors></contributors><auth-address><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Department of Environmental Geographic and Geological Sciences, Lehman College of the City University of New York, New York, United States&#xD;The Graduate Center, Ph.D. Program in Earth and Environmental Sciences, The City University of New York, New York, United States</style></auth-address><titles><title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Assessments of Potential Spatial-temporal Variations in Phosphorus Distribution and Fractionation in River Bed Sediments</style></title><secondary-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Clean - Soil, Air, Water</style></secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Clean - Soil, Air, Water</style></full-title></periodical><pages><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">148-156</style></pages><volume><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">39</style></volume><number><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2</style></number><keywords><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Microbial P</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Mineralization</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">NaHCO3-P</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">NaOH-P</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">P distribution</style></keyword><keyword><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">P pool</style></keyword></keywords><dates><year><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">2011</style></year></dates><abstract><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Sediment characteristics influence the distribution and bioavailability of phosphorus (P) in river sediments. In this study, we analyzed different P fractions in the sediments of the Bronx River, New York City, NY, using sequential extraction. The results showed that the average P pool rank order was HCl-P&amp;gt;NaOH-P&amp;gt;NaHCO3-P&amp;gt;residue-P, and their relative proportions were 3.7: 2.0: 1.4: 1 in sediments collected in 2006, while HCl-P&amp;gt;NaOH-P&amp;gt;residue-P&amp;gt;NaHCO3-P, with their relative proportions of 27.8:6.2:2.7:1 in the sediments obtained in 2007. The strong correlation between microbial P and organic P (OP), along with the changes in microbial P over time indicate that most of the OP in the river bed sediments is potentially bioavailable. The sediment transport, deposition, assimilation, the exchange of P between sediments and water columns, the land use changes, raw sewer discharge, gas spill, construction, fertilizer application, etc., as well as the hydro-climatic changes could result in the spatial and temporal variations in P bioavailability in the river bed sediments. The estimations of P pools and their bioavailability in river bed sediments could help determine the spatial and temporal variations in P transport and impacts of land use on water quality, in turn, help regulate P in the river&apos;s watershed. The spatial and temporal variations on P fractionation and mineralization in the bed sediments, as well as the bioavailability of P in the Bronx River bed sediments were studied. It appears that sediment transport, deposition and assimilation, land use changes, temperature, and precipitation variations would account for the spatial and temporal variations in P distribution and fractionation in river sediments. © 2011 WILEY-VCH Verlag GmbH &amp;amp; Co. KGaA, Weinheim.</style></abstract><notes><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">Export Date: 22 November 2011&#xD;Source: Scopus</style></notes><urls><related-urls><url><style face="normal" font="default" size="100%">http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-79951648840&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=dfd387a2ecc40ff7634b6f789804262d</style></url></related-urls></urls></record></records></xml>